<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A concordance or table made after the order of the alphabet, conteyning the principall both wordes &amp; matters, which are comprehended in the newe Testament, / gathered by T.W.</title>
            <author>T. W.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1579</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 204 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 48 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B00845</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 24917</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S95720</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">57402343</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 57402343</idno>
            <idno type="VID">181144</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B00845)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 181144)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 2171:9)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A concordance or table made after the order of the alphabet, conteyning the principall both wordes &amp; matters, which are comprehended in the newe Testament, / gathered by T.W.</title>
                  <author>T. W.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[95] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>by Christopher Barker, Printer to the Queenes most excellent Maiestie.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Domini 1579..</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title within ornamental border (McK. &amp; Ferg. 146β).</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A-F⁸.</note>
                  <note>"Cum priuilegio."</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: torn, stained and cropped, with loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Bible. --  N.T. --  Concordances, English --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-01</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-01</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:181144:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:181144:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A CONCOR<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>DANCE OR TABLE MADE AFTER THE OR<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the Alphabet, contey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the principall both wordes &amp; matters, which are comprehended in the newe Teſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, Gathered by T. W.</p>
            <p>Imprinted at London by Chriſtopher Barker, Printer to the Queenes moſt excellent Maieſtie.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Cum priuilegio.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Anno Domini. 1579.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:181144:2"/>
            <head>TO THE READ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>His Table folowing, was for thy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> (good Christian reader) taken in hand, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> through Gods goodnes perfourmed &amp; accompli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhed, as thou ſeeſt. For the better vnderſtanding whereof, thou art diligently to remember, that ſuch titles as concerne the ſenſe and meaning of the Scripture, are marked thus ✿. Such as reſpect Doctrine, ey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther touching fayth, or maners, are marked thus <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g>. As for the proper names of men, places &amp;c. they haue no note at all ſet before them. So that thou maieſt eaſelie knowe (by holding the notes and markes) to diſcerne, yea, to referre euery point herein comprehen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, to his right end and purpoſe. Furthermore, this alſo hath bene obſerued on thy behalfe, that looke whatſoeuer titles beginne with one worde, though perhappes they conteyne ſeuerall &amp; diuers mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, yet they are included thus [. The Lord remoue al our ſinnes, as farre from vs, as the Eaſt is from the Weſt, that by that meanes through his ſpecial bleſſing, this and all other good labors, attemp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted for the instruction of his children, may (in theſe ignorant daies, and doting olde age of the worlde) become fruitfull, ſo that our in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward man may growe vp in all holy knowledge, and ſpirituall vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtanding, and we expreſſe the fruites of bleſſed obedience in our liues and conuerſation, till we come at the last to reape that eternall perfection, which he hath reſerued to giue vnto vs in the last day, through Christ Ieſus our Lord, &amp; onely Saui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our. So be it.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:181144:2"/>
            <head>A TABLE MADE AFTER THE ORDER OF THE ALPHABET, CONTEYNING THE PRINCIPALL BOTH WORDS and matters, which are comprehended in the newe Teſtament.</head>
            <p>THE FIRST NVMBER NOTETH the Chapter of the Booke, and the ſecond num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber the verſe of the Chapter.</p>
            <div n="A" type="part">
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Aron. Hebrues 5. verſe 4.</item>
                  <item>Abaddon. Reuelation 9.11.</item>
                  <item>Abba. Marke 14.36. Rom. 8.13. Gal. 4.6.</item>
                  <item>Abel. Matth. 23.35.</item>
                  <item>Abel offered by faith. Heb. 11.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Abide in Chriſt, and not to abide in him, with the vnlike fruites of eyther. Iohn 15.46.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Abomination in the ſight of God, is that which is highly eſteemed among men. Luke 16.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Abomination of deſolation, ſet vp in the holy place. Matth. 24.15. Marke 13.14.</item>
                  <item>Abraham the father of them that beleeue. Rom. 4.11, 16.</item>
                  <item>He was iuſtified by faith. Rom. 4.3.</item>
                  <item>He is named the heire of the world. Rom. 4.13.</item>
                  <item>He ſawe the day of Chriſt. Iohn 8.56.</item>
                  <item>He doubted not of Gods promiſe. Rom. 4.18, 19, 20.</item>
                  <item>He offered vp Iſaac his ſonne by faith. Hebrues 11.17.</item>
                  <item>Abrahams ſonnes who they are. Rom. 4.12.</item>
                  <item>Abrahams ſonnes are of two ſortes. Matt. 3.9. Iohn 8 33,
<pb facs="tcp:181144:3"/> 37, 39. Rom. 9.6, 7. Galat. 4.22, 23. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Abrahams obedience. Actes 7.4. Hebr. 11.8.</item>
                  <item>Abrahams boſome. Luke 16.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Abſolution, ſee Looſing.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Abuſe of Gods giftes reproued. Matth. 25.18. Luk. 15.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Acception of perſons is forbidden. Iames 2.3.</item>
                  <item>Acception of perſons is not with God. Actes 10.34. Rom. 2.11. Galat. 2.6. Epheſ. 6.9. Coloſſ. 3.25. 1. Pet. 1.17.</item>
                  <item>Adam, a figure of Chriſt. Rom. 5.14. 1. Corinth. 15.21.</item>
                  <item>Adam &amp; his fall. Rom. 5.12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 15.21, 22, 45, 47.</item>
                  <item>✿ Adam which was firſt. 1. Corinth. 15.45.</item>
                  <item>Adam which was laſt. 1. Corinth. 15.45.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Admonitions priuate howe they ought to be giuen. Matth. 18.15, 16.</item>
                  <item>✿ Adoption. Rom. 8.15 Rom. 9.4. Galat. 4.5. Epheſ. 1.5.</item>
                  <item>Adramyttium. Actes 27.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Adulterie condemned and forbidden. Matth. 5.27, 28, 32. Matth. 15.19. Matth. 19.9. Marke 10.11. Iohn 8.4, 5. Rom. 7.3. Rom. 13.9. 1. Corin. 6.9. Galat. 5.19. Heb. 13.4. Iames 4.4. 2. Peter. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Affinitie carnal litle profiteth to godlyneſſe. Iohn. 7.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Afflictions are neceſſarie &amp; profitable. Luke 15.14, 17. Philipp. 1.12.13. 1. Theſſ. 3.3. 2. Theſſ. 1.4, 5. 2. Tim. 1.8. 2. Tim. 2.12. Hebr. 12.5, 6.7.</item>
                  <item>Afflictions are of God. Actes. 2.23. Actes 4.27, 28. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinthians. 4.9. Philip. 1.29. Hebrewes. 12.6. 1. Peter. 3.17. 1. Peter 4.19.</item>
                  <item>Afflictions of the godly are diuers and many. Matth. 5.11. Actes 14.22. 2. Tim. 3.12. Iames 1.2. 1. Peter. 6.</item>
                  <item>Afflictions of the godly in this life, are light and of ſhort continuance in reſpect of the life layed vp for them. Rom. 8.18. 2. Timoth. 4 17. 1. Peter. 1.6 1. Peter. 5.10.</item>
                  <item>Afflictions come to the faithfull Matth 24.9. Actes 7.10. Actes 14.22. 2. Corinth. 4.8. 2. Corinth. 6.4. 2. Corinth. 8. 2. Hebr. 11.36, 37.</item>
                  <item>Agabus a Prophet. Actes 11.28.</item>
                  <item>Agar. Galat 4.25.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:3"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Agreement or concord of brethren. Matth. 23.8. Iohn 20.26. Actes. 2.44, 46.</item>
                  <item>Agrippa king. Actes 25.13.</item>
                  <item>✿ All, an vniuerſall terme, is not alwayes vſed vniuerſally. Luke 6.26. Rom. 11.32. 1. Corinth. 6.12. 1. Corinth. 10.23. 1. Corinth. 13.7. 1. Cor. 15.22. Philip. 2.21. Coloſſ. 3.20. 1. Tim. 2.4, 6. Titus 2.11. Reuel. 13.16.</item>
                  <item>All, put for many. Actes 9.35. Actes 10.38. Philip. 2.21.</item>
                  <item>All, put for the elect. Iohn. 6.45. Epheſ. 1.13.</item>
                  <item>All, put for wicked ones. Luke 6.26.</item>
                  <item>Alexander the Copperſmith. 2. Timoth. 4.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Alliance, reade Teſtament.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Almes muſt be giuen, &amp; that cherefully. Matt. 6.1. &amp;c. Luke 11.41. Luke 12.33. Acts 2.45. Actes 9.36. Acts 10.2. Actes 24.17. 2. Corinth. 9.5, 7. Galat. 6.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Almes called a ſacrifice, Philip. 4.18.</item>
                  <item>Almes compared to ſeede. 2. Corinth. 9.6. Galat. 6.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Ambition ſometimes is ioyned with hypocriſie. Luke 18.9, 10 &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Ambition is to be taken heede of, and auoyded. Matthew 18.1, 2, 3. Matthew 23.8, 10, 11.12. Luke 14.7, 8, 9, 10, 11. Iohn 3.27. Rom. 12.10. 1. Corinth. 13.4. Iames 3.1.</item>
                  <item>Ambition and examples therof. Matt. 20.20. &amp;c. Matt. 23.5. Iohn 19.10. Actes 8.18, 19. &amp;c. Actes 25.9. 3. Iohn 9.</item>
                  <item>Ambition the mother of enuie. Actes 13.45. 1. Tim. 6.4.</item>
                  <item>Ambition is a very great plague to the Church. 1. Tim. 3.6. 3. Iohn 9.</item>
                  <item>Ambition the end of incredulitie, or vnbeliefe. Iohn 5.44.</item>
                  <item>✿ Amen. Matth 6.13. 1. Corinth. 14.16. 2. Corinth. 1.20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Amendment of life, See Repentance.</item>
                  <item>Ananias &amp; Sapphira, couetous and hypocrites. Actes 5.1, 2, 3. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Ananias the diſciple. Actes 9.10.</item>
                  <item>Ananias the high Prieſt. Actes. 23.2. Actes 24.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Ancient men &amp; women ought to be honoured. 1. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mothie 5.1, 2.</item>
                  <item>Of what ſort they ought to be. Titus 2.2.</item>
                  <item>Ancients, See, Seniors.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:4"/>
                  <item>Andrewes diligence in Preaching Chriſte. Iohn. 1.40, 41, 42.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Angell will not be worſhipped of Iohn. Reuelat. 19.10. Reuelat. 22, 9.</item>
                  <item>An Angel deliuereth the Apoſtles out of priſo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. Acts. 15.19.</item>
                  <item>Angels good which are in heauen. Mark. 12.25.</item>
                  <item>Angels created by Chriſt. Coloſſ. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>Angells Chriſts ſeruants. Matt. 4.11. mark. 1.13.</item>
                  <item>An angell comforteth Chriſt in the garden. Luke. 22.43.</item>
                  <item>Angels, ſeruants to the faithfull. Matth. 18.10. Acts. 12.11, 15. Hebrew. 1.14.</item>
                  <item>Angels appeare to perſons. Matt. 1.20. Matt. 2.13, 19. Luk. 1.11, 26. Luke. 2.9.</item>
                  <item>Angels ſeene in forme of men. Mark. 16.5. Luke. 24.4. Iohn. 20.12. Acts. 1.10. Actes 10.3, 30.</item>
                  <item>Angels ſhal accompanie Chriſt at the iudgement. Matth. 25.36. Mark. 8.38. Luke. 9.26. 2. Theſſal. 1.7.</item>
                  <item>Angels denied to be by the Sadduces. Acts. 23.8.</item>
                  <item>Angells elect. 1. Timoth. 5.21.</item>
                  <item>Angels called men. Mark. 16.5. Acts 1.10. Acts 10.30.</item>
                  <item>Angells know not al things. Matth. 24.36.</item>
                  <item>Angels whe<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> they haue done that, for which the Lorde ſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deth them, do departe. Acts. 10.7. Acts. 12.10.</item>
                  <item>Angels in credit inferior to the goſpel. Galat. 1.8.</item>
                  <item>Angels, witneſſes of the reſurrection. Iohn. 20.12.</item>
                  <item>Angells are reapers. Math. 13.39.</item>
                  <item>Angels are the purgers of the Church. Matth. 13.41.</item>
                  <item>Angells deſire to behold the accompliſhment of Chriſts kingdome. 1. Peter. 1.12.</item>
                  <item>Angells are Miniſters to the faithful ones. Matth. 4.6, 11. matth. 24.31. matth. 26.53. Luke 16.22. Acts. 5.19. Acts. 12.7. See before, Angels are ſeruants to the faithfull.</item>
                  <item>Angells of the Deuil. Matth. 25.41.</item>
                  <item>Angels fall. 2 Peter 2.4. Iude 6.</item>
                  <item>Angells tongues. 1 Corinth. 13.1.</item>
                  <item>Angels ſeruice ſometimes vſed by God, to deſtroy the wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked. Acts. 12.23.</item>
                  <item>Angels euill, reade deuils.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:4"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Anger or wrath muſt be ouercome by gentlenes. Matt. 5.22. Rom. 12.19. Epheſ. 4.26, 31. Coloſſ. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>All anger not euil. Mark. 3.5. Epheſ. 4.26.</item>
                  <item>Anger or wrath forbidden. Matth. 5.22. 1. Corinth. 13.5. Galat. 5.20. Epheſ. 4.26. 1. Timoth. 2.8. Titus 1.7. Iames. 1.19, 20.</item>
                  <item>Anger we muſt be ſlowe vnto. Iames 1.19.</item>
                  <item>Anger againſt our brother, muſt be put of before we pray Matt. 5.22. 1. Timoth. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Anoint thy head. Matth. 6.17.</item>
                  <item>Anna the prophetiſſe. Luke 2.36.</item>
                  <item>Annas &amp; Caiphas. Luke 3.2. Iohn 18.13. Actes 4.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Antichriſt &amp; his kingdome, from the time of the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles. 2. Theſ. 2.3, 4. 1. Iohn. 2.22. 1. Iohn 4.3. 2. Iohn 7.</item>
                  <item>Antichriſt his deſtruction. 2. Theſſalonians 2.8. Reuela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions. 19.20.</item>
                  <item>Antichriſt, who he is. 1. Iohn. 2 22. 1. Iohn 4.3.</item>
                  <item>Antichriſt, howe he may be diſcerned. 2. Theſſ. 2 9.</item>
                  <item>Antichriſts many 1. Iohn 2.18.</item>
                  <item>Antichriſts miracles. Matth. 24.24. 2. Theſſ. 2.9, 10.</item>
                  <item>Apollyon. Reuelat. 9.11.</item>
                  <item>Apollos. Actes 18.24. 1. Corinth. 3.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Apoſtles were twelue choſen by Chriſt. Mat. 10.2. Luke. 6.13. Iohn 6.67.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles are the light of the world. Matth. 5.14.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles the ſalt of the earth. Matth. 5.13.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles the diſpenſers, or diſpoſers of the myſteries of God. 1. Corinth. 4.1.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles are Gods laborers. 1. Corinth 3.9.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles ordeyned to preache to al nations. Matth 28.19, 20. Marke. 16.15. Luke 24.47. Actes 1.8.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles witneſſes of the death and reſurrection of Chriſt Ieſus. Actes. 1.8. Actes 2.32. Actes 10 42.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles at the firſt vnſkilfull, and vnlearned, Actes 4.13.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles, Chriſtes witneſſes, Iohn 15.27. Actes 1.8, 22. Actes 2.32. Actes 10.39. Actes 22.15.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles called workemen. Matth. 10 10.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles miniſters of the worde. Luke 1.2.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:5"/>
                  <item>Apoſtles woorſhipped Chriſt after his reſurrection. Luke 24.52.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles charitie or loue Acts 4.34, 35.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles ſtriuing for ſuperioritie. Matthewe 81. &amp;c. Luke 22.24, &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles conſtancie. Actes 5.42.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles curioſitie reproued. Actes 1.7.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles humilitie. Galat. 2.9.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles had equall power and authoritie. Matt. 28.19. Iohn 20.21, 22, 23. Actes 2.14. Actes 8.14. 2. Corinth. 11.5. 1. Peter. 5.1.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles reioycing. Actes 5.41.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles groſſe ignorance. Matth. 16.11.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles feare after Chriſtes reſurrection. Iohn 20.19.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles vnorderly zeale. Matth. 19.13. Luke 9.54.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles had no certaine or ſet place appointed them to teach in. Matth. 28.19. Actes 9.32.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles of Chriſt ought chiefly to be beleeued. Iohn 15.27. Iohn 17.18. Iohn 20.21. Actes 1.2.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtle of the Gentiles, Rom. 1.5. Rom. 11.13. Galat. 2.7. 1. Tim. 2.7. 2. Timoth. 2.11.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtle of the Iewes. Galat. 2.7.</item>
                  <item>Apoſtles falſe. 2. Corinth. 2.17. 2. Corinth. 11.13.</item>
                  <item>Aquila Pauls hoſte. Actes 18.2, 3, 26. 1. Corinth. 16.19.</item>
                  <item>Archelaus. Matth. 2.22.</item>
                  <item>Aretas. 2. Corinth. 11.32.</item>
                  <item>Arimathea. Matt. 27.57.</item>
                  <item>Ariſtarchus prayſed. Actes 20.4. Actes 27.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Arme, put for ſtrength or power. Luke 1.51. Iohn 12.38.</item>
                  <item>✿ Armor of light, put for vertues. Rom. 13.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Armour ſpiritual neceſſarie for Gods people. Rom. 6.13. Rom. 13.12. 2. Corinth. 6.7. 2. Corinth. 10.4. Epheſ. 6.11, 12, 13, 14. 1. Theſſal. 5.8. 1. Peter. 4.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Arrogancie, reade Pride.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Aſſemblies holie are to be frequented. Matthew 13.54. Luke 4.16. Actes 3. 1. &amp;c. Actes 5.12. Actes 12.12. Actes. 16.13.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:5"/>
                  <item>✿ Aſtoniſhment or marueiling at Chriſts doctrine. Mat. 7.18. Matt. 13.54. Mark. 1.37. Luk. 4.22, 34.</item>
                  <item>Aſtoniſhment at Chriſtes miracles. Matt. 9.8, 33. Matt. 12.23. Matth. 15.31. Mark. 1.27. Mark. 6.51. Mark. 7.37.</item>
                  <item>Aſtoniſhment at Chriſtes anſweres. Matth. 2<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>.22. Mark. 12.17.</item>
                  <item>Athenians Idolaters. Act. 17.16.</item>
                  <item>Athenians vanitie and lightneſſe. Act. 17.21.</item>
                  <item>Attalia. Act. 14.25.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Attentiuenes in hearing, &amp; an example thereof. Act. 20.7.</item>
                  <item>Auguſtus Caeſar. Luk. 2.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Anſweare, put for to ſpeake. Matth. 15.15. Matt. 17.4. Matt. 28.5. Mark. 11.14. Mark. 12.35. Luke. 13.14. Luk. 14.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Auſteritie or hardneſſe of life maketh not a man perfect. Mat. 11.18, 19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Authoritie of holy Scripture. Act. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>Azotus. Act. 8.4.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="B" type="part">
               <head>B.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ BAbes. 1. Cor. 3.1. 1. Pet. 2.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Babbling or vaine repetitions to be auoided in praier. Matth. 6.7.</item>
                  <item>Babylon. Matth. 1.11, 12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Babylon, put for Damaſcus. Act. 7.43.</item>
                  <item>Babylon which ſignifieth a place of confuſion (as Rome) the place where Antichriſt ſhoulde reigne. Reu. 7.5. Reu. 14.8. Reue. 16.19.</item>
                  <item>Babylon hath made drunke all nations, with the wine of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> wrath of her fornication: it is the lodging of the diuels, the place of vncleane ſpirits, the ſtewes of princes and kings, and the poyſoning of all nations. Reue. 18.2, 3, 21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Backbiting is condemned. Matth. 9.11. Rom. 1.30. Galat. 2.14. Iam. 1.26. Iam. 4.11. 1. Pet. 2.1.</item>
                  <item>Balaam his doctrine and couetouſneſſe. 2. Peter 2.15. Iude. 11. Reue. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Banket prepared by Matthew for Chriſt. Luk. 5.21.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:6"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Bankers, fee feaſtes.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Baptiſme, &amp; the fourme thereof, preſcribed by Chriſt. Matth. 28 19.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme muſt be miniſtred, onely by the miniſters of the word. Matth. 28.29.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme is one. Ephe. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme is not to be denied to Infa<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ts. Mat. 19.14. Act. 2.39.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme is not to be miniſtred to the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, which be of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> yeres of diſcretio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, vnles there be trial had of their faith. Mat. 3.6.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme a ſeale of grace. Act. 2.38. Act. 10.47.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme a ſeale of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> preaching of the Goſpel Mat. 28.19.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme the pledge of repentance. Luk. 3.3. Act. 2.38.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme how it clenſeth and waſheth. Ephe. 5.26.</item>
                  <item>✿ Baptiſme of Iohn, for his doctrine &amp; office, Mat. 21.25. Act. 18.25. Act. 19.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Baptiſme put or vſed improperly. Mat. 20.22. Act. 1.5.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme is co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>maunded to be miniſtred to al that beleeue. Mark. 16.16.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme ſignifieth vnto vs, that we are buried with Ieſus Chriſt, dead to ſinne, &amp; deliuered therefrom by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> death of Chriſt, &amp; haue put on Chriſt, &amp; are made y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> children of God, by who<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> alſo we are all made on<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>, Rom. 6.3, 4.  Galat. 3.27. Coloſſ. 2.12.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme without faith profiteth not. Mark. 16.16. 1. Corin. 10.2.1. Pet. 3.21.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſmes force and vertue proceedeth from Chriſt. Mat. 3.11. Mark. 1.8. Luk. 3.16. Iohn. 1.26.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme men are but the miniſters of. Mat. 3.11. Iohn. 1.26 Iohn. 3.23, 27. Iohn. 4.1, 2. Act. 8.16. Act. 9.18.</item>
                  <item>Baptiſme put for to ſuffer tribulations or death. Mark. 10.38. Luke. 12.50.</item>
                  <item>Barabhas. Mat. 27.21. Mark. 15.7. Luk. 23.18. Iohn. 18.40.</item>
                  <item>✿ Barbarian taken in ill part. 1. Corinth. 14.11.</item>
                  <item>Barbarians and their humanitie. Act. 28.2.</item>
                  <item>Barieſus a Iewe, a ſorcerer. Act. 13.6.</item>
                  <item>Barnabas called a Prophet and teacher. Act. 13.1.</item>
                  <item>Barnabas called an Apoſtle. Act. 14.14.</item>
                  <item>Barnabas liberalitie. Act. 4.36, 37.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:6"/>
                  <item>Bartimeus the blinde man made to ſee. Mark. 10.46. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Beame or poſt in the eye. Matth. 7.3, 4.</item>
                  <item>Beelzebub. Matt. 10.25.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Beggers or loyterers not to be ſuffered. 2. Theſſa. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Belial put for Satan, or the deuil. 2. Corinth. 6.15.</item>
                  <item>Bethabara. Iohn. 1.28.</item>
                  <item>Betheſda. Iohn. 5.2.</item>
                  <item>Bethleem. Matth. 2.1, 6. Luk. 2.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Bill of diuorcement. Matth. 5.31. Matth. 19.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Blaſphemie againſt the ſonne of man may be forgiuen, but blaſphemie againſt the holy Ghoſt cannot be forgi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uen. Mat. 12.31. Mark. 3.28, 29. Luk. 12.10. 1. Timothie. 13.</item>
                  <item>Blaſphemies ſpoken by the beaſt, againſt God &amp; his name. Reue. 13.1, 5, 6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Bleſſedneſſe true what it is. Iohn 13.17.</item>
                  <item>Bleſſedneſſe of man wherein it conſiſteth. Matth. 16.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Bleſſed vſed for deare vnto God, or beloued of him. Matth. 25.34.</item>
                  <item>Bleſſed who be. Matt. 5.3, 4. &amp;c. Luk. 6.20, 21. &amp;c. Luk. 11.28. Iohn. 20.29 Rom. 4.7.</item>
                  <item>Bleſſed vſed for prayſed. Ephe. 1.3.</item>
                  <item>To bleſſe one take<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to pray for one. Mar. 10.16. Heb. 11.20, 21</item>
                  <item>To bleſſe, put for to wiſh wel. Mat. 5.44. Luk. 22.34. 1. Pet. 3.9</item>
                  <item>To bleſſe, taken for to giue thankes. Mat. 14.19. Mat. 26.26.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Bleſſing &amp; curſing proceed both out of one. Iames. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Blind leaders of the blind. Math. 15.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Blood, put for the ſoule, life and whole man. Matth. 27.24.</item>
                  <item>Blood, put for death or murther. Matth. 27.24.</item>
                  <item>Blood, put for reuengement for ſhedding blood. Mat. 27.25.</item>
                  <item>Boanerges. Mark. 3.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Bodie mortall. Rom. 6.12. Rom. 8.11.</item>
                  <item>Bodie called a Tabernacle. 2. Corin. 5.1. 2. Pet. 1.13.</item>
                  <item>Bodie called an earthen veſſel. 2. Corin. 4.7.</item>
                  <item>Bodie called an earthly houſe. 2. Corin. 5.1.</item>
                  <item>Bodie the Temple of the holie Ghoſt. 1. Corin. 6.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Bodie muſt be mortified. Rom. 8.13. 1. Corin. 9.27.</item>
                  <item>Bodie of ſinne. Roman. 6.6. Coloſſ. 2.11.</item>
                  <item>Bodie ought to ſerue God. Roman. 11.4.1. Corinth. 6.13.20.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:7"/>
                  <item>2 Corinth. 7.1. Philip. 2.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Booke, put for rehearſal. Mat. 1.1.</item>
                  <item>Booke of life. Philip. 4.3. Reuelat. 3.5. Reuel. 13.8. Reuelat 17.8. Reuelat. 20.12. Reuelat. 21.21. Reuelat. 22.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Boſome of Abraham Luke. 16.22.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Bountifulnes of God towards vs. Titus. 3.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Bowels, put for moſt tender affections. Coloſſ. 3.12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Bragging or boaſting wicked. Luke. 18.11. Roman. 1.30.</item>
                  <item>Bragging or boaſting good and lawfull. 2. Corin. 11.1, 2. &amp;c. Philip. 3.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Bread, vſed for all maner of bodilie ſuſtenance. Matth. 4.4. Matth. 6.11. Mark. 6.36.</item>
                  <item>✿ Brethren of Chriſt, or kinſmen. Mat. 12.47. Iohn. 7.3. 1 Corinth. 9.5. Galat. 1.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Brethren are all Chriſtians. Rom. 1.13. Roman. 8.29. 1. Corinth. 6.6. 1. Corinth. 8.11. Ephe. 6.21. Coloſſ. 4.15. 1. Theſſal. 5.14.</item>
                  <item>Brethren falſe. 2 Corinth. 11.26. Galat. 2.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Brethren, put for kinſmen. Matt. 13.55. matth. 22.24. Iohn. 7.3, 5. Roman. 9.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Brethren of Chriſt beleeued not in him. Iohn. 7.3, 5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Buriall of the dead commended vnto vs. Matth. 14.12. Matth. 27.59. Luke 7.12. Luke. 16.22. Acts. 8.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Burthen of Chriſt is light. Matth. 11.30. 1 Iohn. 5.3.</item>
                  <item>Burthens heauy and grieuous to be borne. Matth. 23.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Buylding or edifying vſed for teaching. Matth. 21.42. 1 Corinth. 14.17. Galat. 2.18.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="C" type="part">
               <head>C</head>
               <list>
                  <item>CAiaphas prophecieth. Iohn. 11.50, 51.</item>
                  <item>Caiaphas examineth Chriſt. Matth. 26.62.</item>
                  <item>Cain. 1. Iohn. 3.12. Iude. 11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Called are manie. Matth. 20.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ Called, put for declared &amp; ſhewed to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> world. Luk. 1.35.</item>
                  <item>✿ Called, put for accou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ted. Mat. 5.9. Mat. 21.13. Luke. 1.76.</item>
                  <item>✿ Cal on the name of the Lord, or to cal on Chriſt, put for the whole ſeruice &amp; worſhip of God. Act. 2.21. Act. 9.14.<pb facs="tcp:181144:7"/> 1. Corinth. 1.2. 2. Timoth. 2.9, 22.</item>
                  <item>Calling, ſee Gentiles, ſee alſo Vocation.</item>
                  <item>Cana of Galile. Iohn. 2.1. Iohn. 4.46.</item>
                  <item>Cananite or Chananean, Matth. 15.22.</item>
                  <item>Capernaum. Matth. 8 5. Iohn 6.24, 59.</item>
                  <item>Capernau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> ful of corruptions &amp; reproued therfore. Mat. 11.23</item>
                  <item>Capernaum called Chriſts owne citie. Matth. 9.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Care muſt be referred to god. 1. Peter. 5.7.</item>
                  <item>Care we muſt for others. 2. Corinth. 11.2. Philip. 1.24.</item>
                  <item>Care godly. Matth. 6.33. Luke 11.28. 2. Corinth. 12.10.</item>
                  <item>Care fleſhly. Matth. 6.21. Matth. 6.22. Matth. 20.21. Matth. 26.51. Luke. 9.33.54. Luke. 11.38. Rom. 8.6.</item>
                  <item>Care, read Thought.</item>
                  <item>Carefulneſſe that hath doubting with it, is co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>demned. Mat. 6.25, 26. &amp;c. Mat. 10.9. Luk. 12.22, 23. &amp;c. Phil. 4 6.</item>
                  <item>Caſtor and Pollux. Act. 28.11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Cauſe vnheard, no man ſhalbe iudged. Iohn. 7.51.</item>
                  <item>Cedron the brooke. Iohn. 18.1.</item>
                  <item>Cenchrea. Act. 18.18. Rom. 16.1.</item>
                  <item>Centurion. Mat. 8.5. Mat. 27.54.</item>
                  <item>Centurions faith and modeſtie. Mat. 8.5, 6, 7, 8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Charitie, ſee Loue.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Cherefulnes, readines or willingnes in doing any thing, verie neceſſarie for the godly. 1. Cor. 9.17. 2. Cor. 9.7. Col. 1.11. 1. Pet. 4.9. 1. Pet. 5.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Children are embraced of Chriſt and bleſſed. Mat. 19.15. Mark. 10.16.</item>
                  <item>Children praiſe Chriſt. Mat. 21.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Children taken for yong Chriſtians &amp; of ſmal capacitie. 1. Corin. 14.20. Ephe. 4.14.</item>
                  <item>Children are humble, ſimple and without malice. Mat. 18.3. 1. Corin. 14.20.</item>
                  <item>Children of the reſurrection, which can not die. Luk. 20.36.</item>
                  <item>Children of the kingdome. Mat. 8.12.</item>
                  <item>Children of light. Iohn. 12.36. Ephe. 5.8.1. Theſſ. 5.5.</item>
                  <item>Children of diſobedience. Ephe. 2.2. Ephe. 5.6. Coloſſ. 3.6.</item>
                  <item>Children begotten and borne of faithfull parents are ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lie. 1. Corin. 7.14.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:8"/>
                  <item>Childrens duetie towards their parents. Mat. 15.4. Luk. 2.5 Ephe. 6.1, 2, 3. Coloſſ. 3.20.</item>
                  <item>Childrens brynging vp. Mat. 14.8. Ephe. 6.4. Coloſſ. 3.21 1. Timoth. 3.4. 2. Timo. 1.5. 2. Timo. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Choſen, ſee, elect.</item>
                  <item>✿ Choſen to ſome office or miniſterie. Ioh. 15.16. Act. 1.2. Act. 6.5. Act. 15.22. 1. Tim. 5.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Chriſt is God euerlaſting. Mat. 1.23. Iohn. 1.1. &amp;c. Iohn. 20.28. Act. 20.28. Rom. 9.5. Phil. 2.6. 1. Tim. 3.16. Hebr. 1.8. 1. Iohn. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is Alpha and Omega. Reue. 1.8, 11. Reue. 21.6. Reue. 22.13.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt promiſed in the lawe and Prophets. Act. 3.21.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt was conceiued by the holy Ghoſt. Mat. 1.18, 20. Luk. 1.31, 35.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt hath ſo taken fleſh, that by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> taking thereof, he hath not departed from the father. Iohn. 1.18. Iohn. 3.13.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt as concerning the fleſh came of the fathers of the Iewes. Mat. 1.1, 2. Luk. 3.23, 24. &amp;c. Rom. 9.5.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called Ieſus. Mat. 1.16, 21. Luk. 1.31. Luk. 2.21.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt being a childe was ſubiect to his parentes. Luke. 2.51.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt was ſubiect to mans infirmities. Mat. 4.1, 2. Mark. 8.2. Math. 21.18. Mat. 26.37. Luk. 19.41. Iohn. 4.6. Iohn. 11.35, 38. Iohn. 12.27. Heb. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt taught publikely. Matth. 4.23. Mat. 26.55. Iohn. 6.59. Iohn. 17.14. Iohn. 8.2. Iohn. 18.20.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt preached out of a ſhip. Mat. 13.2. Mark. 4.1.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt taught with great diligence. Mat. 9.35. Mat. 26.55. Luk. 8.1. Luk. 21.37.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt vſed to ſpeake familiarly &amp; plainly. Mat. 5.23, 24. Mat 11.21, 23. Mat. 12.41, 42. Luk. 6.40. Iohn. 3.12.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt ſpake ſometimes darkely, and that of purpoſe. Mat. 13.11, 35. Iohn. 2.19. Iohn. 10.6.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt equall with God his father. Iohn. 5.18. Philip. 2.6. Coloſ. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt and the father are one. Iohn. 10.30.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt caſt the byers and ſellers twiſe out of the Temple.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:8"/> Iohn. 2.14, 15. &amp;c. Mat. 21.12.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt moſt farre from all outwarde ſhewe or oftentation. Mat. 12.19.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt hated of the world. 4.29. Iohn. 1.10, 11. Iohn. 5.16. Iohn 7.7. Iohn. 15.18, 23.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt ſometimes gaue place to the rage of his enemies. Mat. 2.14. Luke. 4.30. Iohn. 7.1. Iohn. 8.59. Iohn. 10.39, 40. Iohn. 11.53, 54. Iohn. 12.36.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt prayed for them that crucified him. Luk. 23.34.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt died. Matth. 27.50.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt was buried. Matth. 27.57, 58, 59, 60.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt roſe againe the third day. Act. 10.40.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt aſcended into heauen. Mar. 16.19. Luk. 24.51. Act. 1.9 Ephe. 4.8.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt ſitteth at the right hand of the Father in heauen. Mark. 16.19. Rom. 8.34. Coloſſ. 3.1. Heb. 1.3. Heb. 8.1. Heb. 10.12. 1. Pet. 3.22.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt hath a perpetuall care ouer his Church. Mat. 9.36. Matth. 21.41. Iohn. 17.12.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is to be looked for from heauen. Phil. 3.20. 1. Theſſ. 1 10. 2. Theſſa. 1.7.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the only Maſter who<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> we muſt heare in y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Church. Matth. 17.5. Matth. 23.8. Mark. 9.7. Iohn. 13.13. Act. 3.22.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt hath not taken away original ſinne only, but alſo all other offences. Iohn. 1.29. Rom. 5.16. 1. Iohn. 1.7.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt onely knoweth the father. Matth. 11.27. Iohn. 6.46. Iohn. 17.25.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt full of the holy Ghoſt. Luk. 4.18. Iohn. 3.34.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt onely is to be preached in the Church. Act. 11.20.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt onely maketh God manifeſt. Matt. 11.27. 2. Cor. 4.6.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt only hath ſatiſfied for vs. Mat. 20.28. Mat. 26.28. Ioh. 1.29. Iohn. 3.18. Rom. 3.25. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 8.34. 1. Cor. 1.30. 2. Cor. 5.18. Gal. 1.4. Ephe. 5.25. Coloſſ. 1.14 20. 1. Theſſ. 5.10. 1. Timot. 1.15. 1. Tim. 2.6. Titus. 2.14. Hebr. 1.3. Hebr. 9.12. Hebr. 10.10. 1. Pet. 2.24. 1. Iohn. 4.10.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt alone is ſufficient to ſaluation. Act. 16.31.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt giueth more vnto his, then they hope or looke for. Iohn. 11.23. &amp;c.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:9"/>
                  <item>Chriſt onely can make to liue or giue life. Iohn. 11.25.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called the laſt Adam. 1. Corin. 15.45.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt the perpetuall aduocate of his Church. Iohn. 14.16. 1. Iohn. 2.1.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is our aduocate. Rom. 8.34. 1. Iohn. 2.1, 2.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called an Angel. Act. 7.30. Reue. 7.2. Reue. 8.3. Reue. 10.1. Reuel. 20.1.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the lambe of God. Iohn. 1.29, 36. Reuel. 14.1, 10.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the fountaine and beginning of bleſſedneſſe. Acts. 3.26.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt the authour and cauſe of ſounde &amp; perfect ioy. Iohn. 15.11.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the author of miracles. Act. 3.5, 12, 13, 16. Acts. 4.10. Act. 9.34.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> author of ſaluation. Mat. 1.21. Act. 4.12. Act. 5.31.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the author of life. Iohn. 6.57. Act. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the head of his Church. Matth. 10.25. Ephe. 1.22. Ephe. 4.15. Ephe. 5.23. Coloſſ. 1.18. Coloſſ. 2.10, 19.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the knower and ſearcher of hearts. Mat. 9.2, 4. Mat. 12.25. Matth. 22.18. Mark. 2.8. Luk. 6.8. Luk. 7.4. Luk. 11.17. Luk. 9.47. Iohn. 1.47. Iohn. 2.24. Iohn. 5.42. Ioh. 6.64. Iohn. 13.11, 18. Reue. 2.23. Reue. 3.14, 15.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is Lord of all. Mat. 28.18. Phil. 2.9, 10. Coloſſ. 2.10.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is called the Church. 1. Corin. 12.12.</item>
                  <item>Chriſts example ſet out for the faithfull to followe. Mat. 11.29. Matth. 20.28. Iohn. 13.14, 15. Rom. 15.3. 2. Corin. 8.9. Epheſi. 5.2. Phil. 2.5. Coloſſ. 3.13. Hebre. 12.2. 1. Pet. 2.21 1. Iohn. 2.6.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called Dauids ſonne. Mat. 1.1. Mat. 9.27. Matt. 15.22. Matth. 20.30. Matth. 21.9. Matth. 22.42. Rom. 1.1.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is by nature the ſonne of God. Matt. 3.17. Mat. 14.33. Mat. 16.16. Mat. 17.5. Mat. 27.54. Mark. 1.1. Mar. 3.11. Mar. 5.7. Luk. 1.32, 35. Ioh. 1.14, 18, 34, 49. Iohn. 3.16, 17. Iohn. 9 35, 37. Iohn. 10.36. Iohn. 11.4, 27. Iohn. 20.31. Act. 4.27.30. Act. 8.37. Act. 13.33. Rom. 1.3, 4. Rom. 8.29, 32. Galat. 2.20. Galat. 4.4. Coloſſ. 1.13. Hebr. 1.5. Hebr. 3.6. Hebr. 4.14. 2. Pet. 1.17. 1. Iohn. 1.3.1. Iohn. 4.15.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called the ſonne of man. Mat. 8.20. Mat. 12.8, 40. Mat.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:9"/> 16.13. Matth. 24.27, 30. Matt. 25.31. Matt. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>10. Marke 9.9. Marke 10.33, 45. Marke 13 <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 21. Luke 5.24. Luke 9.22, 44. Luke 17.22. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 19.10. Luke 22.22 Iohn 1.51. Iohn 3.13. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 6.27, 53. Iohn 12.23. Actes 7.56.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the onely foundation of our fayth <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the onely foundation and chiefe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> of his Church. Matt. 16 18. Matth. 21.42. Acts 4.11. 1. Corinth. 3.11. Epheſ. 2.19, 20. Coloſſ. 2.7. &amp;c. 1. Peter 2.6, 7.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the brother of all the faythful ones. Matth. 12.50. Iohn 20.7. Rom. 8 29. Hebr. 2.11, 12.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the glorie of the faythfull. Philip. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt very man. Luke 2.40. Rom. 9.5. Galat. 4.1. 1. Timoth. 2.5. 1. Timoth. 3.16. 2. Timoth. 2.8. Hebr. 10.20.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the liuely image of God his father. 2. Corinth. 4.4. Coloſſ. 1.15. Hebr. 1.3.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt the iudge of the whole world. Matt. 3.12. mat. 16.27. matt. 25.32. Iohn 5.22. Acts 10.42. Acts 17.31. Rom. 14.10. 2. Corinth. 5.10. 2. Theſſal. 1.7, 8. Reuelat. 1.5, 7.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt a common iuſtifier to all beleeuers. Acts 13.39.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called Iuſt. Acts 7.52. 1. Peter 3.18. 1. Iohn. 2.1.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the end of the lawe. Matth. 5.17. Rom. 10.4.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt free from corruption. Acts 2.27. Acts 13.31.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt free from all ſinne. Iohn 8.46. 2. Corint. 5.21. Hebr. 4.15. Heb. 7.26. 1. Peter 1.19. 1. Peter 2.22. 1. Peter. 3.18.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the true light of the worlde. Matthewe 4.15, 16. Luke 2.32. Iohn 1.4, 9. Iohn 8.12. Iohn 9.5. Iohn 12.35, 46.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the mediator betwene God and men. Matt. 3.17. Matth. 7.5. Iohn 1.29. Iohn 14.13, 14, 16. Iohn 16.24. Actes 13.38. Romanes 5.11. Rom. 8.34. 1. Corinth. 6.11. 1. Corinth. 15.22. 2. Corinth. 5.18, 19. Galat. 3.19, 20. Epheſ. 2.14, 16, 18. Epheſ. 5.20. Coloſſ. 1.20. 1. Timoth. 2.5. Heb. 3.1. Heb. 4.14, 16. Heb. 7.22, 25. Heb. 12.24. Hebr. 13.15. 1. Peter 2.5. 1. Iohn 2.1, 2. 1. Iohn. 4.10.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt was by the eternall councell of God appoynted to death. Matth. 26.18, 53, 54. Luke 18.31, 32. Actes 2.23. Actes 4.28.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:10"/>
                  <item>Chriſt was not put out or deſtroyed by death. Matth. 12.40. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 18, 20. Acts 5.3. Acts 8.33. Acts 13.33. Reuel. 1. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>. 5.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>deed dead. Matth. 27.57. &amp;c. Iohn 19.33.</item>
                  <item>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>lingly, and of his owne accord. Matth. 26.2. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </item>
                  <item>Chriſt the obiect of faith. Actes 20.21. Epheſians. 1.15. Epheſ. 3.12.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the true ſheperd of the Church. Matthewe 2.6. matthew 26.31. Iohn 10.11. Hebrewes 13.20. 1. Peter. 2.25. 1. Peter 5.4.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the Lord of life. Acts 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is a Prince. Acts 5.32. Heb 2.10.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the huſband of his Church. Matth. 9.15. matt. 22.2. matthew 25.1, &amp;c. Iohn 3.29. 2. Corinthians 11.2. E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſ. 5.23, 24, 32.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt the vanquiſher of Satan. Matth. 8.31. matth. 12.22, 25. matth. 17.18. Marke 1.23, 24. marke 3.11. marke 9.25. Iohn 12.31. Rom. 16.20.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the onely band of true vnitie. Rom. 15.5. Epheſ. 1.10. Epheſ. 2.15. Epheſ. 3.15. Philip. 4.2.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called man. Acts 17.31.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the power and wiſedome of God. 1. Corinthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans 1.24.</item>
                  <item>Chriſts comming double or twofolde. Iohn 14.3. Titus 2.13. Hebr. 9.28.</item>
                  <item>Chriſts ſecond comming. Matthew 16.27. matthew 25.31. matt. 26.64. Marke 8.38. Coloſſ. 3.4. 1. Peter 1.7.</item>
                  <item>Chriſts comming, the faythfull loue. 2. Timoth. 4.8.</item>
                  <item>Chriſtes comming is the manifeſtation of the life of the faythfull. Coloſſ. 3.4.</item>
                  <item>Chriſts co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ming ſhalbe at an vnknowe<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> time. Luk. 21.35, 36.</item>
                  <item>Chriſts affection and loue towards them which are his. Matth 9.36. Iohn 15.13, 15. 1. Iohn 3.16.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the word. Iohn 1.1. 1. Iohn 1.1.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called the creator. Iohn 1.3. Coloſſ. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called the Lord, of glorie. 1. Corinth. 2 8.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt called the Prince of ſaluation. Hebr. 2.10.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:10"/>
                  <item>Chriſt is come in the fleſhe. Iohn 1.14. Hebrewes 2.14. 1. Iohn 4.2.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt was circumciſed and preſented in the Temple. Luke 2.22, 27.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt grewe in wiſedome and age. Luke 2.40, 52.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt was baptized. Matth. 3.16.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt was tempted of the deuill. Matth. 4.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt preached the kingdome of God and confirmed it with miracles, this is proued throughout the Euange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſts them ſelues. Matth. Marke, Luke &amp; Iohn.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt ſent of God. Iohn 3.17. Iohn 5.36. Iohn 6.29. Iohn 7.28. Iohn 8.16, 26, 42. Iohn 10.36. Iohn 12.44. Iohn 17.21. Iohn 20.21. Rom. 8.3.</item>
                  <item>Chriſt is the heire of all things. Heb. 1.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Chriſtians were called brethren. Iohn 21.23. Acts 14.2. 1. Corinth. 6.6.</item>
                  <item>Chriſtians ſo called firſt in Antiochia Acts 11.26.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Church what it is. 1. Timoth. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Church is Chriſtes wife or ſpouſe. Epheſ. 5.32. 2. Corinth. 11.2. Reuelat. 21.2, 9.</item>
                  <item>Church is Chriſtes body. Epheſians 1.23. Coloſſians 1.24. Coloſſ. 2.19.</item>
                  <item>Church is the houſe of God. 1. Timoth. 3.15. Heb. 3.5. Heb. 10.21. 1. Peter 4.17.</item>
                  <item>Church is Gods heritage. 1. Peter 5.3.</item>
                  <item>Church is the pillar and aſſurance of trueth. 1. Timot. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Church is holie. 1. Corinth. 1.2. Epheſ. 5.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Church, put for the elders of the Church. Matth. 18.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Church, put for the faythfull of one countrey or towne, or houſe. Actes 14.23. Romanes 16.1. 1. Corinthians 1.2. 1. Corinthians 16.1. 2. Corinthians 1.1. Galat. 1.2. Coloſſ. 1.15.</item>
                  <item>Church muſt do all thinges orderly. 1. Corinth. 14.14.</item>
                  <item>Church heareth not, nor hath any other doctrine then Chriſtes word. Iohn 8.47. Iohn 10.3. Iohn 18.37. 2. Ioh. 9.10, 11.</item>
                  <item>Church muſt be heard. Matth. 18.17.</item>
                  <item>Cilicia. Galat. 1.21.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:11"/>
                  <item>✿ Circumciſion double or twofolde. Rom. 2.28, 29. Epheſ. 2.11. Philip. 3.3. Coloſſ. 2 11.</item>
                  <item>Circumciſion which is in the fleſh. Romanes 2.28. Ephe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſians 2.11.</item>
                  <item>Circumciſion ſpiritual. Romanes 2.29. Philip. 3.3. Colo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſians 2 11.</item>
                  <item>Circumciſion &amp; vncircumciſion are nothing. 1. Corinth. 7.19. Galat. 5.6. Galat. 6.15.</item>
                  <item>Circumciſion miniſtred on the eight daye. Luke 1.59. Luke 2.21.</item>
                  <item>Circumciſion put for the Iewes. Galat. 2.7. Titus 1.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Cities menaced by Chriſt. Matt. 11.21. Matth. 23.37. Luke 19.43, 44.</item>
                  <item>Citie of God. Hebr. 12.22. Reuelat. 3.12.</item>
                  <item>Clauda. Actes 27.16.</item>
                  <item>Claudius Caeſar. Actes 11.27.</item>
                  <item>✿ Collection or gathering for the poore ſaints &amp; brethren. Actes 11.29. Rom. 15.26, 27. 1. Corinth. 16.1. 2. Corinth. 8.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Come to Chriſt. Matth. 11.28. Iohn 6.35. Iohn 7.37.</item>
                  <item>✿ Comfort, ſee Conſolation.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Commaundement of God. Matt. 5.19. Matt. 15.3. Matth. 19.17. matt. 22.38. Mark. 7.8. mark. 12.29. Iohn. 13.34. Ioh. 14.15. Io. 15.10. Rom. 7.12. Rom. 13.9. 1. Corin. 7.19. 1. Io. 2.3. 1. Iohn. 3.23. 1. Ioh. 4.21. 2. Iohn 4. Reuelat. 4.17.</item>
                  <item>Commau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>dements of man contrary to Gods commau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, ought not to be obſerued. Matth. 15.9. Mark. 7.7. Luke 11.46. Actes 4.19. Coloſſians. 2.22. 1. Timothie 4.1. Titus. 1.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Common put for vncleane. Mark. 7.2. Acts 10.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Compaſſion or fellowe like ſuffering together, is neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſarie for Chriſtia<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s. Matt. 9.36. mat. 14 14. mat. 20.34. Luk. 10.33. Luke 19.41. Actes 12.5. Actes 28. 2. Rom. 12.15, 16. 1. Corinth. 12.26. 2. Corinth. 1 7. Epheſ. 4.32. Philip. 2.3, 4. &amp;c. Heb. 13.3. 1. Peter 3.8. 1. Iohn. 3.17.</item>
                  <item>Compaſſion, ſee mercie.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Communicating of proprieties. Iohn 3.13. Acts 20.28. 1. Corinth. 2.8. Epheſ. 4.10. Philip. 2.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Communion of Saints. 2. Theſſal. 1.3.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:11"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Communion or Supper of the Lorde and the inſtitution thereof. Matth. 26.26. Mark. 14.22. &amp;c. Luk. 22.14, 15 &amp;c. 1. Corinth. 11.23. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Communion all ought to vſe, and that without eyther ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to it, or taking from it. 1. Corinth. 11.23, 28.</item>
                  <item>Communion often vſed in the primatiue Church. Acts 2.42. Actes 20.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Concord or vnitie co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mended. Matt. 5.23. &amp;c. mat. 6.12. matt. 12.25. matt. 18.19. Acts 2.44, 46. Acts 4.24. Philip. 1.27. Philip. 2.2. Philip. 4.2.</item>
                  <item>Concord of the wicked againſt the trueth. Acts. 23.6.</item>
                  <item>Concord, ſee Agreement.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Confeſſion of the trueth is Gods gifts. Acts. 4.29. Ephe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſians 6.19.</item>
                  <item>Confeſſion of faith is neceſſarie. Rom. 10.10. 1. Peter, 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Confeſſion followeth faith. Matt. 10.32. Luke. 2.17. Iohn 1.41, 49. Iohn 4.42. Iohn 8.55. Iohn 20.28. Acts 3.8. Acts 4.20. Acts 9.20, 28.</item>
                  <item>Confeſſion of ſinnes, an outward teſtimonie of repenta<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce, Matth. 3.6.</item>
                  <item>Confeſſion of ſinnes, what maner of one it ſhould be Luk. 15.18.21. Luke 18.13.</item>
                  <item>Confeſſion and acknowledging of ſinnes very neceſſarie. 1. Iohn 1.9.</item>
                  <item>Confeſſion of ſins to God. Luke 15.18. Luk. 18.13. 1. Io. 1.9.</item>
                  <item>Confeſſion publike. Matt. 3.6. Mark. 1.5. Acts. 19.18.</item>
                  <item>Confeſſion to reconcile loue and friendſhip. Matth. 5.24. Iames 5.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ To confeſſe, put for to prayſe, or to giue thankes, Luke 2.38. Luke 10.21.</item>
                  <item>✿ To confeſſe Chriſt. Matth. 10.32.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Confirming, ſee Strengthening.</item>
                  <item>Conſcience good towards God &amp; men. Acts. 24.16.</item>
                  <item>Conſcience good. 2. Corin. 1.12. 2. Timoth. 1.5. 2. Timo. 1.3. Heb. 13.18. 1. Peter 3.16, 21.</item>
                  <item>Conſcience euill. 1. Timoth. 4.2. Titus 1.15.</item>
                  <item>Conſcience is to be wou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ded with the knowledge of ſinne. Matth. 3.7. matth. 22.9, 10, 11. Actes 2.36, 37. Acts 3.15.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:12"/> Actes 4.9, 10. Actes 8.23.</item>
                  <item>Conſcience euil ioyned with hypocriſie. 1. Timo. 4.2.</item>
                  <item>Conſciences muſt not haue ſnares or yokes layd vpon the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. Mat. 15.2. Acts 15.7. &amp;c. 1. Corinth. 7.37. Coloſſ. 2.16.</item>
                  <item>Conſcience doubting of a thing, or ſtriuing againſt it, that thing is not to be done. Acts 10.14, 29. Rom. 14.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Conſolation or comfort which is true, co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>meth fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> God. Ro. 15.5. 2. Cor. 1.3, 4, 7. 2. Cor. 7.6. Phil. 2.1. 2. Theſſ. 2.16.</item>
                  <item>Conſolation which commeth of the ſcriptures. Rom. 15.4.</item>
                  <item>Conſolation toward our brethren, is neceſſarie. 1. Theſſ. 4.18. 1. Theſſal. 5.11, 14.</item>
                  <item>Conſolatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> of Chriſt to his diſciples. Mat. 14.27. Lu. 10.23.</item>
                  <item>Conſolation in worldly things is euill. Luke. 6.24.</item>
                  <item>✿ Contemners of the Goſpell of two ſortes. Matth. 7.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Contempt of brethren diſpleaſeth God. Matth. 18.6, 16. Luke 18.9. Iohn 7.48, 49. Rom. 14.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Contempt of the faythfull miniſters, is the contempt of God. Matth. 10.40.</item>
                  <item>Contempt of death. Matth. 10.28. Acts 21.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Contentation. Luke 3.14. 1. Corinth. 7.17. Philipp. 4.11. 1. Timoth. 6.6. Hebrewes 13.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Contentednes, ſee Sufficiencie &amp; contentation.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Contentions or ſtrifes are to be auoyded of the godly. Romanes 13.13. 1. Corinth. 1.11. 2. Corinth. 12.20. Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lat 5.20. Philip. 2.3. 1. Timoth. 3.3. 1. Timoth. 4.6. 2. Tim. 2.14. Iames 3.14, 16.</item>
                  <item>Contention or ſtrife among the Apoſtles. Luke. 22.24.</item>
                  <item>Contention betweene Paul &amp; Barnabas. Acts 15.39.</item>
                  <item>Contention betwene Paul &amp; Peter. Galat. 2.11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Continence, or to abſtaine from mariage, is a ſpecial gift of God. Matth. 19.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ To continue in Chriſts word. Iohn. 8.31.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Continuance in good things, ſee Perſeuerance.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Conuerſation of preachers, read Preachers.</item>
                  <item>Conuerſation of maried folke, read maried.</item>
                  <item>Conuerſation approued. Philip. 1.7. 1. Theſſal. 4.12. 1. Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter 1.15. 2. Peter 3.11.</item>
                  <item>Conuerſation for bidden. Epheſ. 2.3. 1. Pet. 1.18. 1. Pet. 4.3.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:12"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Conuerſion or turning to the Lord, commeth from the Lord. Luke 22.61, 62. Iohn. 6.44. Acts 9.4. Acts 26.18.</item>
                  <item>Conuerſion or turning to God ioyned with repentance. Acts 26.20.</item>
                  <item>Corban. Marke 7.11.</item>
                  <item>Cornelius. Acts 10.1 2. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Correction or chaſtiſeme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t which God vſeth towards his. 1. Corint. 11.32. Heb. 12.5. 1. Peter 4.17. Reuelat. 3.19.</item>
                  <item>✿ Couenant for the promiſe made to Abraham &amp; his po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſteritie. Luke 1.72.</item>
                  <item>Couenant, See Teſtament.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Couetouſnes y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> roote of al euil. Mat. 26.15, 16. 1. Tim. 6.10.</item>
                  <item>Couetouſnes called idolatrie. Epheſ. 5.5. Coloſſ. 3.5.</item>
                  <item>Couetouſnes the cauſe of perſecution. Acts 16.19, &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Couetouſnes is condemned. Matth. 6.19. matt. 19.22. Luke 12.15. Luke 16.14. Acts 5.3. Roman. 1.29. 1. Corinth. 5.11. 1. Corinth. 6.10. Epheſ. 5.3. Col. 3.5. 1. Theſſal. 2.5. 1. Tim. 3.3, 8. 1. Tim. 6.10. 2. Tim. 3.2. Heb. 13.5. 2. Peter 2.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Counſell of man eaſelie broken. Iohn 7.53. Actes 5.25. Acts 23.22.</item>
                  <item>Counſell of no man ought by and by to be deſpiſed. Actes 27.21.</item>
                  <item>Counſels of good men haue not alwayes good ſucceſſe. Actes 21.27.</item>
                  <item>Counſell which is good. Iohn 7.51. Actes 5.35. 1. Corin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thians 7.25.</item>
                  <item>Counſell euill againſt Chriſt. Mat. 22.15. matt. 26.4. mat. 27.1. matt. 28.12. Marke 3.6. Iohn 11.47.</item>
                  <item>Counſell euil and an example thereof. Acts. 27.43.</item>
                  <item>Counſell of God. Acts 2.23. Acts 4.28. Acts 20.27.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Courtes of Princes haue ſometimes holy men in them. Philip. 4.22.</item>
                  <item>✿ Court of Herode &amp; the exerciſe thereof. Matth. 14.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Courtiers ſhould reade the ſcriptures. Acts 8.28.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Creatures of God are all good. 1. Timot. 4.4.</item>
                  <item>Creatures ſubiect to vanitie. Rom. 8.20.</item>
                  <item>Creatures waite for the reuelation of the ſonnes of God. Rom. 8.23.</item>
                  <item>Creature newe. 2. Corinth. 5.17. Galat. 6.15.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:13"/>
                  <item>✿ Creeple healed of Peter, Acts 3.6.</item>
                  <item>Creeple healed of Paul. Acts 14.10.</item>
                  <item>Creta. Titus 1.5.</item>
                  <item>Cretians. Titus 1.12.</item>
                  <item>Criſpus. Acts 18.8 1. Corinth. 1.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Croſſe put for preaching of the Goſpell. Philip. 3.18.</item>
                  <item>Croſſe of Chriſt, put for the benefit of redemption. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 1.17.</item>
                  <item>Croſſe put for Chriſt crucified. 1. Corinth. 1.18, 23.</item>
                  <item>Croſſe taken for affliction. Matth. 16.24.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Croſſe, who are ſubiect to it. Actes 9.14. 2. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moth. 3.12.</item>
                  <item>Croſſe neceſſarie for faithfull ones. Rom. 8.17.</item>
                  <item>Croſſe muſt be taken vp dayly. Luke 9.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Crowne of righteouſnes, put for eternal life. 2. Tim. 4.8.</item>
                  <item>Crowne of life. Iames 1.12. Reuelat. 2.10.</item>
                  <item>Crowne of glorie incorruptible. 1. Peter 5.4.</item>
                  <item>Crowne of Thornes. Matth 27.29.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Crueltie is the companion of couetouſnes. Iames 5.4.</item>
                  <item>Crueltie is to be auoyded. Matth. 18.30. matthew 25.42. Luke 16.19. &amp;c. 2. Timoth. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>Crueltie and an example thereof. Matthew 2.16. reade Tyrannie.</item>
                  <item>✿ Cuppe put for the wine in the Lordes Supper. Matt. 26.27. 1. Corinth. 11.25.</item>
                  <item>Cuppe, taken for affliction. Matt 20.22, 23.</item>
                  <item>Cuppe, taken for the wrath of God. Matth. 26.39.</item>
                  <item>Cyprus. Actes 21.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Curioſitie ſpringeth from idleneſſe. 1. Timot. 5.13.</item>
                  <item>Curioſitie the mother of pratling. 1. Timoth. 5.13.</item>
                  <item>Curioſitie very hurtfull. Luke 12.29. Actes 19.19. 1. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moth. 6.5.</item>
                  <item>Curioſitie is to be taken heede of and auoyded. Matt. 11. 25, 26. matth. 24.36. Iohn 9.2. Iohn 14.11. Iohn 21.20, 21, 22. Actes 1.6, 7, 8. Actes 17.19, 21. Rom. 9.22. Rom. 11.33. Coloſſ. 2.18. 1. Theſſal. 5.1. 2. Timothie 2.14. 1. Peter 4.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Cuſtome good of the Romanes. Actes 25.16.</item>
                  <item>Cuſtome euill of the Iewes. Matth. 27.15.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="D" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:181144:13"/>
               <head>D.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ DArkeneſſe, put for the ignorance of God. Iohn. 3.19. Matth. 4.16.</item>
                  <item>Darkeneſſe, put for the whole corruption of mans nature, before regeneration. Ephe. 5.8.</item>
                  <item>Darkneſſe, which is vtter. Matth. 8.12. Matth. 25.30.</item>
                  <item>Darkneſſe, when Chriſt ſuffered. Matth. 27.45.</item>
                  <item>Darkneſſe, taken for ſinne. Rom. 13.12. Ephe. 5.11. 1. Iohn. 1.6.</item>
                  <item>Darkneſſe, put for blindnes of minde, and lacke of ſpirituall light. Matt. 4.16. Luk. 1.79. Iohn. 8.12. Ioh. 12.46. Act. 26.18. Coloſſ. 1.13. 1. Theſſ. 5.4. 1. Pet. 2.9. 1. Iohn. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Daies of themſelues are indifferent. Matt. 12.15. Luk. 13.15, 16. Iohn. 5.10, 11. Rom. 14.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Daies called the laſt ſince Chriſtes comming. 1. Timo. 4. 1.2. Timo. 3. 1. Heb. 1.2. 2. Pet. 3.3. 1. Iohn. 2.18.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Daies euill. Ephe. 5.16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Daies obſerued reproued. Galat. 4.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Daies of fleſh, put for life preſent. Heb. 5.7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Daie of Chriſt, put for the houre of death, and the laſt iudgement. Phil. 1.6.10. Phil. 2.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ Daie of the Lord put for the daie of iudgement. 1. Theſſ. 5.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Daie of the Lord, or Lords day, appointed in ſtead of the Iewes Sabbath. Act. 20.7. 1. Cor. 16.2. Reue. 1.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Daie of iudgement put for the laſt day. Mat. 10.15. matt. 11.21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Daie of iudgement vnknowen to vs. Matth. 24.36. Matth. 25.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Daies difference taken away. Galat. 4.10. Coloſſ. 2.6.</item>
                  <item>✿ Daughters, ſee Philips daughters.</item>
                  <item>✿ Dauid did eate the ſhewe bread. Mark. 2.26.</item>
                  <item>Dauid called a Prophet. Mat. 27.35.</item>
                  <item>Dauid called gods ſeruaunt. Luk. 1.69. Act. 4.25.</item>
                  <item>Dauid a figure of Chriſt. Matt. 27.35, 46. Iohn. 2.17. Iohn. 15.25. Heb. 2.12.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:14"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Deacons who ſhould be choſen. Act. 6.3. 1. Tim. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>Deacons office. Rom. 12.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Dead may be mourned for, but yet moderately. Matt. 9. 23. Luk. 7.17. Iohn. 11.19, 33. Act. 8.2. 1. Theſſ. 4.13.</item>
                  <item>Dead they are that liue ill. Mat. 8.22. 1. Tim. 5.6.</item>
                  <item>Dead men cannot communicate, nor teach vs any thing. Luk. 16.31.</item>
                  <item>Dead that die in the fayth are bleſſed. Reue. 14.13.</item>
                  <item>Dead are with Chriſt. Luk. 23.43. Phil. 1.23.</item>
                  <item>Dead dwell with God. 2. Corin. 5.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Death is the looſing or departing of the ſoule from the bodie. Phil. 1.23. 2. Tim. 4.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Death is due to ſinne. Iohn. 8.24. Rom. 6.23.</item>
                  <item>Death common to all. Luk. 16.22. Heb. 9.27.</item>
                  <item>Death called a ſleepe. Iohn. 11.11. 1. Corin. 11.31.</item>
                  <item>Death which is ſeconde. Reuelat. 2.11. Reuelat. 20.6, 14. Reuelat. 21.8.</item>
                  <item>Death not to be feared. Luk. 2.29. Act. 21.13. 2. Cor. 5.8. Phil. 1.23. Phil. 2.17, 18. Heb. 11.35.</item>
                  <item>Death Chriſt his laſt enemie. 1. Cor. 15.26.</item>
                  <item>✿ To ſee death, put for to die. Luk. 2.26.</item>
                  <item>✿ To taſte of death put for to die. Mat. 16.28. Iohn. 8.52. Heb. 2.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Debate, ſee Strife, ſee alſo Contention.</item>
                  <item>Dedication of the Temple. Iohn. 10.22.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Delightes or pleaſure. Luk. 7.25. Luk. 16.19. 1. Tim. 5.6. Reu. 18.7.</item>
                  <item>Demas, Pauls fellowe helper. Coloſſ. 4.14. Philemon 24.</item>
                  <item>Demas forſaketh Paul. 2. Tim. 4.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Denial of Chriſt hurteful and deadly. Matt. 10.33. Matt. 26.70. 2. Pet. 2.1. 1. Iohn. 2.22, 23. Iude 4.</item>
                  <item>Deniall of our ſelues commaunded. Matt. 16.24. Mar. 8.34. Luk. 9.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Deſires of youth, ſee Luſtes of youth.</item>
                  <item>✿ Deſolation. Luk. 21.21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Deſpayre. Mat. 27.5. Act. 1.18. Reue. 9.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Detraction. Iam. 4.11. 1. Pet. 2.1. See, backbiting.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:14"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Deuil cannot hurt when he wil. Matt. 8.32.</item>
                  <item>Deuil father and prince of the reprobate. Iohn. 8.34.44. Act 13.10. Ephe. 2.2.</item>
                  <item>Deuil enemie to mankinde. Mat. 13.19, 28, 39. Luk. 22.31.</item>
                  <item>Deuil compared to a roaring Lion. 1. Pet. 5.8.</item>
                  <item>Deuil, a Liar, and father of Lies. Iohn. 8.44.</item>
                  <item>Deuil prince of this world. Iohn. 12.32. Luk. 4.5, 6. Ioh. 16.11. Act. 26.18. Ephe. 2.2. Ephe. 6.12.</item>
                  <item>Deuil cannot hurt ſo much as he would. Matth. 8.31, 32, 33. Mark. 9.22. Luk. 4.13. Reue. 2.1, 2, 10. Reue. 7.2, 3.</item>
                  <item>Deuil the Tempter. Matt. 4.1. Mark. 1.13. 2. Cor. 7.5. 1. Theſſ. 3.5.</item>
                  <item>Deuil a murtherer from the beginning. Iohn. 8.44.</item>
                  <item>Deuil ſinneth from the beginning. 1. Iohn. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>Deuil a deceiuer of the world. Reue. 12.9.</item>
                  <item>Deuil the Dragon and olde ſerpent. Reue. 12.9. Reue. 20.2.</item>
                  <item>Deuil the god of this world. 2. Cor. 4.4.</item>
                  <item>Deuil the prince of the aire. Ephe. 2.2.</item>
                  <item>Deuil accuſer of the faithful. Reue. 12.10.</item>
                  <item>Deuil an euil ſpirite, reade Spirite.</item>
                  <item>Deuil or aduerſarie and enemie. Matt. 13.39. 1. Pet. 5.8.</item>
                  <item>Deuil tranſfigureth himſelfe into an Angel of light. 2. Cor. 11.14.</item>
                  <item>Deuil and his Angels haue eternal fire prepared for them. Mat. 25.41. 2. Pet. 2.4. Iude 6. Reue. 12.9.</item>
                  <item>Deuils chaſed out of men by Chriſt. Matt. 8.32. Matth. 9.33. Matt. 12.22. Matt. 17.18. Mark. 1.25.</item>
                  <item>Deuils confeſſe Chriſt. Matth. 8.29. Mark. 1.24. Marke. 3.11. Mark. 5.7.</item>
                  <item>Deuils commaunded into the ſwine. Mat. 8.32.</item>
                  <item>Diana of the Epheſians. Act. 19.28.</item>
                  <item>✿ Die in the Lord what it is. Reue. 14 13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Difference of meates taken away. Matth. 15.11. Act. 10.15. Rom. 14.14. 1. Cor. 10.25, 26. 1. Timo. 4.3. Tit. 1.15. Heb. 13.9</item>
                  <item>✿ Difference of a bodie and a ſpirit. Luk. 24.39.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Diligence in a good thing is commended and ſet foorth vnto vs. Mat. 2.14. Luk. 24.33. Iohn. 20.4. Act. 2.46. Act. 5.21. Act. 10. 7, 8.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:15"/>
                  <item>Dionyſius Areopagita. Act. 17.34.</item>
                  <item>Diotrephes, a proude and vngodly hypocrite. 3. Iohn. 9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Diſciples go backe from Chriſt. Iohn. 6.60, 66.</item>
                  <item>Diſciples of Iohn. Matth. 9.14.</item>
                  <item>Diſciples of Chriſt. Matth. 10.42. Luk. 14.27. Iohn. 8.31. Act, 1.15.</item>
                  <item>Diſciples of the falſe prophets. Act 20.30.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Diſcipline of the olde Church. Mat. 18.17.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Diſeaſes of the bodie flowe from ſinne. Matth. 9.2. Iohn. 5.14. 1. Corin. 11.30.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Diſeaſes, ſee Infirmities.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Diſobedience to the Goſpel, and to the trueth. Rom. 10.16, 21. 2. Theſſ. 1.8. 2. Theſſ. 3.14.</item>
                  <item>Diſobedience to parents. Rom. 1.30. 2. Timo. 3.2.</item>
                  <item>Diſobedience to rulers. 2. Pet. 2.10. Iude 8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Diſorder condemned by Paul. 2. Theſſ. 3.6.</item>
                  <item>✿ Diſpute by the Scriptures. Act. 17.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Diuorce and the lawfull cauſe thereof. Matth. 5.32. Matth. 19.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Do we muſt all thinges to the glorie of God, and in the name of Chriſt. Matth. 5.16. 1. Corinth. 10.31. Coloſſ. 3.17. 1. Pet. 1.11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Do we muſt to another, as we woulde ſhould be done to our ſelues. Mat. 7.12. Luk. 6.31.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Do good we muſt to all, but chifely to the houſholde of fayth. Galat. 6.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Do good we muſt to our enemies, reade Loue towards our enemies.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doing good, or doing well, we ought not to be wearie of. Galat. 6.9. 2. Theſſ. 3.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctors, ſee Teachers.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctrine true and wholſome is of God and of Chriſte. Iohn 7.16. 1. Tim. 1.15. 2. Tim. 3.16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctrine of the Scripture. Rom. 15.4. 2. Tim. 3.16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctrine of men is falſe and corrupt. Matth. 15.5. Mark. 7.11. Ephe. 4.14. Coloſſ. 2.8, 22. Heb. 13.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctrine of deuils. 1. Timoth. 4.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctrine is to be applied to the capacitie of the people.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:15"/> Mark. 4.33.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctrine is to be applyed to priuate men. Luk. 3.12, 14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctrine is not to be eſteemed by mens liues. Mat. 23.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Doctrine particular neceſſarie. 1. Theſſalo. 2.11. Iohn. 2.13. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Dore of faith. Act. 14.27.</item>
                  <item>✿ Dore of vtterance. Coloſſ. 4.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Drunkards companie muſt be auoyded. 1. Corin. 5.11.</item>
                  <item>Drunkenneſſe and drunkardes condemned. Matth. 24.49. Luk. 21.34. Rom. 13.13. 1. Cor. 5.11. 1. Cor. 6.10. 1. Cor. 11.21. Galat. 5.21. Ephe. 5.18. 1. Pet. 4.3.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="E" type="part">
               <head>E.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ EArth put for men placed on the earth. Luk. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Earth called Gods footeſtoole. Mat. 5.35.</item>
                  <item>✿ Earthquake, when Chriſt ſuffered. Mat. 27.51.</item>
                  <item>Earthquake, when Chriſt roſe againe. Mat. 28.2.</item>
                  <item>Earthquake, after the Apoſtles prayers. Acts. 4.31. Acts. 16.26.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Edification muſt be ſought in all things, and we muſt giue our ſelues to the edification of others. Rom. 14.19. Rom. 15 2. 1. Corin. 14.26. 2. Corin. 10.8. 2. Cor. 12.19. Ephe. 4.12, 29. 1. Theſſ. 5.11. 1. Timo. 1.4. 1. Pet. 4.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Edifying ſee Buylding.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Elders, ſee Seniors.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Election of God to ſaluation is eternall and euerlaſting. Matth. 25.34. Iohn. 13.18. Act. 13.48. Act. 22.14. Rom. 8.29. &amp;c. Roman. 9.11. Roman. 11.5. Ephe. 1.4, 11. 1. Theſſa. 1.4. 2. Theſſ. 2.13. 2. Tim. 1.9. Read Vocation.</item>
                  <item>Election of God, and the ende thereof. Luke. 1.74. Epheſi. 1.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Elect written in heauen. Luk. 10.20. Phil. 4.3. Hebrew. 12.23.</item>
                  <item>Elect or choſen are fewe. Matt. 20.16. Matt. 22.14.</item>
                  <item>Elect or choſen. Mark. 13.20. Luke. 18.7. Rom. 8.33. 2. Timo. 2.10. 1. Pet. 1.2. Reue. 17.4.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:16"/>
                  <item>Elias is come. Matt. 11.14. Matt. 17.12.</item>
                  <item>Elias. Luk. 4.26, 27. Iam. 5.17.</item>
                  <item>Eliſeus. Luk. 4.27.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Eloquence which is the excellencie of words not to be ioyned with the Teſtimonie of God. 1. Cor. 2.1.</item>
                  <item>Eloquence abuſed Act. 24.1, 2. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Elymas the ſorcerer. Act. 13.8.</item>
                  <item>Emmanuel. Mat. 1.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Enchaunters. Reue. 22.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Enemies of Chriſt are diuers and many. Iohn. 15.18. Act 20.30.</item>
                  <item>Enemies of Chriſt compared to Wolues. Matth. 10.16. Act. 20.29.</item>
                  <item>Enemies of Chriſt muſt not be feared. Mat. 10.26.</item>
                  <item>Enemies of Chriſt fall into great deſtruction. Matth. 10.15. Matt. 22.7, 44. Luk. 19.27. 1. Corin. 15.25. Heb. 1.13.</item>
                  <item>Enemies muſt be loued. Matth. 5.44. Luke 6.27. Roman. 17.20.</item>
                  <item>Enemies of the Croſſe of Chriſt. Phil. 3.18.</item>
                  <item>Enoch. Heb. 11.5. Iude 14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Enuie is condemned. Mat. 7.1. Luk. 5.30. Rom. 1.29. Rom. 13.13. 1. Corin. 13.4. Galat. 5.20, 21. Phil. 1.15. 1. Tim. 6.4. Titus. 3.3. 1. Pet. 2.1. Iam. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Examples of enuie. Mat. 20.24. Mat. 27.18. Luk. 15.25, 26, 27. &amp;c. Act. 7.9. Act. 17.5.</item>
                  <item>Epaphras the Coloſſians teacher. Coloſſ. 1.7.</item>
                  <item>Epaphroditus commended to the Philippians. Phil. 2.25.</item>
                  <item>Epheſus. Act. 18.19.</item>
                  <item>Epicures. Act. 17.18.</item>
                  <item>✿ Epiſtle of the Apoſtles. Act. 15.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Epiſtles of Saint Paul conteine ſome hard thinges. 2. Pet. 3.16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Equitie is commended, and examples thereof. Matt. 5.25. Matt. 7.12. Matt. 8.6, 7, 8, 9. &amp;c. Luke 6.31. Act. 20.38. Act. 25.40. Act. 25.4, 5.</item>
                  <item>Eſau, Rom. 9.13. Heb. 12.16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Euill proceedeth out of the heart. Mat. 12.34. Mat. 15.11.19. Mark. 7.21.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:16"/>
                  <item>Euill muſt be abhorred and hated. Rom. 12.9.</item>
                  <item>Euil muſt not be rendered for euil, reade Iniurie.</item>
                  <item>Euil ſpeach, reade Speach.</item>
                  <item>✿ Eunuches or gelded, after three ſortes. Mat. 19.12.</item>
                  <item>Eunuch of Queene Candace. Act. 8.27.</item>
                  <item>Enroclydon. Act. 27.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Examine, reade, Proue.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Example of a good Courtier and his exerciſe. Actes. 8.28.</item>
                  <item>Example of another man ſometimes profitable. 2. Corin. 9.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Excommunication vſed in the Church. Matt. 18.17. Iohn 9.22.</item>
                  <item>Excommunication, the beſt remedie againſt vices. 1. Cor. 5.3. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Excommunication not to be pronounced by one alone. 1. Corin. 5.3, 4.</item>
                  <item>Excommunication to bee pronounced for great faultes. 1. Corin. 5.3. &amp;c. 2. Theſſ. 3.14. &amp;c. 1. Tim. 1.20.</item>
                  <item>Excommunication abuſed. Iohn. 9.22.34. Iohn. 16.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Excuſes vaine wil not ſtande. Matt. 8.21. Matt. 25.44. Matt. 27.24.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Exerciſe bodily profiteth litle. 1. Tim. 4.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Exhortation muſt followe doctrine. Coloſſ. 3.16. 1. Timo. 6.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Exhortation neceſſarie in the Church. Acts. 2.40. Acts. 11.23. Actes. 13.15. Rom. 12.8. 1. Tim. 4.13. 2. Tim. 4.2. Titus. 1.9. Titus. 2.15. Heb. 13.22.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Experience helpeth faith. Luk. 2.20. Rom. 5.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Eye, is the light of the bodie. Matth. 6.22.</item>
                  <item>✿ Eye, ſimple or wicked. Matth. 6.22.</item>
                  <item>✿ Eye euill, put for enuie. Matth. 20.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Eye, ſingle. Matth. 6.22. Luk. 11.34.</item>
                  <item>✿ Eye for eye. Matth. 5.38.</item>
                  <item>✿ Eye right to be pulled out. Matth. 5.29.</item>
                  <item>✿ Eyes in prayer lifted vp towardes heauen. Iohn. 11.41. Iohn. 17.1.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="F" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:181144:17"/>
               <head>F.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> FAbles receiued for the trueth. 2. Tim. 4.4.</item>
                  <item>Fables of olde wiues to be auoyded. 1. Tim. 4.7.</item>
                  <item>Fables deceauable. 2. Pet. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>Fables may not be preached. 1. Timo. 47. 2. Pet. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fables all men ought to auoyde. 1. Tim. 1.4. Tit. 1.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fables, put for falſe doctrines. 2. Tim. 4.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Face of Steuen as the face of an Angel. Act. 6.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Faith, what it is. Heb. 11.1.</item>
                  <item>Faith is holpen by experience. Luke 2.20. Rom. 5.4. Iames. 1.3.</item>
                  <item>Fayth muſt not be ſeperated from confeſſion. Rom. 10.10. 1. Pet. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Faith is the gift of God. Mat. 11.25, 27. Mat. 13.11. Mat. 16.17 Mark. 9.23, 24. Luk. 17.5. Iohn. 1.13. Iohn. 6.44, 65. Act. 16.14. Acts. 22.14. Rom. 12.3. 1. Cor. 2.5. Ephe. 2.8. Ephe. 6.23. Phil. 1.29. Coloſſ. 2.12. 2. Theſſ. 1.3. 2. Theſſ. 3.2. Hebr. 12.2. 2. Pet. 1.3. 1. Iohn. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>Faith ordinarily commeth by hearing. Luk. 24.32. Ioh. 1.37, 50. Iohn. 4.41, 42, 50. Iohn. 15.3. Iohn. 17 20. Act. 2.37. Act. 8.6, 30. &amp;c. Acts. 10.5. Acts. 16.14. Acts. 18.8. Rom. 10.17. 2. Theſſ. 2.13.14.</item>
                  <item>Faith is neuer perfect in this life. Matth. 14.28. Marke. 9.24. Iohn. 11.21.</item>
                  <item>Faith obtaineth any thing of God. Matt. 8.13. Matt. 9.29, 30. Matth. 15.28. Mat. 21.21, 22. Mark. 9.23. Iam. 1.6.</item>
                  <item>Faith onely iuſtifieth, purifieth and ſanctifieth. Acts. 13.39. Act. 15.9. Acts. 26.18. Rom. 3.21, 24, 26, 28. Rom. 4.5, 11, 13. Rom. 5.1. Rom. 9.30. Rom. 10.10. Gala. 2.16. Gal. 3.8, 11, 24. Phil. 3.9. Heb. 11.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Faith is not of all men. 6.65. 2. Theſſ. 3.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Faith put for wholſome and ſounde doctrine. 1. Timo. 1.19.</item>
                  <item>✿ Faith put for the doctrine of the Goſpel. Act. 6.7. 1. Tim. 3.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Faith put for the ſumme of Chriſtia<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> doctrine. 1. Tim. 4.6.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:17"/>
                  <item>✿ Faith, put for a vaine ſhewe of fayth. Iames 2.14. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Faith purifieth the heartes. Actes 15.9.</item>
                  <item>Faith is the victorie of the world. 1. Iohn 5.4.</item>
                  <item>Faith is our armour againſt the aſſaultes of the deuill. E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſ. 6.16. 1. Theſſ. 5.8. 1. Peter 5.9.</item>
                  <item>Faythful are Chriſtes friendes. Luk. 12.4. Iohn 15.13, 14.</item>
                  <item>Faythful compared to ſheepe. Matth. 10.16. matt. 25.32, 33. Iohn 10.27. Iohn 21.16.</item>
                  <item>Faythful fewe in number. Matthew 7.13. Luke 12.32. Luke 13.23, 24. Iohn 6.60, 67. Iohn 14.22. Actes 1.15. Coloſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans 4.11. 1. Peter 3.20. 2. Peter 2.5. Reuelation 3.4. Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uelation. 20.8.</item>
                  <item>Faythfull are ſtraungers and pilgrimes on the earth. Luke 22.35. 1. Peter 1.17. 1. Peter 2.11. 2. Peter 1.13, 4.</item>
                  <item>Faythfull are kings and prieſtes. 1. Peter 2.5, 9. Reuel. 1.6. Reuelat. 5.10.</item>
                  <item>Faythfull are called Sayntes, or holy ones. Actes 9.32, 41. Romanes 1.7. Romanes 12.13. romanes 15.25, 31. rom. 16.2. 1. Corinthians 6.2. 1. Corinth. 14.33. 1. Corinth. 16.1. 2. Corinth. 1.1. 2. Corinth. 8.4. 2. Corinth. 13.12. Epheſ. 1.1, 18. Epheſ. 4.12. Epheſians 5.3. Phil. 1.1. Phil. 4.21, 22. Coloſſ. 1.2, 4. 1. Theſſal. 3.13. 1. Theſſal. 5.27. 2. Theſſ. 1.10. 1. Timoth. 5.10. Philemon 5. Hebrewes 3.1. Hebr. 6.10. Hebrewes 13.24. 1. Peter 2.9. Iude. 3. Reuelatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> 13.7. Reuelat. 17.6.</item>
                  <item>Faythfull are the Temples of God, and habitation of the holy Ghoſt, which they haue receyued of God. Iohn 14.17. Romanes 5.5. Romanes 8.9. 1. Corinth. 3.16. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 6.19. 2. Corinth. 1.22. 2. Corinth. 5.5. 2. Corinth. 6.16. Galat. 3.2. Galat. 4.6. Epheſians 2.21, 22. 1. Theſſal. 4.8. 2. Timot. 1.14. Titus 3.5. 1. Peter 2.5. 1. Iohn 3.24.</item>
                  <item>✿ Falſe prophets, reade Preachers.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Falſe witneſſe, read Witneſſe.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Families ought to be well inſtructed. Actes 10.2. &amp;c. Rom. 16.5. Epheſ. 6.4. 2. Timoth. 4.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Familie is to be prouided for. 1. Tim. 5.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Faſting, put for vnaccuſtomed abſtinence from meare. Acts 27.33.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:18"/>
                  <item>✿ Faſting ioyned with prayer. Matth. 17.21. Luke 2.37. Acts 10.30. Actes 13.3. 1. Corinth. 7.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Faſting priuate and examples thereof. Matth. 4.2. Matt. 6.16, 17, 18. Luke 2.37. 1. Corinthians. 7.5. Actes 10.30. 2. Corinth. 11.27.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Faſting publike. Acts 13.2. Acts 14.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Faſting hypocriticall &amp; true. Matth 6.16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Father and mother muſt be obeyed and honored, read Children honor parents.</item>
                  <item>Fathers &amp; mothers muſt not be loued more then Chriſt. Matth 10.37. Luke 14.26.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fathers taken for predeceſſors. Matth. 23.30. Actes 15.10. Hebr. 1.1.</item>
                  <item>Fathers muſt not be folowed in their follies, abuſes and vngodly cuſtomes. Matth. 15.2. &amp;c. Luk. 10.38. &amp;c. Acts 7.51. 1. Peter 1.18.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Faults muſt not be foſtered or borne with. Matt. 8.26. mat. 12.36. matt. 14.4, 31. matth. 15.14. matth. 18.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Fauour of men muſt be ſtoutly contemned. Actes 25.9. Galat. 1.10. Galat. 2.13.</item>
                  <item>✿ To finde fauour, put for to be in fauour. Luke 1.30.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Feare of God, ſuch as children beare towards their fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers. Acts 9.31. Acts 10.2. 2. Corinthians. 7.1. Epheſ. 5.21. Coloſſ. 3.22. 1. Peter 2.17.</item>
                  <item>Feare of God ſuch as ſerua<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ts beare to their maſters. Rom. 8.15. Luke 1.74. 1. Iohn 4.18. Reuelat. 21.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Feare vſed for obedience and reuerence towards men. Rom. 13.47. 2. Corinth. 7.15. Epheſ. 6.5. 1. Peter. 3.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Feare worldlye and carnall. Iohn 9.22. Iohn 12.42. Iohn 19.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Feare taken for trembling and aſtoniſhing. Matth. 14.26. Matth. 27.54 Matth. 28.4. Luke 1.12. Luke 2.9. Actes 5.5, 11. Actes 19.17.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Feare of men muſt be remooued from the profeſſors of the trueth. Mat. 10.26, 28, 31. Phil. 1.28. 1. Peter 3.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Fearefulnes ouermuch in miniſters, is condemned. Matt. 10.26, 28. Acts 18.9.</item>
                  <item>Feareful ones are not by &amp; by to be reiected. Mat. 27.55.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:18"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Feaſtes or bankets to make, is not euill. Luke 14.12.</item>
                  <item>Feaſtes or bankets abuſed. Matth. 14.6. Luke. 14.7, &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Feaſtes or bankets of Chriſtians, polluted by contemners of God. 2. Peter. 2.13. Iude 12.</item>
                  <item>Felix. Actes 23.26. Actes 24.22.</item>
                  <item>Feſtus. Actes 25.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Figge tree, accurſed of Chriſt. Matth. 21.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Fight or warrefare ſpiritual. Rom. 6.13. Rom. 7.15, 19, 23, 25. 1. Timoth. 1.18. 2. Timoth. 2.4, 5.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fire, put for the effect of the holy Ghoſt. Matth. 3.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fire for the trial of doctrine, made by Gods word and his ſpirite. 1. Corinth. 3.13.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fire vnque<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>chable, for the torme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> wicked. Mat. 3.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fire euerlaſting. Matth. 25.41.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fire of hell. Matth. 5.22.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fire vnquenchable. Matth. 3.11. Matth. 9.43.</item>
                  <item>✿ Firſt borne, put for al the faithful. Heb. 12.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ The finger of God, put for the power of God. Luke 11.20. or rather for the holy Ghoſt, or the ſpirite of God, as it is expounded. Matth. 12.28.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Flatterie is to be taken heede of and auoyded. Matth. 11.7. Matth. 14.4. Matth. 18.15. Romanes 16.18. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 11.17. 1. Theſſal. 2.5.</item>
                  <item>Examples of flatterie. Matth. 22.16. Iohn 18.22. Actes 3.4. Actes 12.22. Actes 24.2, 3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fleſh, put for the naturall affection of man. Matt. 26.41.</item>
                  <item>Fleſh, put for the outward ſhewe of man. Iohn 8.15.</item>
                  <item>Fleſh, put eyther for outward pompe &amp; oſtentation, or for weake ſtate and condition. 2. Corinth. 10.2.</item>
                  <item>Fleſh, put for the common courſe of nature. Galat. 4.29.</item>
                  <item>Fleſh, put for man. Matth. 24.22. Rom. 3.20. Rom. 7.18. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 1.29. Galat. 2.16.</item>
                  <item>Fleſh, put for preſent life. 1. Peter 4.2.</item>
                  <item>Fleſh, put for the Ceremonies of the lawe. Galat. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Fleſh, what it iudgeth of true religion. Acts 26.24.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fleſh attributed to fiſhes. 1. Corinth. 15.39.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fleſh and bloud put for man. Matth. 16.17. Galat. 1.16. Epheſ. 6.12.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:19"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Fleſh muſt be crucified. Galat. 5.24.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> After the fleſh we muſt not liue. Rom. 8.13.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fleſh, put for the mortall body. Philip. 1.22.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fleſh taken for the whole man. Matthew 24.22. Actes 2.17. Rom. 3.20.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fleſh, put for the corrupt nature, affection or carnall wiſedome of man. Matthew 16.17. Iohn 3.6. Romanes 7.18. Rom. 8.5, 6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Fleſh &amp; the workes or fruites therof. Galat. 5.19. Eph. 2.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Fleſh luſteth and fighteth againſt the ſpirite. Galat. 5.17. 1. Peter 2.11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Fleſh and bloud of Chriſt are our ſpiritual meate and drinke. Iohn 6.51, 54.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Flocke of Chriſt a litle one. Luke 12.32.</item>
                  <item>✿ Floore of Chriſt. Matth. 3.12. Luke 3.17.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Flying in the time of perſecution ſometimes lawful. Mat. 4.12. Matth. 10.23. Matth. 12.15. Iohn 7.1. Iohn 10.12, 13. Acts 8.1. Acts 9.25. Acts 14.16. Actes 17.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Forgiuenes of ſinnes by the preaching of the Goſpell. Matth. 16.19. Iohn 20.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Forgiuenes of ſinnes is free. Rom. 4.7.</item>
                  <item>Forgiuenes of ſinnes by Chriſt onely. Acts 5.31. Eph. 1.7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fornication put for Idolatrie. Reuelat. 2.14. Reuel. 17.2. Reuelat. 18.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fornication condemned. Matth. 15.19. Acts 15.20. Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manes 1.29. 1. Corinth. 5.11. 1. Corinthians 6.9, 13, 18. 1. Corinth. 10.8. Galat. 5.19. Epheſ. 5.3. Coloſſians 3.5. 1. Theſſal. 4.3. Reuela. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Forſake, ſee Renounce.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Free wil of man ouerthrowen. Matth. 16.17, 23. Iohn 3.3. Iohn 6.44, 45. Iohn 15.5. Acts 26.18. Roman. 5.6. Rom. 8.7. 2. Corinth. 3.5. Galat. 5.17. Epheſ. 2.8. Philip. 1.6. Philip. 2.13. Iames 4.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Frugalitie ſet forth &amp; commended. Iohn 6.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fruite of the vine, put for wine. Matth. 26.29.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fruites worthy amendeme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t of life. Matt. 3.8. Luke 3.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Fulfil the meaſure, put for to make perfect and to finiſh wickedneſſe. Matth. 23.32.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="G" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:181144:19"/>
               <head>G.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>GAbriel the angel declareth the birth of Iohn Baptiſt, &amp; ſaluteth the virgin Marie. Luke 1.13, 19, 28.</item>
                  <item>Gaius of Derbe. Actes 20.4.</item>
                  <item>Galatia. Galat. 1.2.</item>
                  <item>Galatians lightnes and inconſtancie. Galatians 1.6. Gala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tians 5.7.</item>
                  <item>Galile. Iohn 7.52.</item>
                  <item>Gallio Acts 18.12, 14.</item>
                  <item>Gamaliel. Acts 5.34.</item>
                  <item>✿ Gates of hell and what they are. Matth. 16.18.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Gathering, ſee Collection.</item>
                  <item>Gaza. Actes. 8.26.</item>
                  <item>✿ Gelded man, ſee Eunuches.</item>
                  <item>✿ Genealogie of Chriſt deſcribed. Matthew 1.1. &amp;c. Luke 3.23. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Generation, put for condition or ſtate. Luke. 16.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Generation put for an age, or the people or ſtocke li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing in that age. Heb. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Gentiles without the lawe. 1. Corinth. 9.21.</item>
                  <item>Gentiles haue the Lawe, being without the lawe. Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manes 2.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Gentiles knew not God. 1. Theſſal. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Gentiles knew God. Rom. 1.20.</item>
                  <item>Gentiles lacking the worde, are without excuſe before God. Acts 14.17. Rom. 1.20. Rom. 2.12.</item>
                  <item>Gentiles, put for the Iewes diſperſed among the Gentiles. Iohn 7.35.</item>
                  <item>Gentiles put for them which are not regenerated by gods ſpirite. Epheſ. 4.17.</item>
                  <item>Gentiles calling named a myſterie. Romanes 16.25. Epheſ. 3.3. 1. Timoth. 3.18.</item>
                  <item>Gentiles calling foretolde. Mat. 8.11. Mat. 12.18, 21. matth. 21.41. mat. 28.19. Luke 24.47. Iohn. 10.16. Acts 2.17. Acts 9.15. Acts. 13.46. Rom. 9.25. Rom. 10.20. Galat. 4.27.</item>
                  <item>Gentiles calling eſtabliſhed. Actes 11.1. Actes 14.27. Actes 15.7, 14. Epheſ. 3.6.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:20"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Gentlenes or meekenes commended. Matthew 5.5, 25. matt. 11.29. matth. 18.1, 2. &amp;c. 15, 16. 1. Corinth. 13.5. Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lat. 5.22, 23. Epheſ. 4.2. Coloſſ. 3.12. Titus. 3.2.</item>
                  <item>Gentlenes a fruite of the ſpirite. Galat. 5.22.</item>
                  <item>✿ Geſtures vſed in prayer. Matth. 26.39. Acts 20.36. Acts 21.5. Epheſ. 3.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Gift of God. Iohn 4.10. Iohn. 10.28. Epheſ. 2.8. Iames 1.17. 2. Peter 1.3.</item>
                  <item>Giftes of God are without repentance. Rom. 11.29.</item>
                  <item>Giftes of God diuers, and yet peculiar. Rom. 12.6. 1. Cor. 7.7. Epheſ. 4.7. 1. Peter 4.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Giue we ought to whoſoeuer deſireth. Luke 6.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ To giue is better then to receiue. Acts 20.35.</item>
                  <item>✿ Giue glory to god, put for to co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>feſſe a fault before god. Ioh 9.24. the like ſpeach is in y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> old Teſtame<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t. Ioſh. 7.18.</item>
                  <item>✿ Glory, put for Gods mercy. Rom. 9.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Glory all, is due vnto God. Matth. 6.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Glory vaine, or vaine glory, is to be auoided, or fled fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. Matt 6.12. &amp;c. Iohn 5.44. Iohn 7.18. Iohn 8.54. Ioh. 12.43. Galat. 5.26. Philip. 2.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Glory, ſee vaine glory.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Gluttonie condemned. Luke 21.34. Rom. 13.13. Galat. 5.21. 1. Peter 4.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Gnaſhing of teeth. Matth. 8.12. Matth. 13.50.</item>
                  <item>Gnidum the name of an Iland. Acts 27.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> God taketh care for thoſe which are his. Matt. 2.12, 13. Matt. 6.25, 26. Matt. 10.19, 29, 30, 31. Mat. 15.32. Matt. 18.6, 10, 14. Luke 12.22, 33. Luk. 18.7. Ioh. 10.14. Acts 5.19. Acts 7.3, 6, 7<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 9, 10. Acts 12.7. Acts 14.19, 20. Acts 18.10. 1. Tim. 4.10. 1. Timothie 6.17. 2. Timoth. 1.12. 2. Timothie 4.17. Iames 5.11. 1. Peter 1.5. 1. Peter 2.23. 1. Peter 3.12. 1. Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter 5.7. 2. Peter 2.7.</item>
                  <item>God is one. Marke 12.29. Iohn 17.3. 1. Corinth. 8.6. Ephe. 4.6. 1. Timoth. 2.5.</item>
                  <item>God is no accepter of perſo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s. Acts 10.34. Rom. 2.11. Galat. 2.6. Epheſ. 6.9. Coloſſ. 3.25. 1. Peter 1.17.</item>
                  <item>God onely is to be worſhipped. Matth. 4.10. Reuelat. 19.10. Reuelat. 22.9.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:20"/>
                  <item>God is the author of all good things. Matth. 7.7. Iohn 3.17. Rom. 11.36. 1. Corinth. 4.7. 2. Corinth. 9.8. Epheſ. 4.7. 1. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moth. 6.17. Iames 1.17. 2. Peter 1.3.</item>
                  <item>God is onely good. Matth. 19.17. Marke 10.18. Luke 18.19.</item>
                  <item>God is moſt ready to do good. Iames 1.5.</item>
                  <item>God is Chriſts head. 1. Corinth. 11.3.</item>
                  <item>God is the keeper of our life. Matth. 10.29, 30.</item>
                  <item>God called faithfull. 1. Corinthians 1.9. 1. Corinth. 10.13. 2. Theſſal. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>God is the fountaine of life. Iohn 5.26.</item>
                  <item>God onely immortall. 1. Timoth. 6.16. 1. Tim. 1.17.</item>
                  <item>God is inuiſible. Iohn 1.18. Coloſſ. 1.15. 1. Tim. 1.17. 1. Tim. 6.16. Heb. 11.27. 1. Ioh. 4.12, 20.</item>
                  <item>God onely is to be called vpon. Actes 12.5. Rom. 10.13. &amp;c. Epheſ. 3.14. Heb. 5 7. Iames 1.5.</item>
                  <item>God is a ſpirite. Iohn 4.24. 2. Corinth. 3.17.</item>
                  <item>God is light and dwelleth in the light. 1. Iohn 1.5. 1. Timo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thie 6.16.</item>
                  <item>God is father of all. Epheſ. 4.6.</item>
                  <item>God is creator of all things. Actes 17.24. 1. Corinthians 8.6. 1. Corinthians 11.12. Epheſ. 3.9. Hebrewes 3.4. Reuelat. 4.11. Reuelat. 10.6.</item>
                  <item>God is the beginning and the end, Reuelat. 21.6.</item>
                  <item>God woorketh all in all things. 1. Corinthians 12.6. Ephe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſians 1.10.</item>
                  <item>God, to him nothing is impoſſible. Matthew 19.26. Luke 1.37. Luke 18.27.</item>
                  <item>God giueth life and being to all. Actes 17.25. 1. Timo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thie 6.13.</item>
                  <item>God is onely wiſe. Romanes 16.27. 1. Tim. 1.17. Iude 25.</item>
                  <item>God onely holie. Reuelat. 15.4.</item>
                  <item>God is true and faithfull and cannot lie. Iohn 3.33. Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manes 3.4. 1. Corinthians 1.9. 1. Theſſal. 5.24. 2. Theſſal. 3.3. Tit. 1.2. Heb. 6.18. Heb. 10.23. 1. Ioh. 1.9. 1. Ioh. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>God is onely Prince, the King of kings &amp; Lorde of lordes. 1. Timoth. 6.15.</item>
                  <item>God is the knower and ſearcher of heartes. Actes 1.24. Actes 15.8. Rom. 8.27.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:21"/>
                  <item>God knoweth his. 2. Timoth. 2.19.</item>
                  <item>God onely forgiueth ſinnes. Marke 2.7.</item>
                  <item>God iuſtifieth and ſanctifieth. Rom. 3.24. Romanes 8.30, 33. 1. Theſſal. 5.23.</item>
                  <item>God called our Sauiour. 1. Timoth. 2.3. Titus 3.4. Iude 25.</item>
                  <item>God is iudge of all. Hebrewes 12.23.</item>
                  <item>God is the onely Lawegiuer, which can deſtroy and ſaue. Iames 4.12.</item>
                  <item>God onely teacheth and giueth true wiſedome. Iohn 6.45. Epheſ. 1.8, 17. Col. 1.9. Heb. 8.11. Iames 1.5. 1. Iohn. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>God counſeled of none. Rom. 11.34. 1. Corinth. 2.16.</item>
                  <item>God dwelleth not in Temples made with handes. Actes. 7.48. Actes 17.24.</item>
                  <item>God notwithſtanding dwelleth in his, to wit, in the fayth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full. Iohn 14.17. 1. Iohn 4.15. reade Faythfull.</item>
                  <item>God heareth vs in our requeſtes. Matth. 7.7. Matthewe 18.19. Matth. 21.22. 1. Iohn 5.14, 15.</item>
                  <item>God chaſteneth and prooueth his. Hebr. 12.6. Iames 1.12. 1. Peter 1.7. 1. Peter 4.12, 13. Reuelat. 2.10. Reuel. 3.19.</item>
                  <item>God exhorteth to repentance &amp; attendeth. Rom. 2.4. 2. Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter 3.9.</item>
                  <item>God muſt be followed and we muſt ſtriue to be like him. Matth. 5.45. Epheſ. 5.1. 1. Iohn 2.6.</item>
                  <item>✿ Gods, for Princes and Iudges. Iohn 10.34.</item>
                  <item>✿ Gods falſe, or falſe gods, as Idoles, called vanitie and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uils. Actes 14.15. Actes 19.26. 1. Corinthians 8.1. 1. Cor. 10.20. Galat. 4.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Godlines put for the true ſeruice of God. 1. Tim 4.7, 8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Godlines is great gaine. 1. Timoth. 6.6.</item>
                  <item>Gog and Magog. Reuelat. 20.8.</item>
                  <item>Golgotha. Matth. 27.33.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Good doing or well doing neceſſarie for the godly. 2. Theſſal. 3.13. Heb. 13.16.</item>
                  <item>Good doing or well doing ought to be obſerued towards all men. Romanes 12.20. Galat. 6.10. 1. Theſſal. 5.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Good, vſed for profitable. 1. Corinthians. 7.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Good things to knowe is not ſufficient. Iohn 13.17.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Good ones are mingled with ill ones. Matthewe 3.12.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:21"/> Matt. 10.4. Matth. 13.24. &amp;c. 39. &amp;c. 47. &amp;c. Mat. 22.11. Mat. 25.2, 32. Iohn. 9.16. Iohn. 12.42. Iohn. 13.18. Act. 5.1. &amp;c. Act. 20.29, 30. Galat. 4.30. 2. Timo. 2.20. Heb. 3.16, 18. Reue. 2.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Goſpel what it is. Rom. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel was to be preached publikely through all the worlde to euery creature. Matt. 24.14. Matt. 28.19. Marke. 16.15. Act. 1.8. Coloſſ. 1.23.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel is to be preached publikely and priuately. Actes. 5.42.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel called a myſterie or ſecrete and ſecretes. 1. Corin. 4.1. Ephe. 3.9. Ephe. 6.19. Coloſſ. 1.26. Coloſſ. 4.3.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel called Pauls. Rom. 2.16. 1. Theſſa. 1.5. 2. Theſſ. 2.14. 2. Tim. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel is the meſſage of peace. Ephe. 2.17. Ephe. 6.15.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel ſounded throughout all the world. Coloſſ. 1.6.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel furthered by afflictions. Phil. 1.12.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel compared to ſeede. Matt. 13.3. 1. Pet. 1.23.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel called the word of grace. Act. 20.32.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel called the woorde of trueth. Ephe. 1.13. Coloſſ. 1.5. Iam. 1.18.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel called the worde of life. Phil. 2.16.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel called the teſtimonie of God. 1. Cor. 2.1.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel hidden from the reprobate. Matth. 13.11. 2. Corin. 4.3, 4.</item>
                  <item>Goſpel is hid from the wiſe and mightie, and is reueyled to the poore and ſimple. Matt. 11.25. Iohn. 7.48. 1. Cor. 1.21, 25. &amp;c. 1. Cor. 2.7, 8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Grace, put for faith and the fruites thereof. 1. Pet. 1.5.</item>
                  <item>Grace, put for free giftes. 1. Cor. 1.4.</item>
                  <item>Grace, put for ſpirituall giftes. 2. Pet. 3.18.</item>
                  <item>Grace, put for the miniſterie and preaching of grace. Galat. 2.9.</item>
                  <item>Grace, put for free forgiuenes of ſinnes. Iohn. 1.17.</item>
                  <item>Grace, put for the whole calling of the faithfull. Heb. 12.15.</item>
                  <item>Grace, put for the efficacie and power of the ſpirite. Acts. 14.26.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Grace of God through Chriſt. Iohn. 1.17.</item>
                  <item>Grace we are ſaued by. Actes. 15.11. Rom. 11.5. Ephe. 2.5.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:22"/> Titus. 3.7.</item>
                  <item>Grace of God we ought to truſt on. 1. Pet. 1.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Grace or thankes rendered to God before meales and after. Matth. 14.19. Mar. 15.36. Mat. 26.26. 1. Tim. 4.4.5.</item>
                  <item>Grace or thankes muſt be rendred to God for all thinges. Ephe. 5.20. 1. Theſſ. 5.18.</item>
                  <item>✿ Grecians or Greekes, put for the Iewes diſperſed among the Grecians or Greekes. Iohn. 7.31. Iohn. 12.20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Grudging, ſee Murmur.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="H" type="part">
               <head>H.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ HAnd put for power &amp; might. Luk. 1.66. Act. 11.21. Act 13.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hands lifted vp in prayer. 1. Tim. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hands laid on, or put on, or ioyned as a ſigne with wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of myracles. Mark. 7.32. Act. 8.17, 18. Act. 9.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hands laid or put on, ioyned as a ceremonie in ordey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning offices of the Church. Act. 6.6. Act. 13.3. 1. Tim. 4.14. 1. Tim. 5.22. 2. Tim. 1.6.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hands put or laide on mencioned. Matt. 19.13. Heb. 6.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hands waſhing and what it meant. Matt. 27.24.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hand lifted vp, put for to ſweare. Reue. 10.5.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hands pure. 1. Tim. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hand dried healed of Chriſt. Mat. 12.13.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hand to be cut of. Matth. 5.30. Matt. 18.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hand to the plough. Luk. 9.62.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hardnes of life, ſee Auſteritie.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hardening of the heart commeth of God, who hardeneth whom he will, &amp; yet he altogether without euil. Ioh. 12.40. Rom. 9.18. Rom. 11.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heart, put for the affectio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s, or deſire of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> heart Mat. 6.21.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heart, put for the ſoule. 1. Pet. 3.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heart, put for the conſcience. 1. Theſſ. 3.13. 1. Ioh. 3.20, 21</item>
                  <item>✿ Heart, put for the will. Act. 4.32.</item>
                  <item>✿ Theſe words, All the heart, put for a ſincere and an vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right heart. Act. 8.37.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heart is the ſeat of all euill things. Matth. 15.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hearts of men are in Gods hands. Act. 28.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Heart, God beholdeth. Act. 8.21.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:22"/>
                  <item>✿ Harueſt is great, therefore we muſt pray God to ſends forth labourers. Matth. 9.37, 38.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Haſte good and neceſſarie. Matt. 24.17. Luk. 1.39. Luk. 2.15, 16. Luk. 10.4. Luk. 12.35. Luk. 24.33. Act. 10.7. Act. 20.16. 2. Pet. 3.12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Haſte to much is to be taken heed of and auoided. Mat. 8.19. Mat. 13.20, 21. Mat. 14.8, 28. Mat. 20.22. Act. 22.25, 26. Iam. 1.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hate of one towards another is forbidden. Mat. 5.44. Tit. 3.3. 1. Iohn. 2.9. 1. Iohn. 3.15. 1 Iohn. 4.20.</item>
                  <item>✿ Head of the man is Chriſt. 1. Cor. 11.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Head of the woman, is man. 1. Corin. 11.3. Epheſi. 5.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Head put for prince and Lord. Coloſſ. 2.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Health of the bodie, may be cared for. 1. Tim. 5.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heape coales of fire on the enemies head. Roman. 12.20.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heare, put for to beleeue. Matth. 7.24. Iohn. 10.8, 16. 1. Tim. 4.16. 1. Iohn. 4.6.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heare, put for to vnderſtand. 1. Cor. 14.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hearing of the word of God only is not ſufficient. Mat. 7.21. Luk. 11.28. Rom. 2.13. Iam. 1.22. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hearing of Gods word is the beginning of faith. Act. 8.6. Rom. 10.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hearers of Gods word are of foure ſortes. Matt. 13.19, 20. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hearers of Chriſt are of three ſortes. Iohn. 7.40, 41.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heauen called Gods throne. Matt. 5.34. Act. 7.49.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heauen, put for the glorie of Gods kingdome. Hebrew. 9.24.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heauen and earth ſhall paſſe away. Matt. 24.35. Mark. 13.31. Heb. 1.11. 2. Pet. 3.10. Reue. 21.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heauen and earth new. 2. Pet. 3.13. Reue. 21.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Heauen open. Mat. 3.16. Act. 7.56.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Heauenly things are to be ſought for, and regarded, Phil. 3.20. Coloſſ. 3.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Heauineſſe which is commendable. 2. Cor. 7.9.</item>
                  <item>Heauineſſe diſcommendable. Luk. 18.23. 2. Cor. 7.9, 10.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:23"/>
                  <item>✿ Hell. Luk. 10.15. Phil. 2.10. 2 Pet. 2.4. Iude 6. Reuel. 6.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hell fire is vnquenchable. Matt. 3.12. Matt. 18.8. Mark. 9.44. Luk. 3.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hell is darkneſſe, where ſhalbe weeping and gnaſhing of teeth. Matt. 8.12. Matt. 22.13. Matt. 25.30.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hereſie taken in good part. Act. 24.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hereſie taken in ill part. Galat. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hereſies ſometimes bring profit. 1. Cor. 11.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hereſies and ſectes muſt needes be in the worlde, and wherefore. 1. Corin. 11.19. 2. Pet. 2.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Heretike is to be auoyded and when. Tit. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>Herode his crueltie and death. Matth. 2.16, 19. of ſome he is called, Herode the great, of ſome, Aſcalon.</item>
                  <item>Herode his inceſt and other his wickedneſſe. Matth. 14.1. &amp;c. Luke. 13.32. Luke. 23.11. This man was called Herode An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tipas.</item>
                  <item>Herode his hypocriſie, crueltie and death. Act. 12.1, 2, 3, 23. This man is named of ſome. Herode Agrippa.</item>
                  <item>Herodians and who they were. Matth. 22.16.</item>
                  <item>Herodias and her wickedneſſe. Matth. 14.3, 8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hidde, put for ſafe and ſure. Coloſſ. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>Hieruſalem, ſee Ieruſalem.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hireling who he is. Iohn. 10.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hoſte of heauen, what it is. Act. 7.42.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Holineſſe muſt be ſtriuen to. Luk. 1.75. Rom. 12.1. Heb. 12.14. 1. Pet. 1.15, 16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Holy Spirite, ſee the word Spirite.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Honour to God and to Chriſt. Iohn. 5.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Honour to father and mother. Matth. 15.4. Matth. 19.19. Ephe. 6.1. Coloſſ. 3.20.</item>
                  <item>Honour to kings and magiſtrates. 1. Pet. 2.17.</item>
                  <item>Honour to miniſters or elders. 1. Tim. 5.17.</item>
                  <item>Honour to maſters. 1. Tim. 6.1.</item>
                  <item>Honour to wiues. 1. Pet. 3.7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Honour vſed for to helpe, prouide and to intreat wel. Mat. 15.4, 5. 1. Tim. 5.3, 17. 1. Pet. 3.7.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:23"/>
                  <item>✿ Hope, put for faith. 1. Pet. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Hope, put for promiſe. Heb. 6.18.</item>
                  <item>Hope, put for the things which are hoped for. Ephe. 1.18. Coloſſ. 1.5. Titus. 2.13. Rom. 8.24.</item>
                  <item>Hope reſpecteth things which are not ſeene. Rom. 8.24, 25.</item>
                  <item>Hope, compared to an ancker. Heb. 6.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hope ought to be certaine &amp; aſſured. Phil. 1.20. Coloſſ. 1.23. Heb. 3.6. Heb. 10.20.</item>
                  <item>Hope is to be conceiued &amp; ſtrengthened by the conſiderati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Gods benefites alreadie paſt. Mat. 16.8, 9. Rom. 5.4. 2. Corin. 1.10.</item>
                  <item>Hope is one. Ephe. 4.4.</item>
                  <item>Hope is of God. Rom. 15.13.</item>
                  <item>Hope ſaueth vs. Rom. 8.24.</item>
                  <item>Hope muſt be in God. 1. Pet. 1.21.</item>
                  <item>Hope maketh not aſhamed. Rom. 5.5.</item>
                  <item>Hope is a piece of our ſpirituall armour. 1. Theſſ. 5.8.</item>
                  <item>Hope muſt be reioyced in. Rom. 5.2. Rom. 12.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Horne, put for might or power. Luk. 1.69.</item>
                  <item>Hoſanna. Matth. 21.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hoſpitalitie, or houſekeeping (which is to receiue the poore and ſtraungers) muſt be vſed, and examples there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of. Matt. 25.35. Luk. 10.38. Act. 9.43. Act. 16.15, 34. Act. 17.2. Act. 21.16. Act. 28.7. Rom. 12.13. 1. Tim. 3.2. 1. Tim. 5.10. Tit. 1.8. Heb. 13.2. 1. Pet. 4.9.3. Iohn. 5.</item>
                  <item>✿ Houre, put for an appoynted time. Iohn. 2.4. Iohn. 7.30.</item>
                  <item>✿ Houſe of God, put for the place, where the Tabernacle or the Arke was before the Temple was buylded. Mark. 2.26.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Humilitie or humbleneſſe before God. Luk. 18.14. Iam. 4.10. 1. Pet. 5.6.</item>
                  <item>Humilitie towards men is to be imbraced. Mat. 8.8. Mat. 11.29. Matt. 18.3. Matt. 23.12. Luk. 14.7, 8, 9. &amp;c. Luk. 22.25, 26, 27. Act. 12.23. Phil. 2.3. Coloſſ. 3.12. 1. Pet. 5.5.</item>
                  <item>Humilitie counterfeit. Coloſſ. 2.18.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Huſbandes dutie. Epheſi. 5.25, 28 &amp;c. Coloſſ. 3.19. 1. Peter. 3.7.</item>
                  <item>Hymeneus an Apoſtata. 1. Tim. 1.20. 2. Tim. 2.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Hymnes and what they are. Coloſſ. 3.16. Ephe. 5.19.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:24"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Hypocriſie God cannot abide. Matth. 6.1, 2, 3. Matth. 18.35. Matth. 23.5, 13, 14. &amp;c. Act. 5.5. Act 8.21.</item>
                  <item>Hypocriſie ſhall not alwaies be cloked. Mat. 7.15, 16.</item>
                  <item>Hypocriſie is alwayes proud and ambitious. Matt. 6.5. Matt. 23.14. Luke. 7.36. Luk. 18.9. Iohn. 9.40. Iohn. 11.47.</item>
                  <item>Hypocriſie is alwaies enuious and cruell. Luk. 14.1. Iohn. 9.13. Act. 23.12.</item>
                  <item>Hypocriſie and hypocrites be diſcloſed by the Goſpel. Mat. 19.22. mat. 24.12. matt. 27.6. Luk. 2.35. Luk. 13.14. Iohn. 10.19. Iohn. 15.22. Act. 13.5. Act. 19.9. Act. 28.25.</item>
                  <item>Hypocriſie, and an euil conſcience ioyned together. 1. Tim. 4.2.</item>
                  <item>Hypocriſie condemned. Matth. 5.8. Matt. 6.2, 16. Matth. 7.21. Matth. 12.33, 34. Matth. 15.8. Matth. 16.1, 3. Matth. 21.30. Luk. 1.75. Luk. 11.39. Luk. 13.14, 15. Luk. 16.15. Iohn 1.47. Iohn. 3.20, 21. Iohn. 8.7. Iohn. 12.42. Act. 5.3. &amp;c. Ephe. 6.6. Heb. 10.22. Iam. 1.26. Iam. 3.17. 1. Pet. 1.22. 1. Pet. 2.1. 1. Pet 3.10. 1. Iohn. 2.19. 1. Iohn. 3.18.</item>
                  <item>Hypocrites muſt be preſſed and beaten with the Iudge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentes of God. Mat. 7.22, 23. Mat. 23. almoſt throughout the whole Chapter. Luke. 16.15. Act. 28.25.</item>
                  <item>Hypocrites obſeruing verie ſmall matters, careleſly neglect the greater poyntes. Matt. 9.11. Matth. 12.1, 2. &amp;c. Matth. 15.1, 2. &amp;c. Matth. 23.23. Act. 6.14. Heb. 10.5.</item>
                  <item>Hypocrites reuerence Gods miniſters after their death, whom they could not abide, when they were aliue. Matt. 23.29, 30.</item>
                  <item>Hypocrites like to whited tombes. Mat. 23.27.</item>
                  <item>Hypocrites muſt be ſharply reproued. Mat. 3.7. mat. 7.5. mat. 12.34.39. Matth. 15.7. Matth. 16.3. Matth. 22.18. Matth. 23. throughout the whole almoſt. Luk. 3.7. Iohn. 5.45. Iohn. 8.7, 8, 9, 21, 37. Act. 5.52, 53. Act. 8.20, 23. Act. 13.10. Act. 28.25.</item>
                  <item>Hypocrites and their nature or diſpoſition deſcribed. Matt. 3.7. Matt. 7.3. Matt. 9.11. Matt. 14.9. Matt. 23.4, 5 &amp;c. almoſt throughout the whole Chapter. Matth. 27.5, 6, 7. Luk. 16.14. Iohn. 7.32. Iohn. 8.4, 5, 41, 48. Iohn. 9.18. Iohn. 10.33. Iohn. 11.48. Act. 12.3, 4. Act. 21.30.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="I" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:181144:24"/>
               <head>I.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>IAcob the patriarch. Act. 7.12. Rom. 9.13. Heb. 11.20.</item>
                  <item>Iayler deliuered from death by Pauls miniſterie. Actes. 16.28.</item>
                  <item>Iairus and his ſtorie. Mark. 5.22. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Iames the brother of Iohn killed by Herode. Act. 12.2.</item>
                  <item>Iames the ſonne of Zebede, and brother of Iohn is called of Chriſt. Matt. 4.21.</item>
                  <item>Iames the Lords brother. Galat. 1.19.</item>
                  <item>Iames the ſonne of Alpheus. Matt. 10.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Iangling vaine condemned. 1. Tim. 1.6. Tit. 1.10.</item>
                  <item>Iannes and Iambres reſiſted Moſes. 2. Tim. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>Iconium a citie of Licaonia. Act. 13.51.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Idleneſſe is condemned, and therefore to be auoyded. 2. Theſſ. 3.11. 1. Tim. 5.13. Titus. 1.12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Idle words or talke condemned. Matt. 12.36.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Idolatrie or worſhipping of creatures is condemned, and therefore muſt be fled from. Act. 7.43. Act. 14.11. &amp;c. Act. 15.20, 29. Actes. 17.16. Rom. 1.25. 1. Cor. 6.9. 1. Cor. 8.7. 1. Corin. 10.7.14. Galat. 5.20 Coloſſ. 3.5. 1. Pet. 4.3. 1. Iohn. 5.21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Idolaters muſt be auoided. 1. Cor. 5.11. 1. Cor. 6.9. 2. Cor. 6.17. Reue. 2.20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Idolaters puniſhed and condemned. Reue. 9.20. Reue. 21.8. Reue. 22.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Ielouſie of two ſorts. 2. Cor. 11.2. Galat. 4.17.</item>
                  <item>Ieruſalem the citie of the great king. Matth. 5.35.</item>
                  <item>Ieruſalem and Chriſtes entrie into it. Matth. 21.1, 18.</item>
                  <item>Ieruſalem and the deſtruction thereof foretolde. Matth. 23.37.</item>
                  <item>Ieruſalem celeſtiall or heauenly. Galat. 4.26. Heb. 12.22.</item>
                  <item>Ieruſalem the newe. Reue. 3.12. Reue. 21.2.</item>
                  <item>Ieruſalem the killer and verie ſlaughter houſe of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets. Luk. 13.33, 34.</item>
                  <item>Ieruſalem called the holy citie. Mat. 4.5. Matt. 27.53.</item>
                  <item>✿ Iewes of two ſorts. Rom. 2.28, 29.</item>
                  <item>✿ Iewes caſting off foretolde. Matth. 8.12. Matth. 22.8.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:25"/> Rom. 9.27. Rom. 10.21. Rom. 11.11.</item>
                  <item>Iewes a remnant of them ſhalbe ſaued. Matth. 27.57. Luk. 1.16. Luk. 2.25, 34 Iohn. 10.16. Acts. 2.5. Rom. 9.27, 29. Rom. 11. almoſt throughout the whole Chapter.</item>
                  <item>Iewes and their excellencie. Rom. 3.2. Rom. 9.5.</item>
                  <item>Iewes blynded and beleeued not. Iohn. 12.37, 38. Rom. 11.7. 2. Cor. 3.14.</item>
                  <item>Iewes are not to be caſt of, but to be loued and prayed for. Rom. 1.10. Rom. 10.1. Rom. 11.28.</item>
                  <item>Ieſabel. Reuel. 2.20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Ignorance of the Scriptures the mother of errors. Matt. 22.29.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Ignorance of God. Acts. 17.30. Rom. 10.3. 1. Corin. 15.34. Ephe. 4.18. 2. Theſſ. 1.8. 1. Theſſ. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Ignorance may be pardoned. Act. 3.17. 1. Tim. 1.13.</item>
                  <item>Ignorance vnpardonable. 2. Pet. 2.12.</item>
                  <item>Ignorance excuſeth not for ſinne. Matth. 13.54. Luk. 12.48. Iohn. 1.50. Acts. 3.17. Acts. 13.27. Act. 14.16, 17. Act. 17.30. Rom. 10.2. 1. Tim. 1.13.</item>
                  <item>✿ Image of God in man. Ephe 4.24. Coloſſ. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>Image of God is Chriſt, ſee before in the word Chriſt.</item>
                  <item>Image of God is man. 1. Cor. 11.7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Immortalitie. 1. Cor. 15.53, 54.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Immortalitie of the ſoule. Matth. 10.28. Matth. 16.26.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Inconſtancie condemned, and examples thereof. Matth. 8.19.20,21. &amp;c. Luk. 4.22, 28, 29. Act. 28.4, 6. 2. Cor. 1.17. Galat. 1.6. Galat. 4.14, 18. Epheſi. 4.17. Iam. 1.6, 8. 2. Pet. 6. Galat. 4.14, 18. Ephe. 4.17. Iam. 1.6, 8. 2. Pet. 2.14. ſee alſo in the word Galatians.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Indeuour or labour of man is but vaine, vnleſſe Gods fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uour be preſent. Matth. 14.5. Iohn. 21.3. Acts. 5.19, 22, 34, 38 Act. 9.23, 24. Act. 12.11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Infants or yong children are to be baptized. Matth. 19.14. Act. 2.39. 1. Cor. 7.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Infirme ones, ſee Weake in the faith.</item>
                  <item>✿ Infirme in the bodie are healed of Chriſt. Mat. 4.23. Mat. 8.13. Matt. 9.7. Matt. 12.13. Matt. 14.36. Mat. 15.28. Mat. 19. 2. Luk. 14.4. Iohn. 4.50. Iohn. 5.8.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:25"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Infirmities and diſeaſes ſometimes come for ſinne, Iohn 5.14.</item>
                  <item>Infirmities ſometimes come for Gods glory. Iohn 5.3. Iohn 11.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Iniurie or wrong ought not to be done, not rendred, but to be ſuffered. Matth. 5.39. Romanes 12.17. 1. Corinth. 6.7. 1. Theſſal. 5.15. 1. Peter 3.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Intents good, not alwayes allowed of. Matth. 16.22. Iohn 4.22, 23. Iohn 6.15. Rom. 10.2.</item>
                  <item>Ioanna the wife of Chuſa followed Chriſt. Luke 8.3.</item>
                  <item>Iob, an enſample of patience. Iames 5.11.</item>
                  <item>Iohn the Baptiſt his birth. Luke 1.57. his preaching. Mat. 3.1. Luk. 3.2. &amp;c. his death and the cauſe therof. Mat. 14.3. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>He was ſent of God to beare witnes of Chriſt. Iohn 1.6.</item>
                  <item>Iohns Baptiſme, put for his doctrine. Matt. 21.25. Luke 20.4. Acts 18.25. Acts 19.3.</item>
                  <item>Iohn the Apoſtle and Euangeliſt beloued of Chriſt. Iohn 13.23.</item>
                  <item>Iohn, called Marke. Acts 15.37.</item>
                  <item>Ioppa. Actes 10.5.</item>
                  <item>Ioſephs afflictions and exaltation or lifting vp. Actes 7.10. Hebr. 11.22.</item>
                  <item>Ioſeph, the huſband of Marie the virgin. Matth. 1.16, 19.</item>
                  <item>Ioſeph of Arimathea. Matth. 27.57. Marke 15.43. Luke 23.50, 51. Iohn 19.38.</item>
                  <item>Ioſeph called Barnabas. Acts 4.36.</item>
                  <item>Ioſes. Actes 4.36.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Ioye of conſcience. Actes 13.52.</item>
                  <item>✿ Is, put for, ſignifieth. Matth. 26.26. Luke 8.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ Iſrael, put for all the beleeuers. Rom. 11.26.</item>
                  <item>✿ Iſraelites of two ſortes. Rom. 9.6. 1. Corinth. 10.18. Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lat. 6.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ Iſraelites which are in deede. Rom. 9.48.</item>
                  <item>Italian band. Actes 10.1.</item>
                  <item>Iudas the Patriarch. Matthew 1.2, 3.</item>
                  <item>Iudas the traitor called alſo Iſcariot. Matt. 10.4. Marke 3.19.</item>
                  <item>Iudas called a thiefe. Iohn 12.6.</item>
                  <item>Iudas counted vncleane. Iohn 13.10.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:26"/>
                  <item>Iudas called a deuill. Iohn 6.70.</item>
                  <item>Iudas ſelleth and betrayeth Chriſt. Matth. 26.15, 48.</item>
                  <item>Iudas ſeemeth to repent, and hangeth him ſelfe. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thewe 27.5.</item>
                  <item>Iudas his death, and the maner therof. Actes 1.18.</item>
                  <item>Iudas or Iude, Iames brother. Luke 6.16. Iohn 14.22. Iude 1.</item>
                  <item>Iudas of Galile author of ſedition. Actes 5.37.</item>
                  <item>✿ To iudge after the fleſh. Iohn 8.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Iudgement, put for equitie. Matth. 23.23.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement, put for puniſhment. Actes 8.33. Romanes 2.3.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement, put for authoritie and power. Iohn 5.22, 27. Iohn 16.11.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement, put for reſtoring of thinges out of order. Iohn 9.39.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement, put for Gods ſecret counſell and woorkes which are incomprehenſible, true, and iuſt. Rom. 11.33. Reuelat. 19.2.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement taken for Gods correction, vpon his children. 1. Corinth 11.32. 1. Peter 4.17.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Iudgement which is vniuerſal and laſt. Matthewe 11.24. Actes 17.31. Hebrewes 9.27.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement generall after what ſort it ſhalbe. Matthewe 25.31.32.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement general, what ſignes ſhall go before. Matthewe 24.29, 30. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement general the day and houre thereof is not kno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wen to any but God onely. Matthewe 24.36. Marke 13.32. 1. Theſſal. 5.2. 2. Peter 3.10.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement generall muſt be wayted for, from houre to houre. Matth. 24.42, 43, 44. Luke 12.36. Iames 5.7, 8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Iudgement of others which is raſh &amp; headlong, is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demned. Matthew 7.1. matth. 26.8. matth. 27.25. Luke 7.36, 39. Luke 12.57. Luke 13.1, 2. &amp;c. Luke 15.2. Actes 28.4. Romanes 2.1. &amp;c. Roman. 14.3, 4, 13. 1. Corinthians 4.3, 5. Iames 4.12.</item>
                  <item>Iudgement which is iuſt, commaunded. Iohn 7.24.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="K" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:181144:26"/>
               <head>K.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ KEyes of hell and death. Reuelation 1.18.</item>
                  <item>✿ Keyes of the kingdome of heauen. Matth. 16.19</item>
                  <item>✿ Keye of knowledge. Luke 11.52.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Kindnes commaunded. Coloſſ. 3.12. See meekenes.</item>
                  <item>✿ Kingdome of Chriſt eternall. Luke 1.33. 2. Peter 1.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ Kingdome deuided. Matth. 12.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Kingdome of God, put for the adminiſtration of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel. 1. Corinthians 4.20.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of God, put for the Goſpell it ſelfe. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thewe 21.43.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of God, put for all that belongeth to the glory of God. Matthew 6.33.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of God commeth not with obſeruation, but is within vs. Luke 17.20, 21.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of God, put for his ſpiritual gouernment of the faithfull in the perſon of Ieſus Chriſt. Marke 1.15.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of God, put for euerlaſting life. Iohn 3.3.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of God, put for the preaching of the Goſpell. Marke 4.30, 31.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Kingdome prepared for the elect. Matth. 25.34.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Kingdome of God muſt be entred into, through many afflictions. Actes 14.22.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Kingdome of God who are ſhut out of. Marke 10.15. Iohn 3.3. 1. Corinthians 6.9. 1. Corinth. 15.50. Galat. 5.21. Epheſ. 5.5. Reuelat. 21.8. Reuelat. 22.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Kingdome of heauen, put for the newe ſtate of the Church. Matth. 5.19. matthewe 11.11. matth. 15.43.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of heauen, for the doctrine of the Goſpel. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thewe 11.12.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of heauen, for the kingdome of the Meſſias. Matthewe 3.2.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of heauen, for eternall life. Matthewe 7.21. matthewe 5.20. matth. 19.23.</item>
                  <item>Kingdome of heauen, put for the viſible Church Matthew 6.19. matth. 13.24, 47.</item>
                  <item>✿ Kiſſing, an outward token of mutual loue. Romanes 16.16. 1. Corinth. 16.20. 2. Corinth. 13.12. 1. Peter 5.14.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:27"/>
                  <item>✿ Kiſſe of Iudas. Matth. 26.48, 49.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Kneeling or bowing of the knees not to be deſpiſed. E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſ. 3.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Knowe, put for to allowe or proue. Reuelat 2.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Knowledge of God and of Chriſt with the fruits there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of. Iohn. 17.3.</item>
                  <item>Knowledge of God is giuen by Chriſt onely. Matt. 11.27.</item>
                  <item>Knowledge of God and Chriſt not in the worlde. Iohn 1.10. Iohn 8.55. Iohn 17.25. 1. Corinthians 1.21. 1. Iohn 3.6.</item>
                  <item>Knowledge of ſinne by the lawe. Romanes 7.7.</item>
                  <item>Knowledge onelye of good thinges is not ſufficient. Iohn 13.17.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="L" type="part">
               <head>L.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> LAbor, ſee, Indeuour.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Labor &amp; trauaile co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>maunded. Luke 5.4, 6. 1. Theſſ. 4.11. 2. Theſſ. 3.12. 1. Timoth. 5.17.</item>
                  <item>Labor of Saint Paul with his owne hands. Acts 18.3. Acts 20.34, 35. 1. Corinth. 4.12. 1. Theſſ. 2.9. 2. Theſſ. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>Laodicea. Reuelat. 1.11.</item>
                  <item>Laſea. Actes 27.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Lawe deuided into two Tables. Matth 22.37, 38.</item>
                  <item>Lawe, put for other bookes, beſides the bookes of Moſes. Iohn 10.34. Iohn 12.34. Iohn 15.25. Rom. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Lawe, put for the whole doctrine of God. Iames 1.25.</item>
                  <item>Lawe, put for outward profeſſion. Philip. 3.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Lawe abrogated by Chriſt, &amp; how farre. Matt. 5.17. Rom. 6.15. Rom. 7.4. Galat. 3.25. Epheſ. 2.25. Coloſſ. 4.14. Hebr. 12.18, 19. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Lawe could not take away ſinne. Rom. 8.3.</item>
                  <item>Lawe increaſeth ſinne Rom. 4.15. Rom. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>Lawe gaue not grace. Iohn 1.17.</item>
                  <item>Lawe of libertie, put for Gods goodneſſe and mercie. Iames 2.12.</item>
                  <item>Lawe is our ſchoolemaſter to Chriſt. Romanes 10.4. Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>latians 3.24.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:27"/>
                  <item>Lawe is the ſtrength. 1. Corinth. 15.56.</item>
                  <item>Lawe and Goſpell compared together. Matthewe. 11.11, 12, 13, 29, 30. 2. Corinthians 3.6. Hebrewes 12.18, 19, 20. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Lawe a ſhadowe of good things to come. Hebr. 10.1.</item>
                  <item>Lawe, weake and impotent to ſaue by. Galat. 4.9.</item>
                  <item>Lawe morall, good, iuſt and holy. Romanes 7.12. 1. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moth. 1.8.</item>
                  <item>Lawe is ſpiritual. Rom. 7.14.</item>
                  <item>Lawe maketh ſinne knowen. Romanes 3.20. Rom. 7.7.</item>
                  <item>Lawe the adminiſtration of death and damnation. 2. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 3 7, 9.</item>
                  <item>Lawe a yoke importable. Acts 15.10.</item>
                  <item>Lawe procureth anger, Romanes 4.15.</item>
                  <item>Lawe no man can obſerue and keepe. Actes 15.10.</item>
                  <item>Lawe cannot iuſtifie. Actes 13.39. Romanes 3.20.</item>
                  <item>Lawe written of God in the heartes of the faithfull. He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brewes 8.10.</item>
                  <item>Lawe not perfectly fulfilled of the faythfull. Romanes 7.23.</item>
                  <item>Lawe giuen not for the iuſt, but for the vniuſt. 1. Timo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thie 1.9.</item>
                  <item>Lawe and the ſomme thereof. Matthew 22.37. Rom. 13.9. Galat. 5.14.</item>
                  <item>Lawe &amp; the curſe thereof, we are deliuered from through Chriſt. Galat. 3.13. Galat. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Lawe, and he that is vnder it, is accurſed. Galat. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>Lazarus the brother of Martha, &amp; his ſtorie. Iohn 11.1, 11, 43. Iohn 12.2.</item>
                  <item>Lazarus the poore man or begger. Luke 16.20.</item>
                  <item>✿ Leaſt in the kingdome of heauen who is. Matthewe 5.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Leaue we muſt all things to followe Chriſt. Matthew 19.29. Luke 14.26, 33.</item>
                  <item>✿ Legion, put for a great companie. Matthew 26.53. Marke 5.9. Luke 8.30.</item>
                  <item>✿ Lepers healed by Chriſt. Matthewe 8.3. Luke 17.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Letter, put for the lawe. 2. Corinth. 3.6.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:28"/>
                  <item>✿ Leuaine taken for ill doctrine. Matth. 16.6, 12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Leuaine, put for corrupt life and maners. 1. Corinthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans. 5.6, 7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Leuaine taken in good part. Matth. 13.33.</item>
                  <item>✿ Leui, put for the Prieſtes and Leuites. Heb. 7.9, 10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Liberalitie towardes the poore commended. Matth. 5.42. Matthewe. 19.21. Luke 12.35. Luke 16.1. &amp;c. Acts 4.34, 35. 2. Corinth. 9.9. Galat. 6.10. 1. Timoth. 6.18. 2. Timoth. 1.16. Iames 1.27. 1. Iohn 3.17.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Libertie of a Chriſtian, or Chriſtian libertie. Matt. 11.29. Iohn 8.36. Romanes 14.4. &amp;c. 2. Corinth. 3.17. Galat. 5.1. &amp;c. 2. Peter 2.19.</item>
                  <item>Libertie Chriſtian muſt not be abuſed. Rom. 14.19, 20. &amp;c. 1. Corinth. 9.18. 1. Corinth. 10.29. Galat. 5.13. Coloſſ. 4.5. 1. Timoth. 6.1. 1. Peter 2.16.</item>
                  <item>Libertie ſpirituall from the bondage of ſinne. Iohn 8.36. Rom. 6.18, 19. Rom. 8.2.</item>
                  <item>Libertie from the ſubiection &amp; curſe of the lawe. Roman. 7.6. Galat. 3.13. Galat. 4.5. Galat. 5.1.</item>
                  <item>Libertie from the tyrannie of death and the deuil. Rom. 8.2. 1. Corinth. 15.53. Heb. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>Libertie from the ceremonies of the lawe. Galat. 2.4. Galat. 5. 1. Coloſſ. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>Libertie from all thinges indifferent. 1. Timothie 4.4. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tus 1.15.</item>
                  <item>Libertie muſt not be turned to the offence of our brother, but muſt be meaſured by charitie. Romanes 14.15. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinthians 6.12. 1. Corinthians. 8.7, 10. 1. Corinthians 9.22. Galat. 5.13.</item>
                  <item>Libertie carnall. Galatians 15.13. 1. Peter 2.16. 2. Peter 2.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Life bodily compared to a thing that fadeth. Iames 4.14.</item>
                  <item>Life not to be much cared for. Matth. 6.25.</item>
                  <item>Life muſt be forſaken for Chriſt. Matth. 10.39. Iohn 12.25. Actes 20.24. Reuelat. 12.11.</item>
                  <item>Life of man is in the hand of God. Luke 12.15. Luke 13.31, 32, 33. Iohn 10.39. Actes 23.12, 13. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Life of man ſhort in this worlde. Luke 12.20. Iames 4.14.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:28"/> 1. Peter 1.24.</item>
                  <item>Life paſt or former, ſee Remembrance.</item>
                  <item>Life ſingle, ſee Single life.</item>
                  <item>Life euerlaſting. Iohn 17.2, 3.</item>
                  <item>Life euerlaſting is the gift of Chriſt and of God. Iohn 6.27. Iohn 10.28. Romanes 6.22. Titus 1.2. Titus 3.7. 1. Iohn 2.25.</item>
                  <item>✿ Light, put for all bleſſedneſſe in this life and in the life to come. Actes 26.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Lightnes, ſee Galatians.</item>
                  <item>✿ Liue to God. Romanes 14.8. Galat. 2.19.</item>
                  <item>✿ Liue to God, put for to liue with God. Romanes 6 10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Liue vnto the Lorde, diuerſly taken. Romanes 6.10. Romanes 14.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Liuers and louers in pleaſure reprooued. 1. Timothie 5. 6.2. Timoth. 3.4. 2. Timoth. 5.6.</item>
                  <item>Locuſtes. Matth. 3.4. Reuelat 9.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Loyterers, ſee Beggers.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Looſing co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>monly called abſolutio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, &amp; the right vſe there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of. Matth. 18.18. 2. Corinth. 2.6, 7.</item>
                  <item>Lot, vexed at Sodom. 2. Peter 2.7, 8.</item>
                  <item>Lots dayes. Luke 17.28. Lots wife. Luke 17.32.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Loue of a mans ſelfe, ſee Selfe loue.</item>
                  <item>Loue Chriſtian what it is. 1. Corinth. 13.1, 2. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Loue is the lawe of Chriſt. Galatians 6.2.</item>
                  <item>Loue muſt be vnſeigned. 2. Corinth. 6.6. Rom. 12.9. 1. Peter 1.22. 1. Iohn 3.18.</item>
                  <item>Loue is the effect of fayth. Iohn 13.35. Actes 4.32. Epheſ. 6.23. Coloſſ. 1.4. 1. Iohn 5.1.</item>
                  <item>Loue is the fruite of the ſpirite. Galat. 5.22.</item>
                  <item>Loue the ende of the lawe. 1. Timoth. 1.5.</item>
                  <item>Loue the fulfilling of the lawe. Galat. 5.14.</item>
                  <item>Loue is the band of perfection. Coloſſ. 3.14.</item>
                  <item>Loue, called a royall loue. Iames 2.8.</item>
                  <item>Loue couereth the multitude of ſinnes. 1. Peter 4.8.</item>
                  <item>Loue is the true marke of beleeuers. Iohn 13.35. 1. Iohn. 2.9.</item>
                  <item>Loue a ſure ſigne of regeneration. 1. Iohn 3.14.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:29"/>
                  <item>Loue commended to vs. Luke 6.35. Iohn 13.34. Ioh. 15.12. 1. Corinth. 16.14. Epheſ. 4.2, 15. Epheſ. 5.2. Coloſſ. 3.14. 1. Theſſ. 3.12. 1. Theſſal. 4.9. 1. Theſſ. 5.8. 1. Timoth. 4.12. 1. Timoth. 6.11. 2. Timoth. 2.22. Hebrewes 10.24. Heb. 13.1. 1. Peter 2.17. 1. Peter 3.8. 1. Peter 4.8. 2. Peter 1.7. 1. Iohn 4.7, 11.</item>
                  <item>Loue and examples thereof. Actes 4.32, 34. Iohn 15.12. Hebrewes 6.10.</item>
                  <item>Loue towardes God. Matth. 22.37. Marke 12.30.</item>
                  <item>Loue to Chriſt. Matth. 10.37.</item>
                  <item>Loue toward our neighbour. Matth. 5.43. Matt. 22.39. Luke 10.27. Galat. 5.14. Iames 2.8.</item>
                  <item>Loue of one towards an other. Ioh 13.34. Rom. 12.10. Rom. 13.8. 1. Theſſ. 4.9. 1. Peter 1.20. 1. Iohn 3.11.</item>
                  <item>Loue towardes our enemies. Matth. 5.44. Luke 6.35. Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manes 12.20.</item>
                  <item>Loue of God and Chriſt towards vs. Iohn 3.16. Rom. 8.39. Epheſ. 5.2. Reuelat. 1.5.</item>
                  <item>Lucius of Cyrene. Actes 13.1.</item>
                  <item>Luke the Phyſicion. Colloſſ. 4.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Luſt is ſinne. Romanes 7.17.</item>
                  <item>Luſt is forbidden by the lawe, &amp; therefore to luſt is ſinne, contrarie to the aſſertion of papiſts, who ſay that luſt is not ſinne. Matth. 5.28. Rom. 7.7.</item>
                  <item>Luſts youthly and worldly ought to be auoyded. 2. Timoth. 2.22. Titus 2.12. 1. Peter 1.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Lyar who is. Roman. 3.4. 1. Iohn 2.4, 22.1. Iohn 4.20.</item>
                  <item>Lydda. Actes 9.32. Coloſſ. 1.12.</item>
                  <item>Lydia the name of a woman. Actes 16.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> A lye is readily receyued of men. Actes 8.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ To lie vnto the holy Ghoſt, what it is. Actes. 5.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Lying forbidden. Epheſ. 4.25. Coloſſ. 3.9. Reuelat. 21.27. Reuelat. 22.17.</item>
                  <item>Lyſanias the tetrarch of Abilene. Luke 3.1.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="M" type="part">
               <head>M.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>MAcedonia. Actes 16.9, 10, 12. 1. Theſſ. 4.10.</item>
                  <item>Macedonians or men of Macedonia, liberal in relie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing
<pb facs="tcp:181144:29"/> the poore. Rom. 15.26. 2. Cor. 8.1. 2. Cor. 11.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Magiſtrates are ordeined of God, and to what end. Rom. 13.4, 6. 1. Pet. 2.13.</item>
                  <item>Magiſtrates muſt be prayed for. 1. Tim. 2.2.</item>
                  <item>Magiſtrates muſt not be contemned or ſpoken euill of. 2. Pet. 2.10. Iude 8.</item>
                  <item>Magiſtrates muſt not be defrauded of their honour. Act. 4.8. Act. 23.5. Act. 26.25. Rom. 13.7. Tit. 1.1. 1. Pet. 2.17.</item>
                  <item>Magiſtrates duetie. Mat. 27.23. Act. 21.31, 32, Act. 23.19. Act. 25.10, 21. Rom. 13.3, 4. 1. Tim. 2.2. 1. Pet. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>Magiſtrates are to be obeyed, and howe farre. Matth. 22.21. Luk. 2.4, 5. Act. 4.19. Act. 5.29. Act. 16.30.</item>
                  <item>Magiſtrates are called gods. Iohn. 10.34, 35.</item>
                  <item>Magog, ſee Gog.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Maliciouſneſſe or malice condemned. Rom. 1.29. 1. Corin. 5.8. 1. Cor. 14.20. Ephe. 4.3 1. Coloſſ. 3.8. Tit. 3.3. 1. Pet. 2.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man earthly and heauenly. 1. Cor. 15.47.</item>
                  <item>Man carnal and ſolde vnder ſinne. Rom. 7.14.</item>
                  <item>Man ſpiritual. Iohn. 3.6. 1. Cor. 2.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Man euery one is a ſinner. Rom. 3.9, 23. Rom. 5.12. Galat. 3.2. 1. Iohn. 1.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Man naturally the childe of wrath. Ephe. 2.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man deuided into three parts. 1. Theſſ. 5.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man, put for ſonne of man. Matth. 10.35.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man naturall, put for a man not regenerated. 1. Corin. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man outward. 2. Cor. 4.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man inward, or hidden man. Rom. 7.22. 2. Cor. 2.16. Eph. 3.16. 1. Pet. 3.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Man euery one is a lyar. Rom. 3.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man which is olde. Rom. 6.6. Ephe. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 22. Coloſſ. 3.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man which is newe. Coloſſ. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Man in Gods matters altogether blynd. Iohn. 3.3, 4. Iohn 15.5.</item>
                  <item>Man muſt not contende with God. Rom. 9.20. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Mans eſtate before regeneration. Iohn. 1.5. Iohn. 4.9, 10. Act. 17.16. Ephe. 2.1, 2. &amp;c. 1. Pet. 2.9.</item>
                  <item>Mans vanitie, or the vanitie of man. 1. Tim. 6.7. 1. Pet. 1.24.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:30"/>
                  <item>✿ Man ſometimes in y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſcripture, hath that attributed vnto him, which is proper to God. Luk. 1.16. Ioh. 15.16. 1. Cor. 7.16. 1. Cor. 9.1, 22. 1. Theſſ. 3.10. 1. Timo. 4.16. Iam. 5.19. 1. Iohn. 5.16. Iude 23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man, and to ſpeake as a man, or as men. Rom. 3.5. Rom. 6.19. Galat. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man is the image and glorie of God. 1. Cor. 11.7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Man is the womans head. 1. Cor. 11.3. Ephe. 5.23.</item>
                  <item>Manna. Iohn. 6.31, 49, 58. Reue. 2.17.</item>
                  <item>Manahen, a mans name. Act. 13.1.</item>
                  <item>Maran-atha. 1. Cor. 16.22.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Marriage is rather to be diſſolued, then godlines to be forſaken. 1. Cor. 7.15.</item>
                  <item>Marriage hindereth not the dayly prayers of the faythfull. 1. Cor. 7.5.</item>
                  <item>Marriage is honorable among all men. Heb. 13.4.</item>
                  <item>Marriage commanded to ſuch as haue not the gift of con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinencie. 1. Cor. 7.2, 9.</item>
                  <item>Marriage permitted to the miniſters of Gods word. Act. 21.9. 1. Cor. 7.2. 1. Cor. 9.5. 1. Tim. 3.2. Tit. 1.6. Heb. 13.4.</item>
                  <item>Marriage is not in any wiſe to be made with the vnbelee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uers. 2. Cor. 6.14. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Marriage forbidden by deceiuers. 1. Tim. 4.3.</item>
                  <item>Marriage and the bande thereof moſt ſtraite. Ephe. 5.31.</item>
                  <item>Marriage is an inſeparable coniunction of the huſbande &amp; the wife. Mat. 19.5. 1. Cor. 7.4, 10.</item>
                  <item>Marriage ordeined of God. Mat. 19.5.</item>
                  <item>Marriage graunted to al. 1. Cor. 7.2.</item>
                  <item>Marriage honored with Chriſts preſence, and firſt miracle. Ioh. 2.2.</item>
                  <item>Marriage compared to the ioyning of Chriſt w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> his Church Ephe. 5.29.</item>
                  <item>Marriage cannot be vndone by man. Mat. 19.6.</item>
                  <item>Marriage broken through fornication. Matth. 5.32. Matth. 19.9.</item>
                  <item>Marriage is the band betweene the huſband and the wife, alſo betweene the wife and the huſband, and howe they
<pb facs="tcp:181144:30"/> ought to behaue themſelues the one to the other. 1. Cor. 7.3, 12, 13, 14.34. Ephe. 5.28, 33. Coloſſ. 3.18, 19. 1. Tim. 2.12. Tit. 2.5. 1. Pet. 3.17.</item>
                  <item>Marriages ſeconde, or ſeconde marriages lawfull. Rom. 7.2. 1. Cor. 7.8.9, 39. 1. Tim. 5.14.</item>
                  <item>Marie the virgin the mother of Chriſt. Mat. 1.18. Luk. 1.7.</item>
                  <item>Marie the virgins ſong. Luk. 1.46.</item>
                  <item>Marie the virgin, wife of Ioſeph. Mat. 1.16, 20.</item>
                  <item>Marie ſaluted of the Angel. Luk. 1.28.</item>
                  <item>Maries modeſtie, who alſo ſendeth vs to Chriſt. Ioh. 2.5.</item>
                  <item>Marie the ſiſter of Martha. Luk. 10.39. Ioh. 11.1, 38.</item>
                  <item>Marie Magdalen healed by Chriſt. Luk. 8.2.</item>
                  <item>Marie Magdalen goeth to Chriſts ſepulchre. Ioh. 20.1.</item>
                  <item>Marie Lazarus his ſiſter beloued of Chriſte. Iohn. 11.1, 2, 5.</item>
                  <item>Marie anoynted Chriſte. Matthewe. 26.7. Iohn. 11.2. Iohn. 12 3.</item>
                  <item>Marie heareth Chriſts teaching. Luk. 10.39.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Married folkes and their equalitie. 1. Pet. 3.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Married folkes duetie. 1. Corin. 11.11, 12. 1. Cor. 7.3, 4, 5. Ephe. 5.22. Coloſſ. 3.18. &amp;c. Tit. 2.5. &amp;c. 1. Pet. 3.1, 2, 3. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Mars ſtreete. Act. 17.18.</item>
                  <item>Martha receiued Chriſt into her houſe. Luk. 10.38.</item>
                  <item>Martha ſerued at ſupper. Iohn. 12.2.</item>
                  <item>Martha and her weake faith and diſtruſt. Iohn. 11.24, 39.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Martyrs comfort. Mat. 10.28, 29 39. Matt. 16.25. Luk. 21.16, 18. Rom. 8.36, 37. 2. Tim. 2.12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Maſters duetie towards ſeruantes. Epheſians. 6.9. Coloſſ. 4.1.</item>
                  <item>Matthewe named alſo Leui, and called by Chriſt. Matth. 9.9. Mark. 2.14. Luk. 5.27.</item>
                  <item>Matthias and his calling to the Apoſtleſhip. Act. 1.23. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Meaſure, ſee Fulfill.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Meate that endureth and is ſpiritual. Ioh. 6.27, 51. 1. Cor. 10.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Meates bodily, make vs not acceptable to God. 1. Cor. 8.8. Heb. 13.9.</item>
                  <item>Meates bodily differ not as touching y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> matter of co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſcie<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:31"/> Mark. 7.18. Act. 10.13. Rom. 14.14. 1. Cor. 10.25. Coloſſ. 2.16 1. Tim. 4.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Meekeneſſe, ſee Gentlenes.</item>
                  <item>Melchiſedec a figure of Chriſt. Heb. 5.6. Heb. 7.1.</item>
                  <item>Melita. Act. 28.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Members, put for all the parts and powers of man. Rom. 6.19.</item>
                  <item>✿ Members, put for that part of a man which is not rege<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerated. Rom. 7.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Members one of another are the faithfull. Rom. 12.5. 1. Cor. 12.25, 26, 27. Ephe. 4.25.</item>
                  <item>Members of Chriſt are our bodies. 1. Cor. 6.15. Ephe. 5.30.</item>
                  <item>Members ought to ſerue in holines. Rom. 6.19.</item>
                  <item>Members muſt be mortified. Coloſſ. 3.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Mercie of God, or Gods mercie. Epheſi. 2.4. Hebr. 4.16. 1. Pet. 1.3.</item>
                  <item>Mercie of God ſhewed to whom it pleaſed God. Rom. 9.15.</item>
                  <item>Mercie of God ſhewed to the Gentiles. Rom. 11.30. Rom. 15.9.</item>
                  <item>Mercie of God ſhewed to them that feare him. Luk. 1.50.</item>
                  <item>Mercie of God ſhewed to them that repent. Luk. 15.20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Mercie or compaſſion one of vs towards another is com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maunded. Mat. 5.7. Mat. 9.13. Mat. 18.25. Luk. 6.36. Luk. 10. 33. Luk. 22.32. Galat. 6.1. Ephe. 4.32. Hebr. 6.10. Iam. 1.27. Iam. 2.13.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Merits of man ouerthrowen by theſe Scriptures. Matt. 10. 8. mat. 13.11. mat. 18.27. mat. 24.22. mat. 25.34. Luk. 1.30, 48, Luk. 12.32. Luk. 17.7, 9, 10. Luk. 18.14. Iohn 1.6. Iohn. 3.3.15. 16. Iohn. 6 40, 65. Iohn. 10.28. Iohn. 15.16. Act. 13.48. Act. 15 9. Act. 26.8. Rom. 3.27. Rom. 9.32. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 11.2, 5, 32. 1. Cor. 1.27. 1. Cor. 3.5. 1. Cor. 15.57. Galat. 1.15. Galat. 3.18. Ephe. 1.4, 5. Ephe. 2.4, 8, 13. Phil. 1.29. Coloſſ. 1.12. Coloſſ. 2.13. 2. Theſſ. 1.11. 2. Theſſ. 2.16. 2. Tim. 1.9. 2. Tim. 4.8. Tit. 3.5, 7. Heb. 2.10. Iam. 2.5. 1. Pet. 1.2, 3, 9, 18. 1. Pet. 5.10. 2. Pet. 1.3. 1. Iohn. 2.12. 1. Iohn. 3.1. Iude 21. Reu. 3.18. Reue. 4.10, 11. Reu. 21.6. Reu. 22.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Milke diuerſely taken. 1. Corin. 3.2. Hebrew. 5.12. 1. Peter. 2.2.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:31"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Miniſterie why ordeined. Ephe. 4.12.</item>
                  <item>Miniſterie reſembled to a warfare. 2. Cor. 10.4. 2. Tim. 2.4.</item>
                  <item>Miniſterie contemned and the puniſhment thereof. Luk. 10 16. Iohn. 12.48. Act. 7.51, 57. 1. Theſſ. 4.8. 1. Theſſ. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>Miniſterie of the woorde and the commendation thereof. Matt. 11.11. mat. 16.19. Luk. 1.16. Luk. 10.16. Ioh. 15.3. Ioh. 20.23. Act. 8.30, 31. Act. 9.6. Act. 10.5.36. Act. 11.14, 21. Act. 14.22, 23. Act. 26.18. Rom. 1.16. Rom. 10.8, 14, 15. Rom. 12.7. Rom. 15.16. 1. Cor. 2.13. 1. Cor. 3.5, 6. 1. Cor. 4.1, 15. 1. Cor. 9.1, 2. 2. Cor. 5.18. 1. Timo. 3.15. 1. Timo. 4.14, 15. Titus. 1.5. Philem. 10. Heb. 4.12. Iam. 1.21.</item>
                  <item>Miniſters ſtande in need of other mens prayers. Ephe. 6.19. Coloſſ. 4.3. 2. Theſſ. 3.2.</item>
                  <item>Miniſters muſt be examples to the congregation. Matth. 5.13, 14. Luk. 14.35. Act. 20.33. Phil. 3.17. Tit. 2.7. 1. Tim. 4.12. 1. Pet. 5.3.</item>
                  <item>Miniſters, ſee Preachers.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Miniſtration of the word, or preaching of the Goſpel. Act. 20.24. 2. Cor. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>✿ Miracle, firſt that Chriſt wrought, and the ſeconde alſo. Iohn. 2.11, 54.</item>
                  <item>✿ Miracles called by diuers names. Heb. 2.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Miracles and the word ioyned together. Mar. 10.7. Mat. 6 12, 13. Luk. 5.17. Iohn. 3.2. Act. 14.3. Heb. 2.3, 4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Miracles wrought by wicked men. Matth. 7.21. Matth. 24.24. Mark. 13.22. 2. Theſſ. 2.9.</item>
                  <item>Miracles and their ende and vſe. Matth. 11.4, 5, 21. matt. 15.31. matt. 20.34. Luk. 7.16. Iohn. 2.11, 23. Iohn. 11.15, 42, 45. Iohn. 20.30, 31. Act 3.10. Acts. 4.21, 30. Acts. 8.6. Act 9.35, 42.</item>
                  <item>Miracles true are of God, to confirme his trueth. Marke. 16.20. Iohn. 5.36. Iohn. 10.25. Iohn. 20.30, 31. Acts. 2.22. Act. 4.30. Act. 14.3. 2. Cor. 12.12. Heb. 2.4.</item>
                  <item>Miracles true wrought in the name of Ieſus Chriſt onely. Mark. 16.17. Act. 3.16. Act. 4.10, 30. Act. 9.34.</item>
                  <item>Miracles falſe are of the deuill to deceiue. Matth. 24.24. 2. Theſſ. 2.9, 10. Reue. 13.14. Reue. 16.14.</item>
                  <item>Mnaſon of Cyprus. Pauls hoſte. Act. 21.16.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:32"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Mortifying of our ſelues commaunded. Rom. 8.13. Coloſſ. 3.5. Moſes, and places ſpeaking of him. Iohn. 5.45, 46. Act. 7.20, 21, 21. &amp;c. Heb. 11.23, 24 &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Moſes hid his face. 2. Cor. 3.13.</item>
                  <item>✿ Moſes, put for the Lawe written by Moſes. 2. Cor. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Mote in the eye. Mat. 7.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Mouth, put for word and witneſſe. Mat. 18.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ To open the mouth. Mat. 5.2. Act. 8.35. Act. 10.38.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Multitudes muſt not alwayes be followed. Mat. 7.13. Matt. 16.15. mat. 24.5. Luk. 6.26. Luk. 13.22, 23, 24. Ioh. 6.60, 65, 67. Act. 1.15. Act. 9.27. Act. 28.22.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Murmur and grudging ought to be auoyded. 1. Cor. 10.10. Phil. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>Murmurers. Matt. 10.11. Luk. 5.30. Luk. 15. 2. Luk. 19.7. Ioh. 6.41, 61, Rom. 1.20. Iude 16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Murther how much abhorred. Act. 28.4.</item>
                  <item>Murther and murtherers condemned. Mat. 5.21. mat. 15.19. matth. 19.18. Rom. 1.29. Rom. 13.9. Galat. 5.21. 1. Tim. 1.9. 1. Pet. 4.15. Reue. 21.8. Reue. 22.25.</item>
                  <item>Murtherer is he that hateth. 1. Iohn. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Mynde of man vaine, and his vnderſtanding darkened. Ephe. 4.17, 18.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="N" type="part">
               <head>N.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>NAin. Luk. 7.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ Name, put for myght or power, Iohn. 1.12. Iohn. 2.23. Act. 3.6.</item>
                  <item>Name put for dignitie and renowme. Phil. 2.9.</item>
                  <item>Names put for men. Reue. 3.4. Act. 1.15.</item>
                  <item>Narciſſus. Rom. 16.11.</item>
                  <item>Nathanael and his calling. Iohn. 1.45, 46. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Nature vſed in good part. 1. Cor. 11.14.</item>
                  <item>Nature taken in ill part. Ephe. 2.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Natures two, or two natures in Chriſt. Act. 2<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>.28. Rom. 1.3, 4. Phil. 2.6, 7. Iohn. 1.14. Ioh. 6.62. Iohn. 3.13. Mat. 1.23.</item>
                  <item>Nazareth. Matth. 2.23.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:32"/>
                  <item>✿ Neighbour is euery man. Luk. 10.36.</item>
                  <item>Neighbours muſt be loued as our ſelues. Matt. 22.39.</item>
                  <item>✿ Newneſſe of life is of the ſpirite. Iohn. 3.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> New man, reade Man.</item>
                  <item>Nicodemus and his ſtorie. Ioh. 3.1, 2. &amp;c. Ioh. 7.50. Ioh. 19.35.</item>
                  <item>Nicolaitans. Reue. 2.6, 15.</item>
                  <item>Niger. Act. 13.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Night diuided into certaine watches. Matt. 14.35. matt. 24.43. Luk. 12.38.</item>
                  <item>✿ Night otherwiſe diuided. Mark. 13.35. Mark. 14.30.</item>
                  <item>✿ Night, put for the ignorance of God. Rom. 13.12.</item>
                  <item>Noe. Hebrew. 11.7.</item>
                  <item>Noe and his dayes. Matth. 24.37. 1. Pet. 3.20.</item>
                  <item>Noe, called a preacher of righteouſneſſe. 2. Pet. 2.5.</item>
                  <item>✿ None, put for verie fewe. 1. Cor. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Number certaine for an vncertaine. Matth. 12.45. matt. 18.22. Mark. 5.9. Rom. 11.4. 2. Cor. 12 8. Reue. 7.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Number ſingular for the plurall. 1. Iohn. 5.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Number plurall for the ſingular. Matth. 26.8.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="O" type="part">
               <head>O.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g>OBedience to God, rather then to man. Act. 4.19. Acts. 5.29.</item>
                  <item>Obedience to the Goſpel and trueth. Rom. 15.18. Rom. 16.19.26. 2. Cor. 9.13.</item>
                  <item>Obedience to the miniſters of the Church. Heb. 13.17.</item>
                  <item>Obedience to parents. Ephe. 6. 1. Coloſſ. 3.20.</item>
                  <item>Obedience to magiſtrates and rulers. Mat. 22.21. Rom. 13.1, 2, 3. &amp;c. Tit. 3.1.</item>
                  <item>Obedience to God co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mended &amp; commaunded. Mat. 19.17</item>
                  <item>Obedience, but not vnto ſinne. Rom. 6.16.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Oblation, reade Sacrifice.</item>
                  <item>✿ Obſeruation, put for outwarde pompe. Luk. 17.20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Obſtinacie, and examples thereof. Matt. 14.9. Iohn. 20.25.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Occaſion offered muſt be taken and vſed. Luk. 17.22. Luk. 19.42, 44. Iohn. 7.34. Iohn. 9.4. Iohn. 12.35, 36. Actes 16.33.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:33"/> Act. 20.2. Rom. 2.4. Rom. 12.11. 2. Cor. 6.2. Galat. 6.<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>0. Ephe. 5.16. Heb. 4.16. Heb. 12.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Offence, put for let or hinderance to come to God and to Chriſt, or for occaſion giuen to drawe backe, or to fall by any meanes into ſinne and deſtruction. Mat. 18.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Offence muſt not be giuen, or offending of others muſt be auoided. Mat. 17.27. mat. 18.6. &amp;c. Rom. 14.13. 1. Cor. 8.9, 13. 2. Cor. 6.3.</item>
                  <item>Offence, taken vniuſtly. Mat. 24.10. mat. 26.31. mark. 6.3. Ioh. 6, 61. 1. Cor. 1.23. Galat. 5.11.</item>
                  <item>Offence at Chriſt whoſoeuer taketh not, is happie. Matth. 11.6.</item>
                  <item>✿ Offend, put for ſtumblyng or falling. Mat. 5.29, 30. mat. 11.6. mat. 24.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Oyle, put for the holy Ghoſt. Hebr. 1.9. and ſo in many pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of Iohns firſt generall Epiſtle.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Olde age is to be reuerenced. 1. Tim. 5.1. 1. Pet. 5.5.</item>
                  <item>✿ Oliue tree, wilde. Rom. 11.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ One, put for onely. 1. Tim. 2.5.</item>
                  <item>Oneſimus. Philemon. 10.</item>
                  <item>Oneſiphorus. 2. Tim. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ Oth of God. Heb. 6.17. Heb. 7.21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Oth among men and the end thereof. Heb. 6.16.</item>
                  <item>Oth is prohibited in priuate cauſes and talke. Matth. 5.34. Iam. 5.12.</item>
                  <item>Oth lawfull. Rom. 1.9. Rom. 9.1. 2. Corin. 1.23. Hebrew. 6.16, 17.</item>
                  <item>Oth abuſed. Matth. 23.16, 17. &amp;c. matth. 26.63, 72. Mark. 6.26. Act. 23.12.</item>
                  <item>Oth raſh. Matth. 14.7, 9.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="P" type="part">
               <head>P.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ PAlſey healed of Chriſt. Mat. 9.2, 6.</item>
                  <item>✿ Parable or ſimilitude of the candle lyght. Matt 5.15. Luk. 11.33.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the houſe built vpon the ſand. Mat. 7.26.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the children in the ſtreetes. Mat. 11.16.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:33"/>
                  <item>Parable of the piece of newe cloth. Matth. 9.16.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the ſower. Matth. 13.3, 18.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the Darnel or Cockle. Matth. 13.24. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the graine of Muſtard ſeed. Matth. 13.31.</item>
                  <item>Parable of Leuaine. Matth. 13.33.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the treaſure hid, of the marchant &amp; the pearle, and of the nette. Matth. 13.44. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the loſt ſheepe. Matth. 18.12.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the ſeruant that pitieth not his companion. Matthew 18.28.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the workemen ſent to labour in the vineyarde. Matthew 20.2.</item>
                  <item>Parable of two ſonnes. Matth. 21.28.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the vineyard hyred forth. Matth. 21.33.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the king that maketh the mariage. Matthewe 22.2.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the faithfull and naughtie ſeruant. Matthewe 24.45, 48.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the ten virgins. Matth. 25.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the Talents. Matthewe 25.14, 15. &amp;c. Luke 19.12, 13. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the ſeede that groweth and increaſeth. Marke 4.27.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the Samaritan. Luke 10.30. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the importunate friend. Luke 11.5.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the ſtrong man armed. Luke 11.21.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the barren figge tree. Luke 13.6.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the dram or piece of ſiluer loſt. Luke 15.8.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the prodigall ſonne. Luke 15.12. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the vniuſt ſteward. Luke 16.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Parable of the importunate widdowe. Luke 18.3. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Pardon we muſt him that offendeth vs. Matth. 6.14. Mat. 18.22, 35. Marke 11.25. Luke 17.3. Epheſ. 4.32. Coloſſ. 3.13.</item>
                  <item>✿ Paradiſe. Luke 23.43. 2. Corinth. 12.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Parents muſt be honoured, and howe farre. Matthew 15.4. Iohn 2.4. Actes 7.3. Epheſ. 6.1.</item>
                  <item>Parents haue authoritie in the mariage of their children. 1. Corinth. 7.36, 37.</item>
                  <item>Parents duetie towarde their children. Matthewe 9.18. &amp;c.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:34"/>
                  <item>Luke 9.38. Iohn 4.47. &amp;c. Epheſ. 6.4. Coloſſ. 3.20.</item>
                  <item>Parents, reade Father.</item>
                  <item>Paphus. Actes 13.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Patience is neceſſarie for all the godly and faithful ones. Matt. 5.38, 39. Luke 2.25. Luke 21.19. Rom. 5.3. Romanes 8.25. Romanes 12.12. Romanes 15.4. 2. Corinth. 6.4. Coloſſ. 1.11. 1. Theſſ. 5.14. 1. Timoth. 6.11. Titus 2.2. Hebrewes 6.12. Heb. 10.36. Hebr. 12.12. Iames 1.3. Iames 5.7, 8. 2. Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter 1.6. Reuelat. 1.9. Reuelat. 2.2, 3.</item>
                  <item>Patmos. Reuelat. 1.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Paul his vocation, actes, preachings, miracles, iourneis, trauailes, perſecutions, &amp; other afflictions, from the 8. Chapter of the Actes, euen to the laſt, &amp; throughout all his Epiſtles.</item>
                  <item>Paul inforced to co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mend him ſelfe. 1. Corinth. 3.10. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 9.1. 1. Corinth. 14.18. 1. Corin. 15.10. 2. Corint. 3.1. 2. Corinth. 5.12, 13. 2. Corinth. 10.12. Philip. 3.4, 5.</item>
                  <item>Paul wrought with his owne handes &amp; got his liuing. Acts 18.3. Actes 20.30. 1. Corinth. 4.12. 1. Corinth. 9.6. 1. Theſſ. 2.9. 2. Theſſ. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>Paules great charitie or loue. Rom. 9.1. &amp;c. 2. Corint. 12.15. Philip. 1.24. 1. Theſſ. 2.8. 2. Timoth. 2.10.</item>
                  <item>Paules care for the Churches. 2. Corinth. 2.12. 2. Corinth. 11.28. Coloſſ. 2.1. 1. Timoth. 1.3.</item>
                  <item>Paul the Ambaſſadour of Chriſt. 2. Corinth. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>Paul the Apoſtle of the Gentiles. Roman. 11.13. Galat. 2.8. 1. Timoth. 2.7.</item>
                  <item>Paul hath layd the foundation. 1. Corinth. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>Paules ſuffrings for the Goſpell. 1. Corinth. 4.9. 2. Corinth. 4.9. 2. Corinthians 11.24. 2. Corinth. 12.7. 2. Timoth. 2.10. 2. Timoth. 3.11.</item>
                  <item>Paules example of life and doctrine ought to be followed. 1. Corinth. 4.16. 1. Corinth. 11.1. Philip. 3.17. 1. Theſſ. 1.6. 2. Theſſ. 3.9.</item>
                  <item>Paules reuelations. 2. Corinth. 12.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Peace makers are bleſſed. Matth. 5.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Peace, put for reconciliation betweene God and men. Actes 10.36.</item>
                  <item>Peace, for quietnes of conſciences. Luke 2.14.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:34"/>
                  <item>Peace, put for ſafe and ſound. 1. Corinth. 16.11.</item>
                  <item>Peace, put for all maner of felicitie or happines. Luke 19.42. Romanes 8.6.</item>
                  <item>Peace, put for all true felicitie or bleſſed ſucceſſe in all things. Luke 1.7, 9. Luke. 24.36. Iohn 14.27.</item>
                  <item>Peace, put for proſperitie in worldly things. Rom. 1.7. and ſo in the reſt of Paules ſalutations.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Peace to be had with all men, and howe farre. Rom. 12.18. 1. Corinth. 7.15. Heb. 12.14. 1. Peter. 3.11.</item>
                  <item>Peace of Chriſt and of the world differ much. Ioh. 14.27.</item>
                  <item>Peace of God and of Chriſt. Luke 2.14. Luke 24.36. Iohn 14.27. Iohn 16.33. Actes 10.36. Rom. 5.1. Epheſ. 2.14. Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lip. 4.7. Coloſſ. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Peace with our neighbour. Matt. 5.9. Marke 9.50. Rom. 12.18. Rom. 14.19. 1. Corinth. 14.33. 2. Cor. 13.11. Epheſ. 4.3. 1. Theſſ. 5.13. 2. Timoth. 2.22. Heb. 12.14. 1. Peter 3.11.</item>
                  <item>Peace of the world. Matthewe 10.34. Iohn 14.27. 1. Theſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonians 5.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Pearles muſt not be caſt before Swine. Matth. 7.6.</item>
                  <item>Pearle of great price. Matth. 13.45, 46.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Perſecution followeth y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> true Chriſtians. 2. Tim. 3.11, 12.</item>
                  <item>Perſecution they that ſuffer are bleſſed. Matthew 5.10, 11. 1. Peter. 4.14.</item>
                  <item>Perſecution, &amp; in the time thereof we may flie, read Flie.</item>
                  <item>Perſecution co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>meth by the wil of God. 1. Peter 2.19. 1. Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter 3.17. 1. Peter 4.19.</item>
                  <item>Perſecution and examples thereof. Matt. 26.50. Actes 4.3. Acts 6.12. Acts 7.58. Actes 8.1. Acts 12.1. &amp;c. Acts 13.50. Acts 14.5. Acts 16.22. Acts 17.6. Acts 18.17. Actes 19.29. Acts 21.30. Rom. 8.35. 2. Corin. 11.24. &amp;c. Heb. 11.36, 37.</item>
                  <item>Perſecuters of ignorance receyued to repentance. Acts 3.17. 1. Timoth. 1.13.</item>
                  <item>Perſecuters obſtinate puniſhed. Luke 23.28. Acts 12.23.</item>
                  <item>Perſecuters ſometimes are kinſfolkes. Matthewe 10.21, 35. Luke 21.16.</item>
                  <item>Perſeuerance or continuance in good things is neceſſary for all the godly. Matth. 10.22. Matth. 19.30. Matth. 24.13. Luke 1.7 5. Luke 9.62. Iohn 8.31. Actes 2.42. Actes 11.23. Actes 13.43. Romanes 8.38. Rom. 11.22. Galatians 6.9.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:35"/> Philip. 1.5, 6, 10, 25, 27. Philip. 4.1. Coloſſ. 1.23. Coloſſ. 2.6. 1. Theſſ. 4.1, 10.2. Timoth. 4.6, 16. Heb. 3.6, 12, 14. Iames 1.4, 12.1. Iohn 2.24. Reuelat. 2.10, 26.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Perſeuerance or continuance in praier. Matt. 15.23, 27. matt. 20.31: matth. 26.44. Luke 11.5, 6. Luke 18.1. 1. Theſſ. 5.17. Coloſſ. 4.2. See Prayer muſt be continuall.</item>
                  <item>Perſeuerance is the gift of God who onelye can confirme his in goodnes Roma. 16.25. 2. Cor. 1.21. Phil. 1.6. 1. Theſ. 3.13. 1. Theſſ. 5.23. 2. Theſ. 2.16. 2. Theſ. 3.5. 1. Peter. 5.10.</item>
                  <item>Perſeuerance, ſee Continuance.</item>
                  <item>Peter and his calling. Matth. 4.18. &amp;c. Iohn 1.41. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Peter called Cephas of Chriſt. Iohn 1.42.</item>
                  <item>Peter called Satan. Matth. 16.23.</item>
                  <item>Peter denieth Chriſt. Matth. 26.70.</item>
                  <item>Peter preacheth Chriſt. Acts 2.14, 15. &amp;c. Actes 3.12, 13. &amp;c. Actes 10.34, 35.</item>
                  <item>Peter viſion. Actes 10.10, 11. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Peter is taken and put in priſon. Acts 12.3, 4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Phariſes. Matth. 3.7.</item>
                  <item>Phariſes leuaine. Matth. 6.6. Luke 12.1.</item>
                  <item>Phariſes reproued of Chriſt for their hypocriſie and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lice. Matth. 9.12. almoſt throughout the whole Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter. Matth. 15.3, 7. matth. 19.8. matth. 22.18.</item>
                  <item>Phariſes wickednes particularly and plainely deſcribed. Matth. 23. throughout the whole Chapter.</item>
                  <item>Phebe. Romanes 16.1.</item>
                  <item>Phenice. Actes 11.19.</item>
                  <item>Philemon. Philem. 1.</item>
                  <item>Philetus. 2. Timothie 2.17.</item>
                  <item>Philip the tetrarch of Iturea &amp; Thraconitis. Luk. 3.1.</item>
                  <item>Philip the Apoſtle called. Iohn 1.43.</item>
                  <item>Philip the Apoſtle reprooued of Chriſt. Iohn 14.9.</item>
                  <item>Philip the Deacon. Actes 6.5.</item>
                  <item>Philip the Deacon afterwardes an Euangeliſt. Actes 21.8.</item>
                  <item>Philips daughter did prophecie. Actes 21.9.</item>
                  <item>Phillipi the chiefe Citie in the partes of Macedonia. Actes 16.12.</item>
                  <item>Phygellus. 2. Timoth. 1.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Phylacteries. Matth. 23.5.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:35"/>
                  <item>Pilate and his behauiour towardes Chriſt. Matth. 27.2. &amp;c. Iohn 18.29, 38. Iohn 19.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Poets alledged. Acts. 17.28. 1. Corinth. 15.33. Titus 1.12.</item>
                  <item>Pollux. Actes 28.11.</item>
                  <item>Porch of Solomon, reade Solomons porch.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Poore in ſpirite. Matth. 5.3. Luke 6.20.</item>
                  <item>Poore receyue the Goſpell. Matth. 11.5. Luke 7.22.</item>
                  <item>Poore ought to be cared for and muſt be ſuccoured. Matt. 19.21. Marke 12.43. Luke 3.11. Luke 14.12. &amp;c. Luke 16.19. Luke 19.8. Iohn 13.29. Actes 4 34. Acts 9.39. Actes 11.29. 2. Corinth. 8.1. Galat. 2.10.</item>
                  <item>Poore muſt not be deſpiſed. Iames 2.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Pouertie ſhould be taken in good worth. Philip. 4.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Power of God. Matt. 22.29.</item>
                  <item>Power of God worketh in his to ſaluation. Romanes 1.16. 1. Peter 1.5.</item>
                  <item>Power of Chriſt. 2. Corinth. 12.9.</item>
                  <item>Power of the holy Ghoſt. Actes. 1.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Praier muſt not be made in a ſtraunge tongue. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 14.13, 14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Praier with the ſpirite. 1. Corinth. 14.15.</item>
                  <item>Praier in the ſpirite. Epheſ. 6.18. Iude 20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Praier muſt be continual and perſeuering. Luke 11.8. Luke 18.1. Luke 21.36. Actes 1, 14. Acts. 2.42. Actes 10.2. Rom. 12.12. Epheſ. 6.18. Coloſſ. 4.2. 1. Theſſ. 5.17. 1. Tim. 5.5. 2. Timoth. 1.3. 1. Peter 4.7.</item>
                  <item>Praier muſt be made in a ſure faith. Mat. 21.22. Mark. 11.24. Luke 11.5, 6. &amp;c. 1. Timoth. 2.8. Iames 1.6. Iames 5.15.</item>
                  <item>Praier is not tyed to any circumſtances of times and pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces. Mat. 14.23. Iohn. 4.21. Acts 10.2. Actes 12.5. 1. Tim. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>Praier very neceſſarie. Matth. 26.41. Philip. 4.6. Coloſſ. 4.2. 1. Theſſ. 1.2.</item>
                  <item>Praier ioyned with faſting. Matt. 17.21. Luke 2.37. Acts 10.30. Actes 14.23. 1. Corinth. 7.5.</item>
                  <item>Praier very meete in time of affliction. Matth. 17.15. Acts 4.20. Acts 12.5. Actes 16.25. Roman. 15.30, 31. Iames 5.13.</item>
                  <item>Praier is to be made for magiſtrates. 1. Timoth. 2.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Praier for the miniſters of the word. Rom. 15.30. Coloſſ. 4.3. Epheſ. 6.19.2. Theſſ. 3.1. Heb. 13.18.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:36"/>
                  <item>Praier for obteyning ofſpring. Luke 1.13.</item>
                  <item>Praier for ſicke perſons. Iames 5.14, 15.</item>
                  <item>Praier one for another. Iames 5.16.</item>
                  <item>Praier for the Saints. Epheſ. 6.18.</item>
                  <item>Praier for the enemies and perſecuters. Matth. 5.44. Luke 23.34. Actes 7.6.</item>
                  <item>Praiers for all men. 1. Timoth. 2.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Praier againſt temptations. Matth. 26.41. Luke 22.4.</item>
                  <item>Praier and the forme thereof. Matth. 6.9. Luke 11.2.</item>
                  <item>Praier howe it ought to be made. Matth. 6.5. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Praiers publike and in the aſſemblie of many. Matt. 18.19. Acts 1.14, 24. Acts 4.24, 31. Actes 12.5. Actes 16.13. Actes 20.36. Actes 21.5.</item>
                  <item>Praier priuate, and example thereof in Chriſt. Matth 6.6. Matth. 14.23. Matth 26.39. Luke 5.16. Luk. 6.12. Luk. 22.32.</item>
                  <item>Praier hypocriticall reproued. Mat. 6.5. matth. 23.14.</item>
                  <item>Preachers or miniſters of Chriſt muſt preache his Goſpell and feede his flocke with the worde of God. Iohn 21.15. Acts 20.28. 1. Corinth. 3.5. 1. Corinth. 4.1. 2. Corinth. 3.6. Epheſ. 3.7. Coloſ. 1.7. 1. Timoth. 4.6. 1. Peter 5.2.</item>
                  <item>Prechers are ſent of God. Mark. 16.15. Io. 20.21. Ro. 10.15.</item>
                  <item>Preachers may preache nothing, but that which Chriſt hath commaunded, that is, the onelye worde of God. Matth. 28.20. Iohn 7.17. 1. Corinth. 2.13. 2. Timoth. 4.2. 1. Peter 4.11. 2. Iohn. 9.10.</item>
                  <item>Preachers muſt be heard and obeyed. Luke 10.16. 2. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 2.9. Phil. 2.12. 2. Theſ. 3.4, 14. Heb. 13.8, 17.</item>
                  <item>Preachers muſt be receyued, nouriſhed and eſteemed.</item>
                  <item>Matth. 10.40. Iohn 13.20. Galat. 6.6. 1. Theſſ. 5.12, 13. 1. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moth. 5.17. 3. Iohn. 8.</item>
                  <item>Preachers may liue of the Goſpell. 1. Corinth. 9.7, 8, 9. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Preachers are helpers of the faithfull, and not lordes of their faith. 2. Corinth. 1.24. 1. Peter. 5.3.</item>
                  <item>Preachers are ſeruants of the faythfull. Matth. 20.27. Luke 22.27. 2. Corinth. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Preachers power is to edifie, and not to deſtroy. 2. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 13.10.</item>
                  <item>Preachers muſt be appointed particularly throughout all Churches. Actes 14.23. Titus 1.5.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:36"/>
                  <item>Preachers and what thinges and conditions are required in them. 1. Timoth. 3.2, 3. &amp;c. Titus 1.6, 9. 1. Peter 5.3.</item>
                  <item>Preachers ought to be good, and examples to others. Phil. 3.17. 2. Theſſ. 3.9. Titus 2.7. 1. Peter 5.3.</item>
                  <item>Preachers falſe are prophecied to come, and to deceyue many. Matth. 24.11. Actes 20.28, 29.1. Timoth. 4.1. 2. Tim. 4.3. 2. Peter 2.1.</item>
                  <item>Preachers falſe ſhal come with wonderfull ſignes and mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racles. Matthewe 24.24. 2. Theſſalonians 2.9. Reuela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion 13.13.</item>
                  <item>Preachers falſe make marchandiſe of Gods worde. 2. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 2.17.</item>
                  <item>Preachers falſe teache the commaundements &amp; doctrine of men, &amp; deuils. Coloſſ. 2.8. 1. Timoth. 4.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Preachers falſe ſerue their bellie, which is their God. Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manes 16.18. Philip. 3.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Predeſtination, reade Election.</item>
                  <item>✿ Pricke in the fleſh, put for concupiſcence and luſt, or for all kinde of temptation. 2. Corinth. 12.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Pride howe much hated of God. Actes 12.23.</item>
                  <item>Pride and arrogancie condemned. Matt. 23.12. Luke 14.11. Marke 7.22. Rom. 11.25. Roman. 12.16. 1. Corinth. 4.6, 18. 2. Corinth. 10.14. 2. Corinth. 12.20. Epheſ. 4.2. Philipp. 2.3. 1. Timoth. 3.6. 1. Tim. 6.4. 2. Timoth. 3.2. Iames 4.16. 2. Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter 2.18. 1. Iohn 2.16. Iude 16.</item>
                  <item>Pride and examples thereof. Iohn 9.34. Iohn 19.20. Actes 12.21.</item>
                  <item>Pride is a daungerous thing. 2. Corinth. 12.7.</item>
                  <item>Pride is ſometimes ioyned with ignorance. 1. Corin. 8.2.</item>
                  <item>Pride is condemned &amp; therefore muſt be fled from. Matt. 18.10. matth. 23.12. Luke 1.51. Luke 14.11. Luk. 18.9. Acts 12.20, 21, 22, 23. Rom. 1.3. Rom. 11.18, 20. Romanes 22.16. 1. Corinth. 4.7. 2. Timoth. 3.2.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Prieſtes conſpire and procure Chriſtes death. Matth. 21.45, 46. matth. 26.3, 4. matth. 27.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Prieſts perſecute his members and his doctrine. Acts 4.1.3. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Prieſts are all the faithfull, and are ſo made by Chriſt. 1. Peter. 2.5, 9. Reuel. 1.6. Reuel. 5.10.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:37"/>
                  <item>✿ Prieſthood Leuiticall according to the law. Hebrewes 7.5, 11.</item>
                  <item>Prieſthood of Chriſt according to the order of Melchiſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dec. Heb. 7.4. almoſt through out the whole Chapter.</item>
                  <item>Priſcilla. Acts. 18.2. Rom. 16.3. 1. Corinth. 16.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Priſoners muſt be viſited and remembred. Matthewe 25.36, 43. Heb. 13.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Proces in lawe muſt be auoyded. Matthew 5.4. 1. Corin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thians 6.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Promiſe, put for the inheritance promiſed. Heb. 10.36.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Promiſes of God ſtande all vpon Chriſt. 2. Corinthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans 1.20.</item>
                  <item>✿ Promiſe made to the Gentiles. Actes 2.39. Romanes 4.16. Galat. 3.8, 22.</item>
                  <item>Promiſe made to the Gentiles, the ſame that was made to the fathers. 2. Corinth. 7.1. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Prophecie is the gift of God, and no worldly thing. Rom. 12.6. 1. Corinth. 12.10. 2. Peter 1.21.</item>
                  <item>✿ Prophets, put for ſhewers of things to come. Act. 11.27.</item>
                  <item>Prophets, put for interpreters of the ſcriptures, &amp; howe they ought to exerciſe their office in the Church. 1. Corinth 14.29, 32.</item>
                  <item>✿ Proſelytes. Actes 2.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Proud perſons God reſiſteth. Luk. 1.51. Iam. 4.6. 1. Pet. 5.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Proue the ſpirites. 1. Iohn 4.1.</item>
                  <item>Proue himſelfe muſt euery ma<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 1. Cor. 11.28. 2. Cor. 13.5.</item>
                  <item>Proue all things. 1. Theſſ. 5.21.</item>
                  <item>✿ Publicanes. Matth 5.46 matt. 9.10. Luke 3.12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Puniſhment of euery ſinne that is openly knowen, is co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                     <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to the magiſtrates. Rom. 13.4. 1. Peter 2.14.</item>
                  <item>Puniſhment none commeth to the faithful, ſaue for a time to correct them. 1. Corinth. 11.32. 1. Peter 4.12.</item>
                  <item>Puniſhment euerlaſting for the vnbeleeuers. Matth. 3.12. mart. 25.41. Marke 9.44. Reuelat. 20.15. Reuel. 21.8.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="Q" type="part">
               <head>Q.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ QVadrin. Marke 12.42.</item>
                  <item>Quartus. Romanes 16.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Queene of the South. Matth. 12.42.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Quench not the ſpirite. 1. Theſſ. 5.19.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:37"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Queſtions curious and vnprofitable, together with all diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putations and contentions of words muſt be auoyded. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 14.1. Phil. 2.14. 1. Tim. 1.4. 1. Tim. 6.4, 20. 2. Tim. 2.23. Tit. 3.9. Looke more in the word Contention.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="R" type="part">
               <head>R.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>RAbbi, Matth. 23.7. Iohn. 1.38.</item>
                  <item>Rabboni. Iohn. 20.16.</item>
                  <item>Raca. Matt. 5.22.</item>
                  <item>Rahab the harlot. Heb. 11.31. Iam. 2.25.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Raiment bodily ſhould not be cared for. Mat. 6.25, 28.</item>
                  <item>Raiment, the ſuperfluitie of it muſt be taken away. Luk. 3.11, Luk. 7.25. Iam. 2.2. 1. Iohn. 3.17.</item>
                  <item>Raiment muſt be ſimple and honeſt. 1. Tim. 3.9. 1. Pet. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>Raiment which God ſendeth vs, we muſt be content with. 1. Tim. 6.8.</item>
                  <item>Raiment ſpirituall. Mat. 22.11. Luk. 24.49. Rom. 13.12. 2. Cor. 5.2. Galat. 3.27. Ephe. 4.24. Coloſſ. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Railyng ſpeaches forbidden. Matth. 5.22.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reading of Scripture neceſſarie &amp; meete for Courtiers. Act. 8.28.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Readines, ſee Chearefulneſſe.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reaſon of man is blynde in ſpirituall matters. Matt. 13.56. Matth. 15.33. Matth. 16.14, 22. Matth. 22.29. Luk. 24.45. Ioh. 3.4, 12. Iohn. 7.12. Iohn. 8.57. Iohn. 9.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Recompence or rewarde promiſed to them that woorke well. Mat. 6.4, 6, 18. Mat. 16.27. Act. 10.4. 2. Cor. 5.10. 1. Tim. 6.19. 2. Tim. 4.8. Heb. 6.10. Heb. 10.3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>. Heb. 11.26.</item>
                  <item>Recompence or rewarde is notwithſtanding of Gods free goodnes. Matt. 20.9, 10. &amp;c. Luk. 14.24. Luk. 17.10. Coloſſ. 3.24.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reconciliation towards our neighbour. Matth. 5.24.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Regeneration. Iohn. 3.3. Iam. 1.18. 1. Pet. 1.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Reioyce in the fleſh. 2. Cor. 11.18.</item>
                  <item>✿ Reioyce in the face, and not in the heart. 2. Cor. 5.12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reioyce we ought alwayes. 2. Cor. 6.10. Phil. 4.4. 1. Theſſ. 5.16.</item>
                  <item>Reioyce we ought in tribulations and perſecutions. Matt. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>.12. Act. 5.41. 1. Theſſ. 1.6. Heb. 10.34. Iam. 1.2. 1. Pet. 4.13.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:38"/>
                  <item>Reioyce we ought with them that reioyce. Rom. 12.15.</item>
                  <item>Reioyce we ought that our names are written in heauen. Luk. 10.20.</item>
                  <item>Reioycing but not good. 1. Cor. 5.6.</item>
                  <item>Reioycing of the faithfull ones. Galat. 6.4, 14.</item>
                  <item>Reioycing ought to be in God. 1. Cor. 1.31. 2. Cor. 10.17.</item>
                  <item>Reioyce we ought in Chriſt and his croſſe. Galat. 6.14. Phil. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>Reioyce we ought in our tribulations. Actes. 5.41. Rom. 5.3. Iam. 1.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Religion pure and vndefiled. Iam. 1.27.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Remembraunce of former life is profitable. Iohn. 4.29. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 6.21. Coloſ. 1.21. Coloſ. 3.7, 8. 1. Tim. 1.13, 14. &amp;c. 1. Tim. 5.9, 10. 2. Tim. 3.10, 11. Tit. 3.3, 4. Heb. 10.32. &amp;c. 1. Pet. 4.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Rent the clothes or garmentes, and what it ment among the Iewes. Mat. 26.65.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Renounce and forſake muſt a man him ſelfe, and all that he hath, to follow Chriſt. Mat. 16.24, 25. Luk. 14.33.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Repentance and amendement of life muſt be preached. Matt. 3.2. Mat. 4.17. Luk. 24.47. Act. 2.38. Act. 3.19. Act. 17.30.</item>
                  <item>Repentance &amp; faith muſt be ioyned together. Marke. 1.15. Act. 20.21.</item>
                  <item>Repentance is the gift and worke of God. Iohn. 12.40. Act. 5.31. Act. 11.18. 2. Tim. 1.25.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Repetitions often and vaine ought to be auoyded in prai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er. Matth. 6.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reprobates are curſed, or the children of curſe. Matth. 25.4. 2. Pet. 2.14.</item>
                  <item>Reprobates are veſſels of wrath and of diſhonour, appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to perdition. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 1.28. Rom. 9.22. 2. Theſſ. 2.12. 2. Tim. 2.20. 2. Pet. 2.12. Iude 4.</item>
                  <item>✿ Reproue, put for openly to conuince. Iohn. 16.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reſurrectio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> ſpiritual by faith. Luk. 2.34. Ioh. 11.25. Coloſſ. 2.12. Coloſſ. 3.1.</item>
                  <item>Reſurrection or riſing againe of the dead. Ioh. 5.28. Ioh. 11.24. Act. 24.15. Act. 26.8. 1. Cor. 15. throughout.</item>
                  <item>Reſurrection ſhalbe co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mon to the godly and vngodly, but of the one to life euerlaſting, &amp; of the other to euerlaſting
<pb facs="tcp:181144:38"/> co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>demnatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. Mat. 25.46. Ioh. 5.28, 29. Act. 24.15. Reu. 20.13.</item>
                  <item>Reſurrection and the order thereof 1. Corin. 15.42, 43. &amp;c. 1. Theſſ. 4.7.</item>
                  <item>Reſurrection of Chriſt is the foundation of our reſurrecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on. 1. Cor. 15.13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20. 1. Theſſ. 4.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reuengement is forbidden to priuate perſons. Matt. 5.22, 38, 39, 44. Mat. 6.14, 15. Luk. 9.54, 55. Rom. 12.17, 19. 1. Theſſ. 5.15. 1. Pet. 3.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reward of hypocrites is in this life. Mat. 6.2.</item>
                  <item>Reward of ſinne are other ſinnes. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 1.28. 2. Theſſ. 2.10. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Reward of the faithful is in heauen. Matt. 5.12.</item>
                  <item>Reward of the faithfull is life euerlaſting. Matt. 19.29. Matt. 26.46. Rom. 6.29.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Reward, reade Recompence.</item>
                  <item>Rich men are not vtterly ſhut from the kingdome of God. Mat. 19.23.</item>
                  <item>Rich men with great paine receiue the Goſpel. Matt. 19.24.</item>
                  <item>Rich men ſome receiue the Goſpel. Mat. 27.57. Luk. 19.2, 3.</item>
                  <item>Rich men ought not ambitiouſly to ſeeke honour. Iam. 2.2, 3. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Rich to deſire to be, a daungerous thing. 1. Tim. 6.9.</item>
                  <item>Rich men wicked, wo pronounced againſt. Luk. 6.24. Iam. 5.1.</item>
                  <item>Rich man that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                        <desc>•••</desc>
                     </gap>d in pleaſure. Luk. 16.19. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Riches make not men bleſſed. Luk. 6.24. Luk. 12.15, 16.</item>
                  <item>Riches are deceitfull. Matt. 13.22. 1. Tim. 6.9. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Riches muſt be well vſed and ſpent. Luk. 12.33. Luk. 16.9, 10. 1. Tim. 6.17. 1. Iohn. 3.17.</item>
                  <item>Riches muſt not be truſt in. Luk. 12.15. &amp;c. 1. Tim. 6.17.</item>
                  <item>Riches and God cannot both be ſerued. Matt. 6.24.</item>
                  <item>Riches choke the word in ſome Matt. 12.22.</item>
                  <item>✿ Righteouſnes, put for the keeping of the law. Mat. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Righteouſnes, put for that which is vpright and holie. Act. 13.10.</item>
                  <item>Righteouſnes, vſed for vprightnes of conſcience. 2. Cor. 6.7.</item>
                  <item>Righteouſnes of faith. Act. 13.39. Rom. 3.22. Rom. 10.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Righteouſnes of man contrary to the righteouſneſſe of God. Rom. 10.3. Phil. 3.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Riot condemned. Tit. 1.6. 1. Pet. 4.2.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:39"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Riſing againe, reade Reſurrection.</item>
                  <item>✿ Rod, put for ſeueritie or ſharpnes. 1. Cor. 4.21.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="S" type="part">
               <head>S.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ SAbbath, Coloſſ. 2.16.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sabbath ſpirituall. Heb. 4.4, 5. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sacrifice of praiſe. Heb. 13.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sacrifice of Chriſtians or faithful people. Mat. 5.23. Rom. 12. 1. Phil. 4.18. Heb. 13.16. 1. Pet. 2.5.</item>
                  <item>Sacrifices for ſinnes in ſhadow &amp; figure. Heb. 8.3. Heb. 9.10.</item>
                  <item>Sacrifice for ſinne in effect and trueth, Chriſt onely. Hebr. 10.12. and in many other places of that Epiſtle.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sadduces were a ſect, which denyed the reſurrection of the dead, of whom ſee. Mat. 3.7. Mat. 16.6. Mat. 22.23. Act. 4.1. Act. 23.6, 7, 8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Saintes or holy ones are the faithfull called. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 1.7. Rom. 12.13. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 16.15. 1. Cor. 1.2. 1. Cor. 6.1, 2. 2. Cor. 13.12. Eph. 5.3. Phil. 1.1.</item>
                  <item>Salamis. Act. 13.5.</item>
                  <item>Salmona. Act. 27.7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Saluation, put for the plaine manifeſting and declaring of ſaluation. 1. Pet. 1.10.</item>
                  <item>Saluation, put for the doctrine of the Goſpel. Heb. 2.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Saluation is the gift of God, and that of his onely grace. Rom. 6.23. Ephe. 2.1, 5, 8. Tit. 3.47.</item>
                  <item>✿ Saluting one another is commended. Matt. 10.12. Matt. 28.9. Iohn. 20.19.</item>
                  <item>Samaria. Act. 8.5.</item>
                  <item>Samaritans would not receiue Chriſt. Luk. 9.53.</item>
                  <item>Samaritans deceiued by Simon Magus. Act. 8.11.</item>
                  <item>Samaritans and Iewes meddled not together. Iohn. 4.9.</item>
                  <item>Samaritan and his pitie. Luk. 10.33.</item>
                  <item>Samothracia. Act. 16.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sanctifie, put for to cauſe a thing to be counted holie. Matth. 25.17.</item>
                  <item>Sanctifying, put for prayſing and honouring. 1. Pet. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sanctification. 1. Cor. 1.30. 1. Theſſ. 4.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sandales. Mark. 6.9.</item>
                  <item>Sarah. Heb. 11.11. 1. Pet. 3, 6.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:39"/>
                  <item>Sardis. Reue. 1.11.</item>
                  <item>Saron. Act. 9.53.</item>
                  <item>✿ Satan, and what it ſignifieth. Mat. 16.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Satan in ſome ſort the author of ſinne. Iohn. 13.2. Act. 5.3</item>
                  <item>Satan, looke Deuil.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Satiſfaction, looke in the word Chriſt.</item>
                  <item>Saul called alſo Paul. Act. 13.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Scribes and what they were. Matth. 2.4. reade Phariſes.</item>
                  <item>✿ Scripture put for the olde Teſtament. Ioh. 5.39. Rom. 15.4. 1. Cor. 15.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Scripture is written for our cauſe. Rom. 4.24. 1. Cor. 9.10. 1. Cor. 10.11.</item>
                  <item>Scripture written for our learning, conſolation, correction, and full inſtruction to ſaluation. Iam. 20.31. Rom. 15.4. 2. Tim. 3.16.</item>
                  <item>Scripture beareth witneſſe of Chriſt. Luk. 24.27, 46. Iohn. 5.39. Iohn. 20.9. Act. 17.2. Act. 18.28. Rom. 16.26.</item>
                  <item>Scripture that it ſhould be fulfilled was neceſſarie. Matt. 26.54, 56. Luk. 24.26, 27, 44, 46. Iohn. 12.38. Iohn. 13.18. Iohn. 17.12. Iohn. 19.28, 36. Act. 1.16.</item>
                  <item>Scripture muſt trie all doctrine. Act. 17.11.</item>
                  <item>Scripture wreſted and falſely alledged by the deuill and wicked men. Matth. 4.6. 2. Pet. 3.16.</item>
                  <item>Secundus. Act. 20.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ See, put for to know. Matt. 9.4. Iohn. 6.40.</item>
                  <item>✿ See, put for to feele. Iohn. 8.51.</item>
                  <item>See, put for to enter into. Iohn. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>See death, reade Death.</item>
                  <item>✿ Seede, put for poſteritie. Mark. 12.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sell all for the kingdome of heauen. Mat. 13.44. Mat. 19.21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Selfe loue is daungerous. Mat. 7.4. Act. 6.1. &amp;c. 2. Tim. 3.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Seniors called alſo Ancients, which are taken for Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters of the word, or gouernours of diſcipline in y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Church Act. 15.22. Act. 20.17. 1. Tim. 4.14. 1. Tim. 5.17.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Separate vs from that loue that God beareth vs, nothing can. Rom. 8.39.</item>
                  <item>Sergius Paulus and his ſtorie. Act. 13.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Seruants ſtate no hinderaunce to godlines. 1. Cor. 7.22.</item>
                  <item>Seruants &amp; their duetie to their maſters. Matt. 9.9. Eph. 6.5.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:40"/> Coloſſ. 3.22. 1. Tim. 6.1. Tit. 2.9. 1. Pet. 2.18.</item>
                  <item>Seruants we are all vnprofitable. Luk. 17.10.</item>
                  <item>Seruant that knoweth the will of his maſter. &amp;c. Luke. 12.47.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Serue we muſt onely to God. Matt. 4.10.</item>
                  <item>Serue we muſt one another through charitie. Galat. 5.13.</item>
                  <item>Serue we ought not ſinne any longer. Rom. 6.6.</item>
                  <item>Serue we cannot two maſters. Mat. 6.24. reade Riches.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sheepe of Chriſt who they be, &amp; their diſpoſition. Iohn. 10.27.</item>
                  <item>Shepheards. Luk. 2.8, 15.</item>
                  <item>Shepheards in the Church. Eph. 4.11. where they are called Paſtors.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sickneſſe, reade Infirmitie.</item>
                  <item>✿ Signe, put for the thing it ſelfe. 1. Timo. 2.8. 1. Timo. 5.22.</item>
                  <item>Signe of the ſonne of man, and what it is. Matth. 24.30.</item>
                  <item>Signe put for an accuſtomed and miraculous thing. Matth. 12.38, 39.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Silence, is a womans chiefe ornament. 1 Tim. 2.11.</item>
                  <item>Silence is commaunded. Iam. 1.19.</item>
                  <item>Siloam. Iohn. 9.7.</item>
                  <item>Siluanus. 1. Theſſ. 1.1.</item>
                  <item>Simeon and his ſtorie. Luk. 2.25, 26. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Simeon. Act. 13.1.</item>
                  <item>Simeon called Peter. Matt. 4.18. Matt. 10.2.</item>
                  <item>Simon Peter his notable confeſſion. Matt. 16.16.</item>
                  <item>Simons ſhamefull deniall of Chriſt. Matt. 26.69. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Simon, ſee more in this word Peter.</item>
                  <item>Simon the Phariſe, in whoſe houſe Chriſt did eate. Luke. 7.40.</item>
                  <item>Simon the Cananite. Matth. 10.4.</item>
                  <item>Simon of Cyrene. Matth. 27.32.</item>
                  <item>Simon Magus the ſorcerer and his ſtorie. Act. 8.9, 10. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Simon the Tanner Peters hoſt. Act. 9.43. Act. 10.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Simplicitie or ſingleneſſe, a vertue moſt neceſſarie for all Chriſtians. Matth. 5.8, 37. Matth. 10.16, 23. Iohn. 1.47. Act. 2.46. Rom. 16.19. 1. Cor. 14.20. 2. Cor. 11.3.</item>
                  <item>Singleneſſe, ſee Simplicitie.</item>
                  <item>✿ Single life in what reſpect preferred before Marriage.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:40"/> 1. Cor. 7.26.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sinne is in all men, reade, Man euery one is a ſinner.</item>
                  <item>Sinne engendreth death. Roman. 6.23. Roman. 7.13. Iam. 1.15.</item>
                  <item>Sinne he that obeyeth, is the ſeruaunt thereof. Iohn. 8.34. Rom. 6.16. 2. Pet. 2.19.</item>
                  <item>Sinne he that committeth, is of the deuill. 1. Iohn. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sinne what it is. 1. Iohn. 3.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sinne puniſhed with ſinne. Acts. 7.42. Acts. 28.27. Rom. 1.24.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sinne, put for the price of ſinne. Rom. 8.3. 2. Cor. 5.21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sinne originall. Rom. 5.12.</item>
                  <item>Sinne againſt the holy Ghoſt, which is alſo vnpardonable. Mat. 12.31. Heb. 6.4, 5, 7. Heb. 10.29. 2. Pet. 2.22. 1. Ioh. 5.16.</item>
                  <item>Sinnes are not equall. Matth. 11.21. Luk. 12.47, 48. Act. 3.17. Iam. 2.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sinners called to repentance. Mat. 9.13. 2. Pet. 3.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sinner a woman. Luk. 7.37.</item>
                  <item>Syria. Galat. 1.21.</item>
                  <item>✿ Siſters of Chriſt. Matth. 13.56.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sit in Moſes ſeate, and what it is. Matt. 23.2, 3.</item>
                  <item>Sit at the right hande or left hande in Chriſtes kingdome. Matth. 20.21.</item>
                  <item>Sit at the right hand of God. Act. 2.34.</item>
                  <item>Sit with Chriſt. Reue. 3.21.</item>
                  <item>Sit at the feete, put for to be a ſcholer. Luk. 10.39. Act. 22.3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sleepe, put for darkneſſe of ignorance and wicked affecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons. Rom. 13.11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sluggiſhneſſe muſt be ſhaken off. Matth. 7.8. Matth. 19.30. Matth. 24.39, 44, 45. Matth. 25.8, 28. Luk. 12.35, 36. Luke. 19.44. Luk. 24.25 Iohn. 8.2. Act. 2.41. Act. 20.9, 10, 11. 1. Cor. 15.34. 1. Cor. 16.13. Phil. 2.12. Coloſſ. 4.2, 17. 1. Tim. 4.15. 2. Tim. 1.6. Heb. 3.13. Heb. 6.12. Heb. 12.12, 13. 1. Pet. 5.2. 2. Pet. 1.5, 12, 13. 2. Pet. 3.9, 17.</item>
                  <item>Smyrna. Reue. 1.11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sobernes of minde is commended. Acts. 26.25. Rom. 12.3. 1. Theſſ. 5.8. Titus. 2.6. 1. Peter. 1.13. 1. Peter. 4.7. 1. Peter. 5.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Solomons porch. Iohn. 10.23. Act. 3.11.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:41"/>
                  <item>✿ Song of Marie the mother of Chriſt. Luk. 1.46, 47. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Song of Simeon. Luk. 2.29. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Song of Zacharias. Luk. 1.68, 69. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Songs of the faythfull are ſpirituall. Ephe. 5.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sonnes of God. Luk. 20.36. Ioh. 1.12. Rom. 8.14. 2. Cor. 6.18. Galat. 3.26. 1. Iohn. 3.1.</item>
                  <item>Sopater. Act. 20.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sorcerers or diuiners, and their puniſhment. Acts. 8.9. Act. 13.8. Act. 16.16. Reue. 21.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sorrowe is of two ſorts. 2. Cor. 7.10.</item>
                  <item>Sorrowe for the dead is of two ſorts. 1. Theſſ. 4.13.</item>
                  <item>Soſthenes. 1. Cor. 1.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Souldiers ſhould liue well. Luk. 3.14. Act. 10.7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Soule, put for the affection of the heart. Matt. 26.38. Luk. 1.46. Iohn. 12.27.</item>
                  <item>Soule taken for the wil ioyned with vnderſtanding. 1. Theſſ. 5.23. 1. Pet. 1.22.</item>
                  <item>Soule, put for man. Act. 2.43. Rom. 13.1. 1. Pet. 3.20.</item>
                  <item>Soule, put for life, or the vitall ſpirit. Luk. 12.20.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Soules ſleepe not after this life. Luk. 16.25. Reue. 6.9.</item>
                  <item>Soules of the faithful after this life periſhe not. 2. Cor. 5.1, 2, 8, 9. Phil. 1.23. Heb. 12.23.</item>
                  <item>Soule and the immortalitie thereof, reade Immortalitie.</item>
                  <item>✿ Speach by the way of compariſon. Matt. 9.13. Matt. 11.22. Matt. 12.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Speach euill generally or particularly one of another is condemned. Mat. 12.36. 2. Tim. 3.2. Tit. 3.2. Iam. 1.26. Iam. 3.2, 9. Iam. 4.11. 1. Pet. 2.1. 1. Pet. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>Speach which is vaine is condemned. Matt. 12.36. Ephe. 5.4.</item>
                  <item>Speaches of the faithfull ones are manie times by the vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>godly interrupted and cut of. Act. 7.57. Act. 22.22, 23. Act. 23.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Speake within them ſelues, put for to thinke. Matt. 9.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Speaking euil one of another forbidden. Iam. 4.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ Speake, put for to promiſe. Luk. 1.70.</item>
                  <item>✿ Speake and teach differ. Act. 10.25.</item>
                  <item>✿ Spirite, put for the Goſpel. 2. Cor. 3.6. Galat. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>Spirite, put for the minde or ſoule of man. 1. Corinth. 2.11. 2. Cor. 7.1.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:41"/>
                  <item>Spirite, put for will, minde and counſell. Luk. 9.55. 1. Corin. 5. 3. Philip. 1.27. 1. Theſſ. 5.23.</item>
                  <item>Spirit, put for teachers or prophets. 1. Iohn 4.1.</item>
                  <item>Spirit, put for the gifts of the ſpirit. Actes 8.15. Actes 19.2, 5. Galat. 3.2.</item>
                  <item>Spirite, put for earneſtnes of zeale towardes God. 1. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moth. 4.12.</item>
                  <item>Spirit, put for ioy in the holy Ghoſt. Epheſ. 5.18.</item>
                  <item>Spirit, put for that part of man, which is reformed by the holy Ghoſt. Matth. 26.41.</item>
                  <item>Spirit double, to wit, of God and the worlde. 1. Corinthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans 2.12.</item>
                  <item>Spirite double, to wit, of bondage &amp; adoption. Rom. 8.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Spirit holy, or holy Ghoſt is God. Matt. 28.19. Luke 3.22. Iohn 7.39. Iohn 14.17. Iohn 16.13. Actes 2.4. Actes 5.3, 4. Acts 13.2. Acts 16.6. 1. Corin. 3.16. 1. Corinth. 6.19. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 12.11. Galat. 4.6. 1. Iohn 5.7.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy, or holy Ghoſt reſembled to fire. Matthewe 3.11.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy, or holy Ghoſt, reſembled to water. Iohn 3.5.</item>
                  <item>Spirit holy, or holy Ghoſt, is no framer of newe reuelatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s. Iohn 14.26.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is the earneſt or pledge of Gods promiſes in our heartes. Rom. 8.15, 16. 2. Corinth. 1.22. 2. Corinth. 5.5. Galat. 4.6. Epheſ. 1.14.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is the author of holy ſcripture. Hebrewes 4.7. Heb. 10.15. 2. Peter 1.21.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is the directer and leader of the faithfull. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thew 4. 1. Marke 1.13, 14. Luke 2.27. Iohn 16.13. Actes 20.23. Romanes 8.14.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy appeared in the likenes of a Doue. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thewe 3.16.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy dwelleth in the faythfull. 1. Corinth. 3.16.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy and his office. Iohn 14.16. Iohn 15.26. Ioh. 16.7, 8, 13. 1. Corinth. 6.11. 1. Corinth. 12.3, 4. 2. Timoth. 1.14. 1. Iohn 2.27. 1. Iohn 5.6, 7.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy called the ſpirit of God. Matth. 3.16. Matthew 12.28. Actes 2.17. Actes 5.9. Romanes 8.9, 14. 1. Corinth. 3.16. 1. Theſ. 4.8.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:42"/>
                  <item>Spirite holy called the ſpirite of Chriſt. Rom. 8.9. Gal. 4.6.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is one. 1. Corinthians 12.13. Epheſians 2.18. Epheſians 4.4.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy called the comforter. Iohn 14.16, 26. Iohn 15.26. Actes 9.31.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy quickeneth. Iohn 6.63.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy the ſpirite of trueth. Iohn 14.17. Iohn 15.26. Iohn 16.13.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy, the maſter and teacher of the faithfull. Luke 12.12. Iohn 14.26. 1. Corinth. 2.13.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is the ſhewer of things to come. Iohn 16.13. 1. Timoth. 4.1.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is the witnes of Chriſt. Iohn 15.26. Actes. 5.32. 1. Iohn 5.6.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is the diſtributer of all the giftes. 1. Corinthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans 12.11.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy onely knoweth the thinges of God. 1. Corin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thians 2.11.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy helpeth the faithfuls infirmities, and maketh petition for them. Romanes 8.26.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is giuen and ſent of the Father. Iohn 14.26. Actes 5.32. 2. Corinth. 1.22. 2 Corinth. 5.5. Galat. 4.6.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is giuen and ſent of Chriſt. Iohn 4.14. Iohn 15.26. Iohn 16.7. Iohn 20.22. Epheſ. 4.7.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy called the ſpirit of adoption. Ro. 8.15. Gal. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is the water of life. Iohn 4.14. Iohn 7.38.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy is the vnction or anointing. Luke 4.18. Act. 10.38. 1. Iohn 2.20, 27.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy and his comming vpon the Apoſtles. Actes 2.1, 2, 3. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Spirite holy, &amp; his workes and fruites. Galat. 5.22.</item>
                  <item>✿ Spirite of man. Matthewe 27.50. Luke 8.55. Luke 23.46. Romanes 8.16. 1. Corinthians 2.11. 1. Corinthians 5.3. 1. Theſſ. 5.23. Heb. 12.33.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Spirite of diſcerning &amp; iudgement ought to be in Gods children. Matth. 7.15, 16. Iohn 7.17. Actes 17.11. Acts 20.28. &amp;c. Acts 28.6. Philip. 1.9, 10. 1. Iohn 4.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Spirite hath neither fleſh nor bones. Luke 24.39.</item>
                  <item>✿ Spirites wicked and vncleane, reade Deuill.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:42"/>
                  <item>✿ Stater, and what it is. Matth. 17.27.</item>
                  <item>Stephan and his ſtorie. Acts 6.5, 6. &amp;c. Acts 7. throughout.</item>
                  <item>✿ Stoickes. Acts 17.18.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Strengthening of confirming neceſſarie for the mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters of God. Acts 18.9. Actes 23.11. Acts 10.16.</item>
                  <item>Strengthening or confirming in the faith neceſſary for al the godly ones. Matth. 9.22. Luke 1.36. Acts 11.23. Acts 14.22. Actes 15.36. Actes 16.5. Actes 18.23, 27. Actes 20.1, 2, 6. Actes 21.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Strife and debate muſt be auoided. Matth. 5.25. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 6.1, 2. &amp;c. Galat. 5.20. Iames 4.1. See Contentio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>.</item>
                  <item>Strifes howe they may be ended. Matth. 5.25.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sufficiencie or contentednes is a great treaſure. 2. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 9.8. 1. Timoth. 6.6.</item>
                  <item>Sufficiencie or co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>tentednes muſt be meaſured by Gods wil, &amp; not according to abundance of things. Phi. 4.11.</item>
                  <item>✿ Supper of the Lord miniſtred by Paul. Acts 20.7.</item>
                  <item>✿ Supper of the Lord inſtituted. Matth. 26.26, 27. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Surfetting is condemned. Luke 21.34. Rom. 13.13. Suſanna. Luke 8.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Swearing vaine forbidden, ſee Othe.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sworde of the ſpirite is the word of God. Epheſ. 6.17.</item>
                  <item>✿ Sworde taken for affliction. Luke 2 35.</item>
                  <item>Sworde taken for diſcord. Matth. 10.34.</item>
                  <item>Sworde, for the material ſworde, the vſe whereof is co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to the magiſtrate. Rom. 13.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Sworde and the vſe thereof prohibited to priuate per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons. Matth. 5.39. Matth. 26.52. Reuelat. 13.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Synogogues and what they were. Matth. 4.23.</item>
                  <item>Syrtes. Actes 27.17.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="T" type="part">
               <head>T.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ TAble, put for that wherein men chiefly delight. Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manes 11.9.</item>
                  <item>Tables vſed for offices, perteining to the care of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> poore. Acts 6.2.</item>
                  <item>✿ Tabernacle, put for body. 2. Corinth. 5.1. 2. Peter 1.13.</item>
                  <item>Tabitha and her ſtorie. Acts 9.36, 40.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:43"/>
                  <item>✿ Tabitha cumi. Marke 5.41.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Talke, ſee Idle.</item>
                  <item>✿ Taſte of death, ſee Death.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Teachers appointed in the Church. Acts 13.1. 1. Corin. 12.28. Epheſ. 4.11.</item>
                  <item>Teachers falſe muſt be auoyded. Coloſſ. 2.8. 2. Timoth. 3.5. Titus 1.13, 14. Titus 3.9, 10. 2 Peter 3.17. 2. Iohn 10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Temple ſpiritual, reade Faithful.</item>
                  <item>Temple material. Matth. 21.12. Matth. 24. 1. Iohn 2.14.</item>
                  <item>Temples made with handes, God dwelleth not in, reade, God dwelleth not in Temples made with handes.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Tempt, God doth not to euill. Iames 1.13.</item>
                  <item>Tempt God we muſt not. Matthew 4.7. Actes 15.10. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 10.9. Hebrewes 3.10.</item>
                  <item>Tempt the ſpirit of the Lorde. Actes 5.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Ten, put for many. Reuelat. 13.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Tentation, put for aduerſitie, or affliction. Iames 1.2, 12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Tentation is good, when God proueth the fayth and conſtancie of his by the croſſe and afflictions. 1. Corin. 10.13. Heb. 11.17. Iames 1.2, 12. 1. Peter 1.6.</item>
                  <item>Tentation euil whereby Satan draweth one away fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> God, &amp; leadeth him to deſtruction. Matth 4.1. Luke 8.13. Acts 5.3. 1. Cor. 7.5. Galat. 6.1. 1. Theſ. 3.5. 1. Timoth. 6.9. Reue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lat. 2.10.</item>
                  <item>Tentation out of, God onely deliuereth vs. Mat. 6.13. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 10.13. 2. Peter 2.9. Reuelat. 3.10.</item>
                  <item>Tentation to be deliuered from, we muſt pray to God. Mat. 6.13. matth. 26.41. Luke 22.40.</item>
                  <item>Tertullus the Orator againſt Paul. Acts 24.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Teſtament olde. 2. Corinth. 3.14. Galat. 4.24. Hebre. 8.9. Hebrewes 9.15.</item>
                  <item>Teſtament old, the bloud whereof was of Bulles &amp; Goates. Heb. 9.12, 19. Hebrewes 10.4.</item>
                  <item>Teſtament newe. Matth. 26.28. 1. Corinth. 11.25. 2. Corin. 3.6. Heb. 8.8. Heb 9.15. Heb. 12.24.</item>
                  <item>Teſtament newe, the bloud whereof is Chriſtes bloud. Matt. 26.28. Luke 22.20. 1. Corinth. 11.25. Hebre. 9.12, 14. Heb. 10.19, 29. Heb. 12.24. Heb. 13.20.</item>
                  <item>Teſtaments two, &amp; an Allegorie thereof Galat. 4.24. &amp;c.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:43"/>
                  <item>✿ Tetrarch. Matth. 14.1. Luke 3.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Thankes giuing neceſſarie for al the godly. Iohn 6.11, 23. Actes 27.35. Romanes 14.6. 1. Corinthians 1.4. 1. Corin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thians 14.18. 1. Corinth. 15.57. 2. Corinth. 2.14. 2. Corinthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans 4.15. 2. Corinthians 9.11, 15 Epheſians 5.4 20. Philip. 1.3. Philip. 4.6. Coloſſ. 1.1, 2. Coloſ. 2.7. Coloſ. 3.15, 17. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loſ. 4.2. 1. Theſſ. 1.2. 1. Theſ. 2.12. 1. Theſ. 5.8. 2. Theſ. 1.3. 2. Theſ. 2.13. 1. Timoth. 1, 12. 1. Timoth. 2.1. 1. Timothie 4.3. Reuelat. 7.12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Thankes to God before meales and after. Looke in the word Grace.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Thankfulnes of one towards an other, &amp; examples there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of. Luke 24.29. Actes 11.29. Actes 16.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Theeues and theft condemned and forbidden. Matth. 19.18. Rom 2.21. Rom. 13.9. 1. Corinth. 6.10. Epheſ. 4.28. 1. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moth. 1.10. 1. Peter 4.15.</item>
                  <item>Theophilus. Luke 1.3. Acts 1.1.</item>
                  <item>Theudas, an author of ſedition. Actes 5.36.</item>
                  <item>Thomas called Didymus. Iohn 11.16. Iohn 20.24.</item>
                  <item>Thomas his vnbeliefe. Iohn 20.25.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Thought and care muſt be put away. Matth. 6.34. Luke 12.22. 1. Corinth. 7.32.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Thoughts euill are ſinnes before God. Matthewe 15.19. Actes 8.22.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Threatnings ſtirre vp the rage of the wicked. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thewe 21.46.</item>
                  <item>Threatnings of the Goſpell howe feareful. Actes 5.5.</item>
                  <item>Threatnings of the enemies ought to pricke vs forwarde to praier. Acts 4.29.</item>
                  <item>Thyadra. Reuelat. 1.11.</item>
                  <item>Tiberius Caeſar. Luke 3.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Till, diuerſly vſed in ſcripture. Matth. 5.8, 26. matth. 23.39. 1. Corinth. 15.25. Galat. 3.19. Reuelat. 20.5.</item>
                  <item>✿ Time certaine, put for an vncertaine. Luke 13.33.</item>
                  <item>Time preſent, put for the time to come. Matth. 3.10. Luke 19.8. Luke 24.44. Ioh. 4.21. Iohn 20.17. Coloſ. 3.6. 1. Theſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſalonians 4.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Times which are laſt, and places ſpeaking thereof. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinthians 10.11. 2. Timoth. 3.1. Hebrewes 1.1. 1. Pet. 1.20.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:44"/> 1. Peter 4.7. 1. Iohn 2.18. Iude 18. Looke in the worde Daies.</item>
                  <item>Time to come appertaineth not to vs to knowe. Acts 1.7.</item>
                  <item>Time of Chriſt is the time of Grace. Marke 1.15. Romanes 5.6. 2. Corinth. 6. 2. Galat. 4.4.</item>
                  <item>Time which we haue is ſhort. 1. Corinth. 7.29.</item>
                  <item>Time ought to be recouered and redeemed. Epheſ. 5.16. Coloſſ. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Timotheus &amp; places ſpeaking of him. Actes 16.1, 2. &amp;c. 1. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinth. 4.17. 1. Corinth. 16.10, 11. Philipp. 1. 1. Philippians 2.19, 20. &amp;c. 1. Theſſ. 1.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Time, put for receyuing of tithes. Matth. 23.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Tongue is the image of the minde or heart. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thewe 12.34.</item>
                  <item>Tongue and the nature there of Iames 3.5, 6, 7. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Tongue muſt be bridled &amp; reſtrayned from euill. Matth. 12.36. Iames 1.26. Iames 3.2, 5, 6. &amp;c. 1. Peter 3.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Tongues diuers to ſpeake, is the gift of the holy Ghoſt. Acts 2.4. Acts 10.45, 46. Acts 19.6. 1. Corinth. 12.28.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Tongue muſt be vſed in y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> church which is vnderſtood. 1. Corinth. 14. almoſt throughout the whole Chapter.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Traditions, reade Commaundements.</item>
                  <item>✿ Tranſfiguration of Chriſt. Matth. 17.2. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Treaſon and traytors condemned. Matthewe 26.24. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thewe 27.3, 4, 5. Marke 14.21. Luke 6.16. Actes 7.52. 2. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mothie 3.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Treaſure is to be laid vp in heauen. Mat. 6.20. Mat. 19.21.</item>
                  <item>Treaſures of God are in Chriſt. Coloſſ. 2.3.</item>
                  <item>Treaſure of the Goſpell. Matth. 13.44. 2. Corin. 4.7.</item>
                  <item>Treaſure vaine and tranſitorie. Luke 12.15. &amp;c. Iam. 5, 2, 3.</item>
                  <item>✿ Tree good and euill. Matth 7.17, 18. Matth. 12.33.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Tribulation we muſt be patient in. Romanes 12.12. 2. Theſſ. 1.4.</item>
                  <item>Tribulation bringeth forth patience. Rom. 5.3.</item>
                  <item>Tribulatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s of our owne, God comforteth vs in, that we might comfort others in theirs. 2. Corinth. 1.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Tribute ought to be payed to Princes and Magiſtrates. Matth. 17.25, 26, 27. Matth. 22.21. Rom. 13.6, 7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Trie, reade Proue.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:44"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Trinitie proued Matthewe 18.19. 2. Corinthians 13.13. 1. Iohn 5.7.</item>
                  <item>Trophimus an Epheſian, Paules companion. Actes 20.4. Actes 21.29.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Trouble is to them that are maried. 1. Corinth. 7.28.</item>
                  <item>✿ Trueth, put for all light left in man after his fall. Rom. 1.18. Rom. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>Trueth, put for true and ſincere knoweledge of God. Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tus 1.1.</item>
                  <item>Trueth, put for ſinceritie and vpright dealing. Epheſ. 4.25. Epheſ. 6.14. Philip. 4.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Trueth cannot be vanquiſhed. Matth. 16.18. Luke 21.15. Actes 6.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Trueth to be of, or to be of the trueth. Iohn 18.37. 1. Iohn 3.19.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Trueth muſt be done and followed. Ioh. 3.21. Epheſians 4.15. 1. Iohn 1.6. Againſt them which withdrawe them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelues from the trueth, and withſtand or diſobey it. Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manes 2.8. Galatians 3. 1. Galatians 5.7. 2. Timoth. 2.18. 2. Timothie 3.8. 2. Timoth. 4.4. Titus 1.4. Hebrewes 10.26. 2. Peter 2.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Turning to the Lord co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>meth fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the Lord. Act. 26.18.</item>
                  <item>Turning to God ioyned with repentance. Acts 26.20.</item>
                  <item>Turning, ſee Conuerſion.</item>
                  <item>Tychicus. Actes 20.4. Epheſ. 6 21.</item>
                  <item>Tyrannus his ſchole. Acts 19.9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Tyrannie and crueltie. Matth. 2.16. mat. 14.10. Acts 7.59. Acts 12.2, 3. &amp;c. ſee more in the worde Crueltie.</item>
                  <item>Tyrus. Actes 21.3.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="V" type="part">
               <head>V.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> VAine glory is forbidden. Matth. 23.6, 7. Galat. 5.26. Philip. 2.3. ſee alſo Glory vaine.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vaine repetitions, looke Repetitions.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vaine ſpeache, reade Speache.</item>
                  <item>✿ Vanitie of the Athenians. Actes 17.21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vanitie of man, reade Mans vanitie.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vaunting, reade Bragging or boaſting.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:45"/>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vengeance belongeth onely to the Lord. Romanes 12.19. 1. Theſſ. 4.6. Hebrewes 10.30.</item>
                  <item>Vengeance ſhalbe declared agaynſt the perſecuters of Gods elect, and againſt all rebels. Luke 18.7. 1. Theſſ. 1.8. Reuelat. 6.10. Reuelat. 19.2.</item>
                  <item>Vengeance is committed alſo to the magiſtrate. Rom. 13.4. 1. Peter 2.4.</item>
                  <item>Vengeance, reade Reuengement.</item>
                  <item>✿ Vertue, put for good and godly maners. 2. Peter 1.5.</item>
                  <item>✿ Veſſell, put for body. 1. Theſſ. 4.4.</item>
                  <item>Veſſels ſome to honor and ſome to diſhonor. Rom. 9.21. 2. Timoth. 2.20.</item>
                  <item>✿ Vipers poyſon very daungerous &amp; hurtfull. Acts 28.6.</item>
                  <item>✿ Virgins and virginitie. 1. Corinth. 7.25, 26. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Viſions ſhewed to Paul. Actes 16.9. Actes 18.9. Acts 22.17. Acts 27.23. 2. Corinth. 12.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Viſite, put for to ſhewe him ſelfe mindfull. Luke 1.68.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Viſite the ſicke and priſoners. Matth. 25.36.</item>
                  <item>Viſite the fatherles and widowes. Iames 1.27.</item>
                  <item>✿ Viſitation, put for the time of manifeſting Gods mercie. Luke 19.44. 1. Peter 2.12.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vnbeliefe. Matth. 17.20. Marke 9.24. Marke 16.14. Iohn 6.64. Iohn 10.25. Iohn 20.27. Rom. 11.30.</item>
                  <item>✿ Vncircumciſion, put for the Gentiles. Galat. 2.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vngodly, ſee Wicked.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vnitie commended. Acts 4.32. Romanes 15.6. 1. Corin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thians. 1.10. Epheſians 4.3. Philippians 3.16. 1. Peter 3.8. ſee Concord.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vnitie in God and Chriſt. Iohn 17.21.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vnthankefulneſſe towardes God or man condemned. Marke 5.17. Luke 14.18. Luke. 17.11, 12. Iohn 1.5. Actes 7.18, 19, 26, 27. &amp;c. Actes 27.42. Romanes 1.21. Galat. 1.6. Galatians 6.6. 1. Corinthians 16.18. Coloſſians 2.7. 1. Tim. 5.4, 17, 18. 2. Tim. 3. 2. Heb. 2.3. Heb. 13.17. Reuelat. 2.5.</item>
                  <item>✿ Vocation or calling to followe Chriſt. Matth. 8.22. Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thewe 9.9. Iohn 1.43.</item>
                  <item>Vocation or calling to preach. Matth. 4.18, 19. Marke 3.14. Luke 6.13. Romanes 1.1. 1. Corinth. 1. 1. Galat. 1.15. reade, Choſen to ſome office or miniſterie.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:45"/>
                  <item>Vocation or calling to life euerlaſting &amp; eternal ſaluation. Rom. 8.29, 30. Rom. 9.24. Rom. 11.29. 1. Cor. 1.9, 24. Ephe. 4.1. 1. Tim. 2.12. 1. Theſſ. 5.24. 1. Tim. 6.12. 2. Tim. 1.9. 1. Pet. 2.9. 1. Pet. 5.10. 2. Pet. 1.3, 10.</item>
                  <item>Vocation or calling of the Gentiles. Iohn. 10.16. Rom. 9.24 Rom. 11.12. Rom. 15.9. ſee Gentiles.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Voluptuous liuing condemned. Luk. 8.14.</item>
                  <item>✿ Vowes vſed for giftes and ceremonies. Act. 21.23. Vowe, taken for promiſe to do euill. Act. 23.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Vſurie prohibited. Matth. 5.42. Luk. 6.30, 35.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="W" type="part">
               <head>W.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ WAges of ſinne is death euerlaſting. Rom. 6.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Waies, put for the order of Gods cou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſels and do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings. Rom. 11.33.</item>
                  <item>Way, put for ſect. Act. 19.23.</item>
                  <item>Way of God, put for Chriſtianitie. Act. 19.9.</item>
                  <item>Way of the Lord, put for the will of the Lord. Act. 18.25.</item>
                  <item>Way of righteouſnes, put for vpright life and conuerſati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on. Matt. 21.32.</item>
                  <item>Waies of man, and what they are. Act. 14.16.</item>
                  <item>Waies of God. Act. 13.10.</item>
                  <item>✿ Wake, put for to liue in this life. 1. Theſſ. 5.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Warfare, ſee Fight.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Watch we ought and be readie continually. Matth. 24.42, 43, 44. &amp;c. Matth. 26.41. Mark. 13.33. Luk. 12.37. Luk. 21.36. Act. 20.31. 1. Corin. 16.13. 2. Cor. 6.6. Ephe. 6.18. Coloſſ. 1.2. 1. Pet. 4.7. 1. Pet. 5.8. Reue. 3. 2. Reue. 16.15.</item>
                  <item>✿ Water flowing out of the rocke, a figure of Chriſtes blood. 1. Cor. 10.4.</item>
                  <item>Water pure, put for the grace of the holy Ghoſt. Heb. 10.23.</item>
                  <item>✿ Weake, put for him that doubteth in his conſcience. 1. Cor. 8.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Weake in the faith ought to be borne with, that they may be wonne. Rom. 14. 1. Rom. 15.1. 1. Cor. 9.22. 1. Theſſ. 5.22.</item>
                  <item>Weake ones muſt not be offended. Rom. 14.13. reade, Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence muſt not be giuen.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:46"/>
                  <item>Weake things of the world God chuſeth. 1. Cor. 1.27.</item>
                  <item>Weake in the body, ſee Infirme.</item>
                  <item>✿ Weapons carnall. 2. Cor. 10.4. reade Armour.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Well doing, ſee Good doing.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Whiſperers condemned. Rom. 1.29.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Whoredome, looke Adulterie.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Wicked or vngodly agree in oppreſſing or perſecuting the trueth and godly ones. Matt. 16. 1. Matt. 22.23. Mark. 3.6. Luk. 23.12. Act. 4.26. Act. 23.6.</item>
                  <item>Wicked or vngodly, pronounce ſentence againſt the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſelues Matth. 21.31, 41. Luk. 7.43. Act. 4.16. Act. 26.31.</item>
                  <item>Wicked or vngodly ſeeke and require a ſigne. Matth. 12.38. Matth. 16.4. Luk. 23.8. Iohn. 2.18. Iohn. 6.30.</item>
                  <item>Wicked or vngodly feare men more then God. Matt. 21.26, 46. Matth. 26.5. Matth. 27.64. Mark. 11.32. Luk. 19.48. Act. 5.26.</item>
                  <item>Wicked mens purpoſes &amp; indeuours, are many times made voyd. Matth. 2.13. Matth. 21.46. Matth. 22.22. Matth. 27.66. and the next Chapter. Iohn. 6.44, 45, 46. Iohn. 10.39. Act. 5. 19, 22. Act. 9.23, 24. &amp;c. Act. 12.11. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Widowes muſt be prouided for. 1. Tim. 5.3. Iam. 1.27.</item>
                  <item>Widowes miniſterie. Act. 6.1. 1. Tim. 5.9.</item>
                  <item>Widowes continencie. 1. Cor. 7.8. 1. Tim. 5.11, 16.</item>
                  <item>Widowe deuourers. Matth. 23.14. Mark. 12.40, Luk. 20.47.</item>
                  <item>✿ Widowe poore that offered in the Temple. Marke. 12.42.</item>
                  <item>Widowe importunate. Luk. 10.3.</item>
                  <item>Widowe of Nain. Luk. 7.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Wife of Pilate. Matth. 27.19.</item>
                  <item>Wife of Lot. Luk. 17.32.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Will of God, according whereunto he determineth and worketh all thinges. Matth. 18.14. Rom. 9.19. 1. Cor. 1.1. Ephe. 1.5. Heb. 2.4. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>. Pet. 3.17. 1. Pet. 4.19. Reue. 4.11.</item>
                  <item>Will of God, put for his wil reuealed in his word, according to which he commaundeth vs and requireth of vs euery thing. Matth. 12.50. Iohn. 7.17. Rom. 2.18. 1. Theſſalo. 4.3. 1. Theſſaloni. 5.18. Hebrew. 10.36. 1. Peter. 2.15. 1. Iohn. 2.17.</item>
                  <item>Will of GOD we muſt ſeeke to vnderſtande and fulfill.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:46"/> Matth. 7.21. Rom. 12. 2. Ephe. 5.17. 1. Pet. 4.2.</item>
                  <item>Will of God we ought to pray for, that it may be done. Mat. 6.10. Matth. 26.42. Coloſſ. 4.12. Heb. 13.21.</item>
                  <item>Will of God we muſt referre al things to. Act. 18.21. Act. 21.14. Rom. 1.10. Rom. 15.32. 1. Cor. 4.19. 1. Cor. 16.7. Iames. 4.15.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Will of ma<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> how it is able to do nothing of it ſelfe, no not in the regenerate, read, Free will, read alſo, Works which are good, are of God.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Willingnes, ſee Chearefulnes.</item>
                  <item>✿ Windes &amp; ſea appeaſed by Chriſt. Mat. 8.26. Mat. 14.32.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Wine ſhould be moderately and ſparingly vſed. Ephe. 5.18. 1. Tim. 5.23. Tit. 1.7.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Wiſdome ſound and true. Iam. 3.17.</item>
                  <item>Wiſdome of this world is fooliſhnes with God. 1. Cor. 1.20, 25. 1. Cor. 3.9.</item>
                  <item>Wiſdome earthly, ſenſual and diueliſh. Iam. 3.15.</item>
                  <item>Wiſdome muſt be aſked of God. Iam. 1.5.</item>
                  <item>Wiſdome of God, looke Chriſt, and Goſpel.</item>
                  <item>✿ Wiſe me<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> come to Ieruſalem and worſhip Chriſt. Matth. 2.11.</item>
                  <item>Witnes which God beareth, or giueth of himſelfe and of his bountifulnes. Act. 14.17.</item>
                  <item>Witnes which God beareth of Chriſt and his Goſpel. Ioh. 5.32. Ioh. 8.18. Act. 14.3. Act. 15.8. 1. Cor. 2.1. 1. Ioh. 5.6.</item>
                  <item>Witnes that Chriſt beareth to himſelfe, &amp; the trueth of his Goſpel. Ioh. 3.11. Ioh. 8.14. 1. Cor. 1.6. 1. Tim. 6.13.</item>
                  <item>Witnes which he teſtifieth of the world. Iohn. 7.7.</item>
                  <item>Witnes which the ſpirit beareth of Chriſt, looke Spirit.</item>
                  <item>Witnes of the Scripture &amp; Prophets, who witnes of Chriſt. Act. 10.43. Reade Scripture.</item>
                  <item>Witnes of Iohn Baptiſt. Iohn. 1.15, 19, 32 Iohn, 3.28.</item>
                  <item>Witnes of Iohn the Euangeliſt. Iohn. 19.35. Iohn. 21.24.</item>
                  <item>Witnes of the Apoſtles &amp; of the faithfull which they beare to Chriſt &amp; his Goſpel. Luk. 21.13. Act. 2.32. Act. 3.15. Act. 4.33. Act. 5.32. Act. 10.39. 1. Cor. 15.15. 2. Theſ. 1.10. 2. Tim. 1.8. Reue. 1. 2. Reue. 6.9. Reue. 20.4.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Witnes of the conſcience. Roman. 2.15. Rom. 9.1. 2. Cor. 1.12.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:47"/>
                  <item>Witnes of two or three is ſufficient. Matth. 18.16. Iohn. 8.17. 2. Cor. 13.1. Heb. 10.28.</item>
                  <item>Witnes falſe is forbidden. Matth. 15.19. Matth. 19.18. Rom. 13.9.</item>
                  <item>Witneſſes falſe. Matth. 26.59, 60, 61.</item>
                  <item>✿ Witneſſes did firſt ſtone Steuen. Act. 7.58.</item>
                  <item>✿ Wiues of Paſtors and Deacons. 1. Tim. 3.11.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Wiues deutie toward their huſbands. Eph. 5.22. &amp;c. Coloſſ. 3.18. Tit. 2.5. 1. Pet. 3.1, 2. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Wo, ſometime a note of temporall miſerie. Matth. 24.19.</item>
                  <item>✿ Woman is the glorie of the man. 1. Cor. 11.7.</item>
                  <item>Woman is of man and made for man. 1. Cor. 11.8, 9.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Woman how ſhe ought to be apparelled. 1. Timoth. 2.9. 1. Pet. 3.3.</item>
                  <item>Woman ought not to teach in the Church. 1. Cor. 14.34. 1. Tim. 2.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Women that followed Chriſt. Luk. 8.2.</item>
                  <item>Women married to the biſhops and miniſters of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Church. 1. Tim. 3.2, 11. Tit. 1.6.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Women muſt be ſubiect to their huſbandes. 1. Cor. 11.3. 1. Cor. 14.4. Ephe. 5.22, 23. Coloſſ. 3.18. 1. Tim. 2.11, 12. Tit. 2.5. 1. Pet. 3.1.</item>
                  <item>✿ Word, put for promiſe. Ephe. 5.26.</item>
                  <item>Word of God, put for the ſonne of God. Iohn. 1.1, 14. Reue. 19.13.</item>
                  <item>Word of God created all things. Iohn. 1.3. Heb. 11.3.</item>
                  <item>Word of God, put for the word written, or preached. Heb. 4.12. 1. Pet. 1.23.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Word of God is the power of God. Rom. 1.16. 1. Cor. 1.18</item>
                  <item>Word of God and the efficacie thereof. Heb. 4.12.</item>
                  <item>Word of God is the word of life. Matth. 4.4. Iohn. 5.35. Iohn. 6.63. Act. 5.20.</item>
                  <item>Word of God is the word of trueth. Iohn. 17.17. 2. Cor. 6.7. Ephe. 1.13. Coloſſ. 1.5. 2. Tim. 2.15. Iam. 1.18.</item>
                  <item>Word of God is the word of ſaluation. Act. 13.26. Iam. 1.21.</item>
                  <item>Word of God is the word of reconciliation. 2. Cor. 5.19.</item>
                  <item>Word of God is the ſword of the ſpirite. Ephe. 6.17.</item>
                  <item>Word of God endureth for euer. 1. Pet. 1.25.</item>
                  <item>Word of God is liuely, effectuall, &amp; iudgeth the thoughts.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:47"/> Heb. 4.12.</item>
                  <item>Word of God ſanctifieth all creatures. 1. Tim. 4.5.</item>
                  <item>Word of God is the incorruptible and immortall ſeede. 1. Pet. 1.23.</item>
                  <item>Word of God compared to the ſeede that groweth and fructifieth. Luk. 8.11. Act. 6.7. Act. 12.24.</item>
                  <item>Word of God muſt be kept and put in practiſe. Matth. 7.24. Iohn. 14.21. Iam. 1.23. 1. Iohn. 2.5.</item>
                  <item>Word of God ſerueth not to ſaluation in all. 2. Cor. 2.15, 16.</item>
                  <item>Word of God only muſt be preached &amp; taught. Rom. 10.17. 1. Cor. 3.11, 12. 1. Cor. 15.3, 4. 2. Cor. 6.7. Galat. 1.8, 9.</item>
                  <item>Words, ſee Idle.</item>
                  <item>✿ Worke of the Lord, put for the preaching of the Goſpel. 1. Cor. 16.8.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Works which are good, do not iuſtifie before God. Ioh. 6.29. Rom. 3.20. Galat. 2.16. Galat. 3.17, 18. Eph. 2.8, 9. Tit. 3.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Workes which are good are commended to the faithful. Mat. 5.16. Ro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 12.9, 10. &amp;c. 1. Cor. 15.58. Eph. 2.10. Phil. 4.8. Tit. 2.12. Tit. 3.8. Iam. 2.14, 15, 16. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Works which are good are of God. Phi. 1.6. Phi. 2.13. 2. Theſ. 2.17. Tit. 2.14. Heb. 13.21.</item>
                  <item>Workes which pleaſe God, follow faith. Luk. 19.8. Hebr. 11. throughout.</item>
                  <item>Workes good are done onely by the faithfull. Matth. 7.17. Matth. 12.33. Luk. 6.44.</item>
                  <item>VVorkes good aſſure vs of our election. 2. Pet. 1.10.</item>
                  <item>VVorkes good the faithfull muſt walke in. Ephe. 2.10. Heb. 10.24.</item>
                  <item>VVorkes good muſt be done for the glorie of God. Matth. 5.16. 1. Pet. 2.12.</item>
                  <item>VVorkes good followe the faithfull after their death. Reue. 14.13.</item>
                  <item>VVorkes good God wil reward. Mat. 10.42. Luk. 14.14. Rom. 2.7. 1. Cor. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>VVorkes are not good without faith. Rom. 14.23. Heb. 11.6.</item>
                  <item>VVorkes euill are of the fleſh. Galat. 5.19.</item>
                  <item>VVorkes euill are wrought by the deuill in the Infidels. Ephe. 2.2.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:181144:48"/>
                  <item>Workes euill, Chriſt is come to looſe &amp; deſtroy. 1. Ioh. 3.8.</item>
                  <item>Workes euill we muſt laye away and abſtaine from. Rom. 13.12. Ephe. 4.17. Ephe. 5.11. 1. Pet. 4.3.</item>
                  <item>Worke we can no good thing of our ſelues. Iohn. 6.44. Ioh. 15.4. Rom. 7.16, 17, 18. &amp;c. 1. Cor. 2.14 1. Cor. 12.3. 1. Cor. 15.10. 2. Cor. 3.5. Galat. 5.17. Phil. 2.13.</item>
                  <item>Euery man ſhall receiue according to his Workes. Matt. 16.27. Rom. 2.6. 2. Corin. 5.10. Galat. 6.5. 1. Pet. 1.17. Reu. 2.23. Reue. 20.12. Reue. 22.12.</item>
                  <item>✿ Workes great of our ſauiour Chriſt. Matth. 11.20. Matt. 13.58. Act. 2.22. Heb. 2.4.</item>
                  <item>✿ World, put for all mankind. 1. Ioh. 5.19.</item>
                  <item>Worlde, put for the elect. Iohn. 3.16. Iohn. 6.33. 1. Iohn. 2.2. 1. Iohn. 4.14.</item>
                  <item>World, put for the reprobate. Iohn. 17.9. 1. Cor. 11.32.</item>
                  <item>World, put for things appertaining to this life. 1. Cor. 7.31.</item>
                  <item>World, put for euill men in the world. Rom. 12.2.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> World was made by Chriſt. Iohn. 1.10.</item>
                  <item>World knoweth not Chriſt. Iohn. 1.11. Iohn. 17.25.</item>
                  <item>World fully bent on wickednes. 1. Iohn. 5.19.</item>
                  <item>World and prince thereof is the deuil, reade Deuill.</item>
                  <item>World we muſt not loue. 1. Iohn. 2.15.</item>
                  <item>World Chriſt praieth not for. Iohn. 17.9.</item>
                  <item>World Chriſt hath ouer come. Iohn. 16.33.</item>
                  <item>World the faithfull ouercome by faith. 1. Iohn. 5.4.</item>
                  <item>World &amp; the friendſhip thereof is enimitie w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> God. Iam. 4.4.</item>
                  <item>World hateth Chriſt and his. Ioh. 7.7. Ioh. 15.18. 1. Ioh. 3.13.</item>
                  <item>World paſſeth away. 1. Cor. 7.31. 1. Ioh. 2.17.</item>
                  <item>World the faithfull ſhall iudge. 1. Cor. 6.2.</item>
                  <item>World the faithfull are not of. Iohn. 15.19. Iohn. 17.14.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Worſhippe or ſerue God we may in all places. Iohn. 4.21. 1. Tim. 2.8.</item>
                  <item>✿ Worſhippers true which are. Iohn. 4.23, 24.</item>
                  <item>✿ Worſhipping, put for bowing of the knee. Matth. 9.18.</item>
                  <item>✿ Worſhipping of God, and the ſame commanded. Matth. 4.10. Luk. 4.8. Act. 14.15. 1. Cor. 14.25. 1. Theſſ. 1.9. Reue. 4.9, 10. Reu. 14.7. Reu. 15.4. Reu. 19.10. Reu. 22.8, 9. ſee God.</item>
                  <item>Worſhipping in ſpirit and trueth. Iohn. 4.23, 24.</item>
                  <item>Worſhipping ſuperſtitious. Actes. 10.25. Actes. 14.11, 12. &amp;c.
<pb facs="tcp:181144:48"/> Reue. 19.10. Reue. 22.9.</item>
                  <item>✿ Worſhipping of the beaſt and his Image. Reue. 13.4. Reue. 14.11. Reue. 16.2. Reue. 19.20. reade Idolatrie.</item>
                  <item>✿ Wrath taken for puniſhment. Ephe. 5.6. 1. Theſſ. 5.9.</item>
                  <item>Wrath, put for the iudgement of God. Rom. 4.15. Ephe. 2.3.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Wrath, ſee Anger.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Wrong ought not to be done or rendered, but ſuffered. Matth. 5.39. Rom. 12.17. 1. Cor. 6.7. 1. Theſ. 5.15. 1. Pet. 3.9.</item>
                  <item>Wrong, ſee Iniurie.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="Y" type="part">
               <head>Y.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>✿ YOke of Chriſt, eaſie. Matth. 11.29, 30.</item>
                  <item>Yoke of the lawe, neither the auncient fathers, nor the Apoſtles were able to beare, therefore the Chriſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans ought not to be burdened with it. Act. 15.10.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Yong children, ſee Infants.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Yong folkes, how they ſhould order themſelues. 1. Tim. 5.19. Tit. 2.6. 1. Pet. 5.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Yong men muſt be ſubiect to the elder. 1. Pet. 5.5.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Youth which is godly, muſt not be deſpiſed for lacke of yeeres. 1. Tim. 4.1.</item>
                  <item>
                     <g ref="char:trefoil">♣</g> Youthly luſts muſt be fled from. 2. Tim. 2.22.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="Z" type="part">
               <head>Z.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>ZAcharias, Iohn Baptiſts father, and his ſtorie. Luk. 1.5, 6, 7. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>Zacharias the ſonne of Barachias, ſlaine betweene the Altar and the Temple. Matth. 23.35.</item>
                  <item>Zacheus and his ſtorie. Luke. 19.1, 2. &amp;c.</item>
                  <item>✿ Zeale without knowledge. Rom. 10.2.</item>
                  <item>Zeale blinde, falſe, and diſorderly. Matt. 10.21. Matt. 26.51. Marke. 9.38. Luk. 9.54, 55. Iohn. 8.59. Iohn. 16.2. Act. 7.57. Act. 21.27. &amp;c. Act. 26.11.</item>
                  <item>Zeale taken in good part. 2. Cor. 7.11.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
